The officers put a cloth over my face and spun me around to make me dizzy.
Then they dragged and threw me into a 200-liter oil drum.
They lit a fire around the oil drum.
I tried to crawl out, but they hit me with the butt of a rifle.
Finally, I faked fainting. Then they let me crawl out.
Once I was out, they all ganged up and beat me.
They kicked my face, hit my mouth and knocked out two of my  teeth.
They also tortured me by lighting a candle and burning my body.
They put ice in a large cylinder, and then they put me inside the cylinder.
They dunked my head under the water several times. At last I ran out of patience.
So I stood up and fought them by pushing them away.
But they punched me and broke my eye socket.
In the Deep South, many people have told us
that they have had experiences like this
But the person who told us this story was a minor.  He was only 16 years old when he was arrested.
Throughout the 7 years of the southern unrest
Young people have come under suspicion of being involved in the insurgency00:02:05:24 00:02:10:24 and they must face the same fate as adults.
In another case, there was a minor who was 16 years old
when he became a suspect in a bombing case.
I was at school
Before I arrived home, a friend came to tell me that there were soldiers surrounding my house
My mom said that the soldiers wanted to see me
They asked me to go to the Army Task Force.
My mom had to wait outside. I was interrogated there alone with the officer
The officers told my mom that they would take me to Inkhayuth Army Camp.
I was shocked and then I cried.  I didn't want to go.
According to the law and judicial process in general,
youths should be given special treatment
as they have not yet reached the age of majority.
They are considered to be incapable of taking full responsibility for their actions.
Generally, during investigation and proceedings,
the minor's parent or guardian is required to be present, even during interrogation.
Whatever it takes to result in the minimal impact possible.
To ensure that youth do not feel ashamed or embarassed.
and suffer subsequent mental impacts.
Physical action against youth are out of the question.
No force should be used on minors.
Even the use of restraints is prohibited
The application of chains, hand restraints, or handcuffs is prohibited.
The Muslim Attorney Center has never received any information
from the parents or guardians that
during the investigation process, there was a psychologist present to question the child
and an interrogator taking notes.
All we have heard is that
the interrogating officials directly questioned them.
The statistics of the Muslim Attorney Center
on complaints received from the villagers shows that
In the Deep South, the number of youths arrested
and prosecuted is 55 individuals in 31 cases.
But there is no information that suggests
They have received treatment as juveniles as outlined in the principles
of special care for children and youths.
In addition to not receiving special treatment,
they have also been abused. Human rights activists indicated that
this was partly due to
the fact that state officials used their authority according to the special laws that have been declared in the area
The problem is with the power specified in the two special laws,
which are the Emergency .Decree and Martial Law.  There's a lot of power
and far-reaching authority.
The system of checks and balances to limit the wide-ranging powers
was, however, designed in a
way that does not limit abuses.
Therefore, the use of power under both laws
lacks the proper checks and balances
This leads to the illegitimate use of power
in the form of torture.
On the issue of special treatment for children and youths
No clear answer could be obtained from state officials
on whether they realize that this problem exists.
Regarding the issue of torture,
Responsible state officials, such as the military, insisted that there was very little torture.
As for state officials breaking the law
beating people, violating human rights,
during the time that I have been here, there have not been many cases.
Those cases that have come up are now going through the criminal justice process.
Therefore, regarding
state officials beating and torturing those who they arrest,
I maintain that it does not exist.
If state officials do it, they must be severely punished.
This is became the Deep South is a special area, where we are trying to solve the problems using special means
Therefore, there can be little or no chance of human rights violations being committed.
If they do occur, then it is a case of an individuals.
But in terms of policy, the policy is
to prevent it and use other methods.
Whether or not this is true, for those who have experienced it
,the attorneys say that
they still have a way to fight and to demand justice.
If the question is: "Under what sort of authority did the officials act?"
I can answer that they have no authority to do so.
If the villagers are to bring a case against the officials, they can do so
since the act is considered to be a deprivation of freedom
and the officials have no authority to detain them.
Martial Laws allows for no more than 7 days of detention.
After 7 days, if further detention is necessary,
a request must be made to the court
for an arrest warrant according to the Emergency Decree.
This is the issue about which we have received a lot of complaints from the villagers
including on not being notified of where the suspect would be taken,
detaining suspects for more than 7 days
and not detaining them officially under the Emergency Decree.
But the problem that attorneys themselves admit is that
in many cases, the villagers do not dare to bring a case against state officials.
Human rights activists raise as a concern the issue
that these violations then create frustration within the minds of individuals who experience them,
particularly for the youth themselves.
I feel very sad that my son was beaten
It's not that I'm not hurt. I am really hurt.
I want to beg the officials to stop doing this.
I feel really sad that there is nothing we can do.
They are the mighty people, while we are just the small ones.
When officers arrest and detain children based only on suspicion,
how are the villagers supposed to put their hope in the officials?
When something like this is done to the people,
there will be a feeling of mistrust towards the officials
and anger that the officials treat them this way.
Even today, there is anger, but it is hidden inside.
It cannot be vented out
It's hidden in our minds, and we would not dare take vengeance
But instead feel sorry and angry that the officials treated us like this.
Many experts have studied
and looked for ways to solve the problems of affected youth.
Even though most are not ready to provide information
nearly all have expressed concern about the long-term consequences.
If the child is not guilty
but is accused of being guilty,
they will be at risk of being persuaded from the opposite side,
and more easily than other children.
Political scientists also commented that
this issue will have long-term consequences on solving the conflict in the area,
as by their own admission, the Melayu in the Deep South
are already suspicious and afraid of state officials.
It is a long-existing feeling and has been passed on until today.
Today, children and youth
have been directly affected
and thus the feeling of uneasiness and dislike is likely to mount up.
At present, I feel that the effect on children who experience this
is that it may facilitate, partially, persuade or push them
to act in another manner
that it may cause them to take actions against the state
it may only create further certainty that what they have done was correct.
Because no matter what state officials do, it will not  be fair anyways
This will be be embedded and make it harder to solve the problem
One approach to solve the problem
suggested by the attorneys and human rights activists
is that the state should change their working method to take special care of youth.
This does not mean not taking legal action against them,
but there should be a process in which these individuals receive special care.
I would like to ask security agencies
to write a manual outlining policy on the  treatment of youths, children, and women.
It should deal with is the method of arrest,
the method of searching, the method of detaining, the conditions of the place of detention,
method of interrogation while being detained by military units under martial law,
the method of interrogation while being detained under the Emergency Decree,
and the conditions of the place of detention.
In addition, children and youths should be given the right to have social workers or psychologists
and their parents present during interrogation by officials,
as we have to accept the fact that children and youth
have different way of thinking than adults.
If the person interrogating the child is a soldier,
the soldier should have received training on children's rights
and training on the psychology of interrogating children
The judicial process for children and minors who have committed crimes,
has the objective of rehabilitating juvenile offenders
so that they can return to join society,
and in which the child will feel remorse for their crime and grow in strength
to an adequate extent that they will not re-commit the crime
Therefore, a just and fair criminal justice process for children and youth
is important and should be made a reality.