THE ADVENTURES OF SHERLOCK HOLMES bySIR ARTHUR CONAN DOYLE
ADVENTURE I.A SCANDAL IN BOHEMIA
I.To Sherlock Holmes she is always THE woman.
I have seldom heard him mention her underany other name.
In his eyes she eclipses and predominatesthe whole of her sex.
It was not that he felt any emotion akin tolove for Irene Adler.
All emotions, and that one particularly,were abhorrent to his cold, precise but
admirably balanced mind.
He was, I take it, the most perfectreasoning and observing machine that the
world has seen, but as a lover he wouldhave placed himself in a false position.
He never spoke of the softer passions, savewith a gibe and a sneer.
They were admirable things for theobserver--excellent for drawing the veil
from men's motives and actions.
But for the trained reasoner to admit suchintrusions into his own delicate and finely
adjusted temperament was to introduce adistracting factor which might throw a
doubt upon all his mental results.
Grit in a sensitive instrument, or a crackin one of his own high-power lenses, would
not be more disturbing than a strongemotion in a nature such as his.
And yet there was but one woman to him, andthat woman was the late Irene Adler, of
dubious and questionable memory.I had seen little of Holmes lately.
My marriage had drifted us away from eachother.
My own complete happiness, and the home-centred interests which rise up around the
man who first finds himself master of hisown establishment, were sufficient to
absorb all my attention, while Holmes, who
loathed every form of society with hiswhole Bohemian soul, remained in our
lodgings in Baker Street, buried among hisold books, and alternating from week to
week between cocaine and ambition, the
drowsiness of the drug, and the fierceenergy of his own keen nature.
He was still, as ever, deeply attracted bythe study of crime, and occupied his
immense faculties and extraordinary powersof observation in following out those
clues, and clearing up those mysteries
which had been abandoned as hopeless by theofficial police.
From time to time I heard some vagueaccount of his doings: of his summons to
Odessa in the case of the Trepoff murder,of his clearing up of the singular tragedy
of the Atkinson brothers at Trincomalee,
and finally of the mission which he hadaccomplished so delicately and successfully
for the reigning family of Holland.
Beyond these signs of his activity,however, which I merely shared with all the
readers of the daily press, I knew littleof my former friend and companion.
One night--it was on the twentieth ofMarch, 1888--I was returning from a journey
to a patient (for I had now returned tocivil practice), when my way led me through
Baker Street.
As I passed the well-remembered door, whichmust always be associated in my mind with
my wooing, and with the dark incidents ofthe Study in Scarlet, I was seized with a
keen desire to see Holmes again, and to
know how he was employing his extraordinarypowers.
His rooms were brilliantly lit, and, evenas I looked up, I saw his tall, spare
figure pass twice in a dark silhouetteagainst the blind.
He was pacing the room swiftly, eagerly,with his head sunk upon his chest and his
hands clasped behind him.
To me, who knew his every mood and habit,his attitude and manner told their own
story.He was at work again.
He had risen out of his drug-created dreamsand was hot upon the scent of some new
problem.
I rang the bell and was shown up to thechamber which had formerly been in part my
own.His manner was not effusive.
It seldom was; but he was glad, I think, tosee me.
With hardly a word spoken, but with akindly eye, he waved me to an armchair,
threw across his case of cigars, andindicated a spirit case and a gasogene in
the corner.
Then he stood before the fire and looked meover in his singular introspective fashion.
"Wedlock suits you," he remarked."I think, Watson, that you have put on
seven and a half pounds since I saw you."
"Seven!"I answered.
"Indeed, I should have thought a littlemore.
Just a trifle more, I fancy, Watson.
And in practice again, I observe.You did not tell me that you intended to go
into harness.""Then, how do you know?"
"I see it, I deduce it.
How do I know that you have been gettingyourself very wet lately, and that you have
a most clumsy and careless servant girl?""My dear Holmes," said I, "this is too
much.
You would certainly have been burned, hadyou lived a few centuries ago.
It is true that I had a country walk onThursday and came home in a dreadful mess,
but as I have changed my clothes I can'timagine how you deduce it.
As to Mary Jane, she is incorrigible, andmy wife has given her notice, but there,
again, I fail to see how you work it out."He chuckled to himself and rubbed his long,
nervous hands together.
"It is simplicity itself," said he; "myeyes tell me that on the inside of your
left shoe, just where the firelight strikesit, the leather is scored by six almost
parallel cuts.
Obviously they have been caused by someonewho has very carelessly scraped round the
edges of the sole in order to removecrusted mud from it.
Hence, you see, my double deduction thatyou had been out in vile weather, and that
you had a particularly malignant boot-slitting specimen of the London slavey.
As to your practice, if a gentleman walksinto my rooms smelling of iodoform, with a
black mark of nitrate of silver upon hisright forefinger, and a bulge on the right
side of his top-hat to show where he has
secreted his stethoscope, I must be dull,indeed, if I do not pronounce him to be an
active member of the medical profession."
I could not help laughing at the ease withwhich he explained his process of
deduction.
"When I hear you give your reasons," Iremarked, "the thing always appears to me
to be so ridiculously simple that I couldeasily do it myself, though at each
successive instance of your reasoning I ambaffled until you explain your process.
And yet I believe that my eyes are as goodas yours."
"Quite so," he answered, lighting acigarette, and throwing himself down into
an armchair."You see, but you do not observe.
The distinction is clear.
For example, you have frequently seen thesteps which lead up from the hall to this
room.""Frequently."
"How often?"
"Well, some hundreds of times.""Then how many are there?"
"How many?I don't know."
"Quite so!
You have not observed.And yet you have seen.
That is just my point.Now, I know that there are seventeen steps,
because I have both seen and observed.
By-the-way, since you are interested inthese little problems, and since you are
good enough to chronicle one or two of mytrifling experiences, you may be interested
in this."
He threw over a sheet of thick, pink-tintednote-paper which had been lying open upon
the table."It came by the last post," said he.
"Read it aloud."
The note was undated, and without eithersignature or address.
"There will call upon you to-night, at aquarter to eight o'clock," it said, "a
gentleman who desires to consult you upon amatter of the very deepest moment.
Your recent services to one of the royalhouses of Europe have shown that you are
one who may safely be trusted with matterswhich are of an importance which can hardly
be exaggerated.
This account of you we have from allquarters received.
Be in your chamber then at that hour, anddo not take it amiss if your visitor wear a
mask."
"This is indeed a mystery," I remarked."What do you imagine that it means?"
"I have no data yet.It is a capital mistake to theorize before
one has data.
Insensibly one begins to twist facts tosuit theories, instead of theories to suit
facts.But the note itself.
What do you deduce from it?"
I carefully examined the writing, and thepaper upon which it was written.
"The man who wrote it was presumably wellto do," I remarked, endeavouring to imitate
my companion's processes.
"Such paper could not be bought under halfa crown a packet.
It is peculiarly strong and stiff.""Peculiar--that is the very word," said
Holmes.
"It is not an English paper at all.Hold it up to the light."
I did so, and saw a large "E" with a small"g," a "P," and a large "G" with a small
"t" woven into the texture of the paper.
"What do you make of that?" asked Holmes."The name of the maker, no doubt; or his
monogram, rather.""Not at all.
The 'G' with the small 't' stands for'Gesellschaft,' which is the German for
'Company.'It is a customary contraction like our
'Co.'
'P,' of course, stands for 'Papier.'Now for the 'Eg.'
Let us glance at our ContinentalGazetteer."
He took down a heavy brown volume from hisshelves.
"Eglow, Eglonitz--here we are, Egria.It is in a German-speaking country--in
Bohemia, not far from Carlsbad.
'Remarkable as being the scene of the deathof Wallenstein, and for its numerous glass-
factories and paper-mills.'Ha, ha, my boy, what do you make of that?"
His eyes sparkled, and he sent up a greatblue triumphant cloud from his cigarette.
"The paper was made in Bohemia," I said."Precisely.
And the man who wrote the note is a German.
Do you note the peculiar construction ofthe sentence--'This account of you we have
from all quarters received.'A Frenchman or Russian could not have
written that.
It is the German who is so uncourteous tohis verbs.
It only remains, therefore, to discoverwhat is wanted by this German who writes
upon Bohemian paper and prefers wearing amask to showing his face.
And here he comes, if I am not mistaken, toresolve all our doubts."
As he spoke there was the sharp sound ofhorses' hoofs and grating wheels against
the curb, followed by a sharp pull at thebell.
Holmes whistled.
"A pair, by the sound," said he."Yes," he continued, glancing out of the
window."A nice little brougham and a pair of
beauties.
A hundred and fifty guineas apiece.There's money in this case, Watson, if
there is nothing else.""I think that I had better go, Holmes."
"Not a bit, Doctor.
Stay where you are.I am lost without my Boswell.
And this promises to be interesting.It would be a pity to miss it."
"But your client--"
"Never mind him.I may want your help, and so may he.
Here he comes.Sit down in that armchair, Doctor, and give
us your best attention."
A slow and heavy step, which had been heardupon the stairs and in the passage, paused
immediately outside the door.Then there was a loud and authoritative
tap.
"Come in!" said Holmes.A man entered who could hardly have been
less than six feet six inches in height,with the chest and limbs of a Hercules.
His dress was rich with a richness whichwould, in England, be looked upon as akin
to bad taste.
Heavy bands of astrakhan were slashedacross the sleeves and fronts of his
double-breasted coat, while the deep bluecloak which was thrown over his shoulders
was lined with flame-coloured silk and
secured at the neck with a brooch whichconsisted of a single flaming beryl.
Boots which extended halfway up his calves,and which were trimmed at the tops with
rich brown fur, completed the impression ofbarbaric opulence which was suggested by
his whole appearance.
He carried a broad-brimmed hat in his hand,while he wore across the upper part of his
face, extending down past the cheekbones, ablack vizard mask, which he had apparently
adjusted that very moment, for his hand wasstill raised to it as he entered.
From the lower part of the face he appearedto be a man of strong character, with a
thick, hanging lip, and a long, straightchin suggestive of resolution pushed to the
length of obstinacy.
"You had my note?" he asked with a deepharsh voice and a strongly marked German
accent."I told you that I would call."
He looked from one to the other of us, asif uncertain which to address.
"Pray take a seat," said Holmes.
"This is my friend and colleague, Dr.Watson, who is occasionally good enough to
help me in my cases.Whom have I the honour to address?"
"You may address me as the Count Von Kramm,a Bohemian nobleman.
I understand that this gentleman, yourfriend, is a man of honour and discretion,
whom I may trust with a matter of the mostextreme importance.
If not, I should much prefer to communicatewith you alone."
I rose to go, but Holmes caught me by thewrist and pushed me back into my chair.
"It is both, or none," said he.
"You may say before this gentleman anythingwhich you may say to me."
The Count shrugged his broad shoulders.
"Then I must begin," said he, "by bindingyou both to absolute secrecy for two years;
at the end of that time the matter will beof no importance.
At present it is not too much to say thatit is of such weight it may have an
influence upon European history.""I promise," said Holmes.
"And I."
"You will excuse this mask," continued ourstrange visitor.
"The august person who employs me wisheshis agent to be unknown to you, and I may
confess at once that the title by which Ihave just called myself is not exactly my
own."
"I was aware of it," said Holmes dryly.
"The circumstances are of great delicacy,and every precaution has to be taken to
quench what might grow to be an immensescandal and seriously compromise one of the
reigning families of Europe.
To speak plainly, the matter implicates thegreat House of Ormstein, hereditary kings
of Bohemia."
"I was also aware of that," murmuredHolmes, settling himself down in his
armchair and closing his eyes.
Our visitor glanced with some apparentsurprise at the languid, lounging figure of
the man who had been no doubt depicted tohim as the most incisive reasoner and most
energetic agent in Europe.
Holmes slowly reopened his eyes and lookedimpatiently at his gigantic client.
"If your Majesty would condescend to stateyour case," he remarked, "I should be
better able to advise you."
The man sprang from his chair and paced upand down the room in uncontrollable
agitation.
Then, with a gesture of desperation, hetore the mask from his face and hurled it
upon the ground."You are right," he cried; "I am the King.
Why should I attempt to conceal it?"
"Why, indeed?" murmured Holmes.
"Your Majesty had not spoken before I wasaware that I was addressing Wilhelm
Gottsreich Sigismond von Ormstein, GrandDuke of Cassel-Felstein, and hereditary
King of Bohemia."
"But you can understand," said our strangevisitor, sitting down once more and passing
his hand over his high white forehead, "youcan understand that I am not accustomed to
doing such business in my own person.
Yet the matter was so delicate that I couldnot confide it to an agent without putting
myself in his power.I have come incognito from Prague for the
purpose of consulting you."
"Then, pray consult," said Holmes, shuttinghis eyes once more.
"The facts are briefly these: Some fiveyears ago, during a lengthy visit to
Warsaw, I made the acquaintance of thewell-known adventuress, Irene Adler.
The name is no doubt familiar to you."
"Kindly look her up in my index, Doctor,"murmured Holmes without opening his eyes.
For many years he had adopted a system ofdocketing all paragraphs concerning men and
things, so that it was difficult to name asubject or a person on which he could not
at once furnish information.
In this case I found her biographysandwiched in between that of a Hebrew
rabbi and that of a staff-commander who hadwritten a monograph upon the deep-sea
fishes.
"Let me see!" said Holmes."Hum!
Born in New Jersey in the year 1858.Contralto--hum!
La Scala, hum!
Prima donna Imperial Opera of Warsaw--yes!Retired from operatic stage--ha!
Living in London--quite so!
Your Majesty, as I understand, becameentangled with this young person, wrote her
some compromising letters, and is nowdesirous of getting those letters back."
"Precisely so.
But how--""Was there a secret marriage?"
"None.""No legal papers or certificates?"
"None."
"Then I fail to follow your Majesty.If this young person should produce her
letters for blackmailing or other purposes,how is she to prove their authenticity?"
"There is the writing."
"Pooh, pooh!Forgery."
"My private note-paper.""Stolen."
"My own seal."
"Imitated.""My photograph."
"Bought.""We were both in the photograph."
"Oh, dear!
That is very bad!Your Majesty has indeed committed an
indiscretion.""I was mad--insane."
"You have compromised yourself seriously."
"I was only Crown Prince then.I was young.
I am but thirty now.""It must be recovered."
"We have tried and failed."
"Your Majesty must pay.It must be bought."
"She will not sell.""Stolen, then."
"Five attempts have been made.
Twice burglars in my pay ransacked herhouse.
Once we diverted her luggage when shetravelled.
Twice she has been waylaid.
There has been no result.""No sign of it?"
"Absolutely none."Holmes laughed.
"It is quite a pretty little problem," saidhe.
"But a very serious one to me," returnedthe King reproachfully.
"Very, indeed.
And what does she propose to do with thephotograph?"
"To ruin me.""But how?"
"I am about to be married."
"So I have heard.""To Clotilde Lothman von Saxe-Meningen,
second daughter of the King of Scandinavia.You may know the strict principles of her
family.
She is herself the very soul of delicacy.A shadow of a doubt as to my conduct would
bring the matter to an end.""And Irene Adler?"
"Threatens to send them the photograph.
And she will do it.I know that she will do it.
You do not know her, but she has a soul ofsteel.
She has the face of the most beautiful ofwomen, and the mind of the most resolute of
men.
Rather than I should marry another woman,there are no lengths to which she would not
go--none.""You are sure that she has not sent it
yet?"
"I am sure.""And why?"
"Because she has said that she would sendit on the day when the betrothal was
publicly proclaimed.
That will be next Monday.""Oh, then we have three days yet," said
Holmes with a yawn.
"That is very fortunate, as I have one ortwo matters of importance to look into just
at present.Your Majesty will, of course, stay in
London for the present?"
"Certainly.You will find me at the Langham under the
name of the Count Von Kramm.""Then I shall drop you a line to let you
know how we progress."
"Pray do so.I shall be all anxiety."
"Then, as to money?""You have carte blanche."
"Absolutely?"
"I tell you that I would give one of theprovinces of my kingdom to have that
photograph.""And for present expenses?"
The King took a heavy chamois leather bagfrom under his cloak and laid it on the
table."There are three hundred pounds in gold and
seven hundred in notes," he said.
Holmes scribbled a receipt upon a sheet ofhis note-book and handed it to him.
"And Mademoiselle's address?" he asked."Is Briony Lodge, Serpentine Avenue, St.
John's Wood."
Holmes took a note of it."One other question," said he.
"Was the photograph a cabinet?""It was."
"Then, good-night, your Majesty, and Itrust that we shall soon have some good
news for you.
And good-night, Watson," he added, as thewheels of the royal brougham rolled down
the street.
"If you will be good enough to call to-morrow afternoon at three o'clock I should
like to chat this little matter over withyou."
II.At three o'clock precisely I was at Baker
Street, but Holmes had not yet returned.
The landlady informed me that he had leftthe house shortly after eight o'clock in
the morning.
I sat down beside the fire, however, withthe intention of awaiting him, however long
he might be.
I was already deeply interested in hisinquiry, for, though it was surrounded by
none of the grim and strange features whichwere associated with the two crimes which I
have already recorded, still, the nature of
the case and the exalted station of hisclient gave it a character of its own.
Indeed, apart from the nature of theinvestigation which my friend had on hand,
there was something in his masterly graspof a situation, and his keen, incisive
reasoning, which made it a pleasure to me
to study his system of work, and to followthe quick, subtle methods by which he
disentangled the most inextricablemysteries.
So accustomed was I to his invariablesuccess that the very possibility of his
failing had ceased to enter into my head.
It was close upon four before the dooropened, and a drunken-looking groom, ill-
kempt and side-whiskered, with an inflamedface and disreputable clothes, walked into
the room.
Accustomed as I was to my friend's amazingpowers in the use of disguises, I had to
look three times before I was certain thatit was indeed he.
With a nod he vanished into the bedroom,whence he emerged in five minutes tweed-
suited and respectable, as of old.
Putting his hands into his pockets, hestretched out his legs in front of the fire
and laughed heartily for some minutes.
"Well, really!" he cried, and then hechoked and laughed again until he was
obliged to lie back, limp and helpless, inthe chair.
"What is it?"
"It's quite too funny.I am sure you could never guess how I
employed my morning, or what I ended bydoing."
"I can't imagine.
I suppose that you have been watching thehabits, and perhaps the house, of Miss
Irene Adler.""Quite so; but the sequel was rather
unusual.
I will tell you, however.I left the house a little after eight
o'clock this morning in the character of agroom out of work.
There is a wonderful sympathy andfreemasonry among horsey men.
Be one of them, and you will know all thatthere is to know.
I soon found Briony Lodge.
It is a bijou villa, with a garden at theback, but built out in front right up to
the road, two stories.Chubb lock to the door.
Large sitting-room on the right side, wellfurnished, with long windows almost to the
floor, and those preposterous Englishwindow fasteners which a child could open.
Behind there was nothing remarkable, savethat the passage window could be reached
from the top of the coach-house.
I walked round it and examined it closelyfrom every point of view, but without
noting anything else of interest.
"I then lounged down the street and found,as I expected, that there was a mews in a
lane which runs down by one wall of thegarden.
I lent the ostlers a hand in rubbing downtheir horses, and received in exchange
twopence, a glass of half and half, twofills of shag tobacco, and as much
information as I could desire about Miss
Adler, to say nothing of half a dozen otherpeople in the neighbourhood in whom I was
not in the least interested, but whosebiographies I was compelled to listen to."
"And what of Irene Adler?"
I asked."Oh, she has turned all the men's heads
down in that part.She is the daintiest thing under a bonnet
on this planet.
So say the Serpentine-mews, to a man.She lives quietly, sings at concerts,
drives out at five every day, and returnsat seven sharp for dinner.
Seldom goes out at other times, except whenshe sings.
Has only one male visitor, but a good dealof him.
He is dark, handsome, and dashing, nevercalls less than once a day, and often
twice.He is a Mr. Godfrey Norton, of the Inner
Temple.
See the advantages of a cabman as aconfidant.
They had driven him home a dozen times fromSerpentine-mews, and knew all about him.
When I had listened to all they had totell, I began to walk up and down near
Briony Lodge once more, and to think overmy plan of campaign.
"This Godfrey Norton was evidently animportant factor in the matter.
He was a lawyer.That sounded ominous.
What was the relation between them, andwhat the object of his repeated visits?
Was she his client, his friend, or hismistress?
If the former, she had probably transferredthe photograph to his keeping.
If the latter, it was less likely.
On the issue of this question dependedwhether I should continue my work at Briony
Lodge, or turn my attention to thegentleman's chambers in the Temple.
It was a delicate point, and it widened thefield of my inquiry.
I fear that I bore you with these details,but I have to let you see my little
difficulties, if you are to understand thesituation."
"I am following you closely," I answered.
"I was still balancing the matter in mymind when a hansom cab drove up to Briony
Lodge, and a gentleman sprang out.
He was a remarkably handsome man, dark,aquiline, and moustached--evidently the man
of whom I had heard.
He appeared to be in a great hurry, shoutedto the cabman to wait, and brushed past the
maid who opened the door with the air of aman who was thoroughly at home.
"He was in the house about half an hour,and I could catch glimpses of him in the
windows of the sitting-room, pacing up anddown, talking excitedly, and waving his
arms.
Of her I could see nothing.Presently he emerged, looking even more
flurried than before.
As he stepped up to the cab, he pulled agold watch from his pocket and looked at it
earnestly, 'Drive like the devil,' heshouted, 'first to Gross & Hankey's in
Regent Street, and then to the Church ofSt. Monica in the Edgeware Road.
Half a guinea if you do it in twentyminutes!'
"Away they went, and I was just wonderingwhether I should not do well to follow them
when up the lane came a neat little landau,the coachman with his coat only half-
buttoned, and his tie under his ear, while
all the tags of his harness were stickingout of the buckles.
It hadn't pulled up before she shot out ofthe hall door and into it.
I only caught a glimpse of her at themoment, but she was a lovely woman, with a
face that a man might die for.
"'The Church of St. Monica, John,' shecried, 'and half a sovereign if you reach
it in twenty minutes.'"This was quite too good to lose, Watson.
I was just balancing whether I should runfor it, or whether I should perch behind
her landau when a cab came through thestreet.
The driver looked twice at such a shabbyfare, but I jumped in before he could
object.
'The Church of St. Monica,' said I, 'andhalf a sovereign if you reach it in twenty
minutes.'
It was twenty-five minutes to twelve, andof course it was clear enough what was in
the wind."My cabby drove fast.
I don't think I ever drove faster, but theothers were there before us.
The cab and the landau with their steaminghorses were in front of the door when I
arrived.
I paid the man and hurried into the church.There was not a soul there save the two
whom I had followed and a surplicedclergyman, who seemed to be expostulating
with them.
They were all three standing in a knot infront of the altar.
I lounged up the side aisle like any otheridler who has dropped into a church.
Suddenly, to my surprise, the three at thealtar faced round to me, and Godfrey Norton
came running as hard as he could towardsme.
"'Thank God,' he cried.
'You'll do.Come!
Come!'"'What then?'
I asked.
"'Come, man, come, only three minutes, orit won't be legal.'
"I was half-dragged up to the altar, andbefore I knew where I was I found myself
mumbling responses which were whispered inmy ear, and vouching for things of which I
knew nothing, and generally assisting in
the secure tying up of Irene Adler,spinster, to Godfrey Norton, bachelor.
It was all done in an instant, and therewas the gentleman thanking me on the one
side and the lady on the other, while theclergyman beamed on me in front.
It was the most preposterous position inwhich I ever found myself in my life, and
it was the thought of it that started melaughing just now.
It seems that there had been someinformality about their license, that the
clergyman absolutely refused to marry themwithout a witness of some sort, and that my
lucky appearance saved the bridegroom from
having to sally out into the streets insearch of a best man.
The bride gave me a sovereign, and I meanto wear it on my watch-chain in memory of
the occasion."
"This is a very unexpected turn ofaffairs," said I; "and what then?"
"Well, I found my plans very seriouslymenaced.
It looked as if the pair might take animmediate departure, and so necessitate
very prompt and energetic measures on mypart.
At the church door, however, theyseparated, he driving back to the Temple,
and she to her own house.'I shall drive out in the park at five as
usual,' she said as she left him.
I heard no more.They drove away in different directions,
and I went off to make my ownarrangements."
"Which are?"
"Some cold beef and a glass of beer," heanswered, ringing the bell.
"I have been too busy to think of food, andI am likely to be busier still this
evening.
By the way, Doctor, I shall want your co-operation."
"I shall be delighted.""You don't mind breaking the law?"
"Not in the least."
"Nor running a chance of arrest?""Not in a good cause."
"Oh, the cause is excellent!""Then I am your man."
"I was sure that I might rely on you."
"But what is it you wish?""When Mrs. Turner has brought in the tray I
will make it clear to you.
Now," he said as he turned hungrily on thesimple fare that our landlady had provided,
"I must discuss it while I eat, for I havenot much time.
It is nearly five now.
In two hours we must be on the scene ofaction.
Miss Irene, or Madame, rather, returns fromher drive at seven.
We must be at Briony Lodge to meet her."
"And what then?""You must leave that to me.
I have already arranged what is to occur.There is only one point on which I must
insist.
You must not interfere, come what may.You understand?"
"I am to be neutral?""To do nothing whatever.
There will probably be some smallunpleasantness.
Do not join in it.It will end in my being conveyed into the
house.
Four or five minutes afterwards thesitting-room window will open.
You are to station yourself close to thatopen window."
"Yes."
"You are to watch me, for I will be visibleto you."
"And when I raise my hand--so--you willthrow into the room what I give you to
throw, and will, at the same time, raisethe cry of fire.
You quite follow me?"
"Entirely.""It is nothing very formidable," he said,
taking a long cigar-shaped roll from hispocket.
"It is an ordinary plumber's smoke-rocket,fitted with a cap at either end to make it
self-lighting.Your task is confined to that.
When you raise your cry of fire, it will betaken up by quite a number of people.
You may then walk to the end of the street,and I will rejoin you in ten minutes.
I hope that I have made myself clear?"
"I am to remain neutral, to get near thewindow, to watch you, and at the signal to
throw in this object, then to raise the cryof fire, and to wait you at the corner of
the street."
"Precisely.""Then you may entirely rely on me."
"That is excellent.I think, perhaps, it is almost time that I
prepare for the new role I have to play."
He disappeared into his bedroom andreturned in a few minutes in the character
of an amiable and simple-mindedNonconformist clergyman.
His broad black hat, his baggy trousers,his white tie, his sympathetic smile, and
general look of peering and benevolentcuriosity were such as Mr. John Hare alone
could have equalled.
It was not merely that Holmes changed hiscostume.
His expression, his manner, his very soulseemed to vary with every fresh part that
he assumed.
The stage lost a fine actor, even asscience lost an acute reasoner, when he
became a specialist in crime.
It was a quarter past six when we leftBaker Street, and it still wanted ten
minutes to the hour when we found ourselvesin Serpentine Avenue.
It was already dusk, and the lamps werejust being lighted as we paced up and down
in front of Briony Lodge, waiting for thecoming of its occupant.
The house was just such as I had picturedit from Sherlock Holmes' succinct
description, but the locality appeared tobe less private than I expected.
On the contrary, for a small street in aquiet neighbourhood, it was remarkably
animated.
There was a group of shabbily dressed mensmoking and laughing in a corner, a
scissors-grinder with his wheel, twoguardsmen who were flirting with a nurse-
girl, and several well-dressed young men
who were lounging up and down with cigarsin their mouths.
"You see," remarked Holmes, as we paced toand fro in front of the house, "this
marriage rather simplifies matters.The photograph becomes a double-edged
weapon now.
The chances are that she would be as averseto its being seen by Mr. Godfrey Norton, as
our client is to its coming to the eyes ofhis princess.
Now the question is, Where are we to findthe photograph?"
"Where, indeed?""It is most unlikely that she carries it
about with her.
It is cabinet size.Too large for easy concealment about a
woman's dress.She knows that the King is capable of
having her waylaid and searched.
Two attempts of the sort have already beenmade.
We may take it, then, that she does notcarry it about with her."
"Where, then?"
"Her banker or her lawyer.There is that double possibility.
But I am inclined to think neither.Women are naturally secretive, and they
like to do their own secreting.
Why should she hand it over to anyone else?She could trust her own guardianship, but
she could not tell what indirect orpolitical influence might be brought to
bear upon a business man.
Besides, remember that she had resolved touse it within a few days.
It must be where she can lay her hands uponit.
It must be in her own house."
"But it has twice been burgled.""Pshaw!
They did not know how to look.""But how will you look?"
"I will not look."
"What then?""I will get her to show me."
"But she will refuse.""She will not be able to.
But I hear the rumble of wheels.
It is her carriage.Now carry out my orders to the letter."
As he spoke the gleam of the side-lights ofa carriage came round the curve of the
avenue.
It was a smart little landau which rattledup to the door of Briony Lodge.
As it pulled up, one of the loafing men atthe corner dashed forward to open the door
in the hope of earning a copper, but waselbowed away by another loafer, who had
rushed up with the same intention.
A fierce quarrel broke out, which wasincreased by the two guardsmen, who took
sides with one of the loungers, and by thescissors-grinder, who was equally hot upon
the other side.
A blow was struck, and in an instant thelady, who had stepped from her carriage,
was the centre of a little knot of flushedand struggling men, who struck savagely at
each other with their fists and sticks.
Holmes dashed into the crowd to protect thelady; but just as he reached her he gave a
cry and dropped to the ground, with theblood running freely down his face.
At his fall the guardsmen took to theirheels in one direction and the loungers in
the other, while a number of better-dressedpeople, who had watched the scuffle without
taking part in it, crowded in to help thelady and to attend to the injured man.
Irene Adler, as I will still call her, hadhurried up the steps; but she stood at the
top with her superb figure outlined againstthe lights of the hall, looking back into
the street.
"Is the poor gentleman much hurt?" sheasked.
"He is dead," cried several voices."No, no, there's life in him!" shouted
another.
"But he'll be gone before you can get himto hospital."
"He's a brave fellow," said a woman."They would have had the lady's purse and
watch if it hadn't been for him.
They were a gang, and a rough one, too.Ah, he's breathing now."
"He can't lie in the street.May we bring him in, marm?"
"Surely.
Bring him into the sitting-room.There is a comfortable sofa.
This way, please!"
Slowly and solemnly he was borne intoBriony Lodge and laid out in the principal
room, while I still observed theproceedings from my post by the window.
The lamps had been lit, but the blinds hadnot been drawn, so that I could see Holmes
as he lay upon the couch.
I do not know whether he was seized withcompunction at that moment for the part he
was playing, but I know that I never feltmore heartily ashamed of myself in my life
than when I saw the beautiful creature
against whom I was conspiring, or the graceand kindliness with which she waited upon
the injured man.
And yet it would be the blackest treacheryto Holmes to draw back now from the part
which he had intrusted to me.I hardened my heart, and took the smoke-
rocket from under my ulster.
After all, I thought, we are not injuringher.
We are but preventing her from injuringanother.
Holmes had sat up upon the couch, and I sawhim motion like a man who is in need of
air.A maid rushed across and threw open the
window.
At the same instant I saw him raise hishand and at the signal I tossed my rocket
into the room with a cry of "Fire!"
The word was no sooner out of my mouth thanthe whole crowd of spectators, well dressed
and ill--gentlemen, ostlers, and servant-maids--joined in a general shriek of
"Fire!"
Thick clouds of smoke curled through theroom and out at the open window.
I caught a glimpse of rushing figures, anda moment later the voice of Holmes from
within assuring them that it was a falsealarm.
Slipping through the shouting crowd I mademy way to the corner of the street, and in
ten minutes was rejoiced to find myfriend's arm in mine, and to get away from
the scene of uproar.
He walked swiftly and in silence for somefew minutes until we had turned down one of
the quiet streets which lead towards theEdgeware Road.
"You did it very nicely, Doctor," heremarked.
"Nothing could have been better.It is all right."
"You have the photograph?"
"I know where it is.""And how did you find out?"
"She showed me, as I told you she would.""I am still in the dark."
"I do not wish to make a mystery," said he,laughing.
"The matter was perfectly simple.You, of course, saw that everyone in the
street was an accomplice.
They were all engaged for the evening.""I guessed as much."
"Then, when the row broke out, I had alittle moist red paint in the palm of my
hand.
I rushed forward, fell down, clapped myhand to my face, and became a piteous
spectacle.It is an old trick."
"That also I could fathom."
"Then they carried me in.She was bound to have me in.
What else could she do?And into her sitting-room, which was the
very room which I suspected.
It lay between that and her bedroom, and Iwas determined to see which.
They laid me on a couch, I motioned forair, they were compelled to open the
window, and you had your chance."
"How did that help you?""It was all-important.
When a woman thinks that her house is onfire, her instinct is at once to rush to
the thing which she values most.
It is a perfectly overpowering impulse, andI have more than once taken advantage of
it.
In the case of the Darlington substitutionscandal it was of use to me, and also in
the Arnsworth Castle business.A married woman grabs at her baby; an
unmarried one reaches for her jewel-box.
Now it was clear to me that our lady of to-day had nothing in the house more precious
to her than what we are in quest of.She would rush to secure it.
The alarm of fire was admirably done.
The smoke and shouting were enough to shakenerves of steel.
She responded beautifully.
The photograph is in a recess behind asliding panel just above the right bell-
pull.She was there in an instant, and I caught a
glimpse of it as she half-drew it out.
When I cried out that it was a false alarm,she replaced it, glanced at the rocket,
rushed from the room, and I have not seenher since.
I rose, and, making my excuses, escapedfrom the house.
I hesitated whether to attempt to securethe photograph at once; but the coachman
had come in, and as he was watching menarrowly it seemed safer to wait.
A little over-precipitance may ruin all."
"And now?"I asked.
"Our quest is practically finished.I shall call with the King to-morrow, and
with you, if you care to come with us.
We will be shown into the sitting-room towait for the lady, but it is probable that
when she comes she may find neither us northe photograph.
It might be a satisfaction to his Majestyto regain it with his own hands."
"And when will you call?""At eight in the morning.
She will not be up, so that we shall have aclear field.
Besides, we must be prompt, for thismarriage may mean a complete change in her
life and habits.
I must wire to the King without delay."We had reached Baker Street and had stopped
at the door.He was searching his pockets for the key
when someone passing said:
"Good-night, Mister Sherlock Holmes."There were several people on the pavement
at the time, but the greeting appeared tocome from a slim youth in an ulster who had
hurried by.
"I've heard that voice before," saidHolmes, staring down the dimly lit street.
"Now, I wonder who the deuce that couldhave been."
III.I slept at Baker Street that night, and we
were engaged upon our toast and coffee inthe morning when the King of Bohemia rushed
into the room.
"You have really got it!" he cried,grasping Sherlock Holmes by either shoulder
and looking eagerly into his face."Not yet."
"But you have hopes?"
"I have hopes.""Then, come.
I am all impatience to be gone.""We must have a cab."
"No, my brougham is waiting."
"Then that will simplify matters."We descended and started off once more for
Briony Lodge."Irene Adler is married," remarked Holmes.
"Married!
When?""Yesterday."
"But to whom?""To an English lawyer named Norton."
"But she could not love him."
"I am in hopes that she does.""And why in hopes?"
"Because it would spare your Majesty allfear of future annoyance.
If the lady loves her husband, she does notlove your Majesty.
If she does not love your Majesty, there isno reason why she should interfere with
your Majesty's plan."
"It is true.And yet--Well!
I wish she had been of my own station!What a queen she would have made!"
He relapsed into a moody silence, which wasnot broken until we drew up in Serpentine
Avenue.The door of Briony Lodge was open, and an
elderly woman stood upon the steps.
She watched us with a sardonic eye as westepped from the brougham.
"Mr. Sherlock Holmes, I believe?" said she.
"I am Mr. Holmes," answered my companion,looking at her with a questioning and
rather startled gaze."Indeed!
My mistress told me that you were likely tocall.
She left this morning with her husband bythe 5:15 train from Charing Cross for the
Continent."
"What!"Sherlock Holmes staggered back, white with
chagrin and surprise."Do you mean that she has left England?"
"Never to return."
"And the papers?" asked the King hoarsely."All is lost."
"We shall see."
He pushed past the servant and rushed intothe drawing-room, followed by the King and
myself.
The furniture was scattered about in everydirection, with dismantled shelves and open
drawers, as if the lady had hurriedlyransacked them before her flight.
Holmes rushed at the bell-pull, tore back asmall sliding shutter, and, plunging in his
hand, pulled out a photograph and a letter.
The photograph was of Irene Adler herselfin evening dress, the letter was
superscribed to "Sherlock Holmes, Esq. Tobe left till called for."
My friend tore it open and we all threeread it together.
It was dated at midnight of the precedingnight and ran in this way:
"MY DEAR MR. SHERLOCK HOLMES,--You reallydid it very well.
You took me in completely.Until after the alarm of fire, I had not a
suspicion.
But then, when I found how I had betrayedmyself, I began to think.
I had been warned against you months ago.I had been told that if the King employed
an agent it would certainly be you.
And your address had been given me.Yet, with all this, you made me reveal what
you wanted to know.
Even after I became suspicious, I found ithard to think evil of such a dear, kind old
clergyman.But, you know, I have been trained as an
actress myself.
Male costume is nothing new to me.I often take advantage of the freedom which
it gives.
I sent John, the coachman, to watch you,ran up stairs, got into my walking-clothes,
as I call them, and came down just as youdeparted.
"Well, I followed you to your door, and somade sure that I was really an object of
interest to the celebrated Mr. SherlockHolmes.
Then I, rather imprudently, wished yougood-night, and started for the Temple to
see my husband.
"We both thought the best resource wasflight, when pursued by so formidable an
antagonist; so you will find the nest emptywhen you call to-morrow.
As to the photograph, your client may restin peace.
I love and am loved by a better man thanhe.
The King may do what he will withouthindrance from one whom he has cruelly
wronged.
I keep it only to safeguard myself, and topreserve a weapon which will always secure
me from any steps which he might take inthe future.
I leave a photograph which he might care topossess; and I remain, dear Mr. Sherlock
Holmes,"Very truly yours, "IRENE NORTON, ne
ADLER."
"What a woman--oh, what a woman!" cried theKing of Bohemia, when we had all three read
this epistle."Did I not tell you how quick and resolute
she was?
Would she not have made an admirable queen?Is it not a pity that she was not on my
level?"
"From what I have seen of the lady sheseems indeed to be on a very different
level to your Majesty," said Holmes coldly.
"I am sorry that I have not been able tobring your Majesty's business to a more
successful conclusion.""On the contrary, my dear sir," cried the
King; "nothing could be more successful.
I know that her word is inviolate.The photograph is now as safe as if it were
in the fire.""I am glad to hear your Majesty say so."
"I am immensely indebted to you.
Pray tell me in what way I can reward you.This ring--" He slipped an emerald snake
ring from his finger and held it out uponthe palm of his hand.
"Your Majesty has something which I shouldvalue even more highly," said Holmes.
"You have but to name it.""This photograph!"
The King stared at him in amazement.
"Irene's photograph!" he cried."Certainly, if you wish it."
"I thank your Majesty.Then there is no more to be done in the
matter.
I have the honour to wish you a very good-morning."
He bowed, and, turning away withoutobserving the hand which the King had
stretched out to him, he set off in mycompany for his chambers.
And that was how a great scandal threatenedto affect the kingdom of Bohemia, and how
the best plans of Mr. Sherlock Holmes werebeaten by a woman's wit.
He used to make merry over the clevernessof women, but I have not heard him do it of
late.
And when he speaks of Irene Adler, or whenhe refers to her photograph, it is always
under the honourable title of the woman.
>
THE ADVENTURES OF SHERLOCK HOLMES bySIR ARTHUR CONAN DOYLE
ADVENTURE II.THE RED-HEADED LEAGUE
I had called upon my friend, Mr. SherlockHolmes, one day in the autumn of last year
and found him in deep conversation with avery stout, florid-faced, elderly gentleman
with fiery red hair.
With an apology for my intrusion, I wasabout to withdraw when Holmes pulled me
abruptly into the room and closed the doorbehind me.
"You could not possibly have come at abetter time, my dear Watson," he said
cordially."I was afraid that you were engaged."
"So I am.
Very much so.""Then I can wait in the next room."
"Not at all.
This gentleman, Mr. Wilson, has been mypartner and helper in many of my most
successful cases, and I have no doubt thathe will be of the utmost use to me in yours
also."
The stout gentleman half rose from hischair and gave a bob of greeting, with a
quick little questioning glance from hissmall fat-encircled eyes.
"Try the settee," said Holmes, relapsinginto his armchair and putting his
fingertips together, as was his custom whenin judicial moods.
"I know, my dear Watson, that you share mylove of all that is bizarre and outside the
conventions and humdrum routine of everydaylife.
You have shown your relish for it by theenthusiasm which has prompted you to
chronicle, and, if you will excuse mysaying so, somewhat to embellish so many of
my own little adventures."
"Your cases have indeed been of thegreatest interest to me," I observed.
"You will remember that I remarked theother day, just before we went into the
very simple problem presented by Miss MarySutherland, that for strange effects and
extraordinary combinations we must go to
life itself, which is always far moredaring than any effort of the imagination."
"A proposition which I took the liberty ofdoubting."
"You did, Doctor, but none the less youmust come round to my view, for otherwise I
shall keep on piling fact upon fact on youuntil your reason breaks down under them
and acknowledges me to be right.
Now, Mr. Jabez Wilson here has been goodenough to call upon me this morning, and to
begin a narrative which promises to be oneof the most singular which I have listened
to for some time.
You have heard me remark that the strangestand most unique things are very often
connected not with the larger but with thesmaller crimes, and occasionally, indeed,
where there is room for doubt whether anypositive crime has been committed.
As far as I have heard it is impossible forme to say whether the present case is an
instance of crime or not, but the course ofevents is certainly among the most singular
that I have ever listened to.
Perhaps, Mr. Wilson, you would have thegreat kindness to recommence your
narrative.
I ask you not merely because my friend Dr.Watson has not heard the opening part but
also because the peculiar nature of thestory makes me anxious to have every
possible detail from your lips.
As a rule, when I have heard some slightindication of the course of events, I am
able to guide myself by the thousands ofother similar cases which occur to my
memory.
In the present instance I am forced toadmit that the facts are, to the best of my
belief, unique."
The portly client puffed out his chest withan appearance of some little pride and
pulled a dirty and wrinkled newspaper fromthe inside pocket of his greatcoat.
As he glanced down the advertisementcolumn, with his head thrust forward and
the paper flattened out upon his knee, Itook a good look at the man and
endeavoured, after the fashion of my
companion, to read the indications whichmight be presented by his dress or
appearance.I did not gain very much, however, by my
inspection.
Our visitor bore every mark of being anaverage commonplace British tradesman,
obese, pompous, and slow.
He wore rather baggy grey shepherd's checktrousers, a not over-clean black frock-
coat, unbuttoned in the front, and a drabwaistcoat with a heavy brassy Albert chain,
and a square pierced bit of metal danglingdown as an ornament.
A frayed top-hat and a faded brown overcoatwith a wrinkled velvet collar lay upon a
chair beside him.
Altogether, look as I would, there wasnothing remarkable about the man save his
blazing red head, and the expression ofextreme chagrin and discontent upon his
features.
Sherlock Holmes' quick eye took in myoccupation, and he shook his head with a
smile as he noticed my questioning glances.
"Beyond the obvious facts that he has atsome time done manual labour, that he takes
snuff, that he is a Freemason, that he hasbeen in China, and that he has done a
considerable amount of writing lately, Ican deduce nothing else."
Mr. Jabez Wilson started up in his chair,with his forefinger upon the paper, but his
eyes upon my companion.
"How, in the name of good-fortune, did youknow all that, Mr. Holmes?" he asked.
"How did you know, for example, that I didmanual labour.
It's as true as gospel, for I began as aship's carpenter."
"Your hands, my dear sir.Your right hand is quite a size larger than
your left.
You have worked with it, and the musclesare more developed."
"Well, the snuff, then, and theFreemasonry?"
"I won't insult your intelligence bytelling you how I read that, especially as,
rather against the strict rules of yourorder, you use an arc-and-compass
breastpin."
"Ah, of course, I forgot that.But the writing?"
"What else can be indicated by that rightcuff so very shiny for five inches, and the
left one with the smooth patch near theelbow where you rest it upon the desk?"
"Well, but China?"
"The fish that you have tattooedimmediately above your right wrist could
only have been done in China.
I have made a small study of tattoo marksand have even contributed to the literature
of the subject.
That trick of staining the fishes' scalesof a delicate pink is quite peculiar to
China.
When, in addition, I see a Chinese coinhanging from your watch-chain, the matter
becomes even more simple."Mr. Jabez Wilson laughed heavily.
"Well, I never!" said he.
"I thought at first that you had donesomething clever, but I see that there was
nothing in it, after all.""I begin to think, Watson," said Holmes,
"that I make a mistake in explaining.
'Omne ignotum pro magnifico,' you know, andmy poor little reputation, such as it is,
will suffer shipwreck if I am so candid.Can you not find the advertisement, Mr.
Wilson?"
"Yes, I have got it now," he answered withhis thick red finger planted halfway down
the column."Here it is.
This is what began it all.
You just read it for yourself, sir."I took the paper from him and read as
follows:
"TO THE RED-HEADED LEAGUE: On account ofthe bequest of the late Ezekiah Hopkins, of
Lebanon, Pennsylvania, U. S. A., there isnow another vacancy open which entitles a
member of the League to a salary of 4pounds a week for purely nominal services.
All red-headed men who are sound in bodyand mind and above the age of twenty-one
years, are eligible.
Apply in person on Monday, at eleveno'clock, to Duncan Ross, at the offices of
the League, 7 Pope's Court, Fleet Street.""What on earth does this mean?"
I ejaculated after I had twice read overthe extraordinary announcement.
Holmes chuckled and wriggled in his chair,as was his habit when in high spirits.
"It is a little off the beaten track, isn'tit?" said he.
"And now, Mr. Wilson, off you go at scratchand tell us all about yourself, your
household, and the effect which thisadvertisement had upon your fortunes.
You will first make a note, Doctor, of thepaper and the date."
"It is The Morning Chronicle of April 27,1890.
Just two months ago."
"Very good.Now, Mr. Wilson?"
"Well, it is just as I have been tellingyou, Mr. Sherlock Holmes," said Jabez
Wilson, mopping his forehead; "I have asmall pawnbroker's business at Coburg
Square, near the City.
It's not a very large affair, and of lateyears it has not done more than just give
me a living.
I used to be able to keep two assistants,but now I only keep one; and I would have a
job to pay him but that he is willing tocome for half wages so as to learn the
business."
"What is the name of this obliging youth?"asked Sherlock Holmes.
"His name is Vincent Spaulding, and he'snot such a youth, either.
It's hard to say his age.
I should not wish a smarter assistant, Mr.Holmes; and I know very well that he could
better himself and earn twice what I amable to give him.
But, after all, if he is satisfied, whyshould I put ideas in his head?"
"Why, indeed?
You seem most fortunate in having anemploy who comes under the full market
price.It is not a common experience among
employers in this age.
I don't know that your assistant is not asremarkable as your advertisement."
"Oh, he has his faults, too," said Mr.Wilson.
"Never was such a fellow for photography.
Snapping away with a camera when he oughtto be improving his mind, and then diving
down into the cellar like a rabbit into itshole to develop his pictures.
That is his main fault, but on the wholehe's a good worker.
There's no vice in him.""He is still with you, I presume?"
"Yes, sir.
He and a girl of fourteen, who does a bitof simple cooking and keeps the place
clean--that's all I have in the house, forI am a widower and never had any family.
We live very quietly, sir, the three of us;and we keep a roof over our heads and pay
our debts, if we do nothing more."The first thing that put us out was that
advertisement.
Spaulding, he came down into the officejust this day eight weeks, with this very
paper in his hand, and he says:"'I wish to the Lord, Mr. Wilson, that I
was a red-headed man.'
"'Why that?'I asks.
"'Why,' says he, 'here's another vacancy onthe League of the Red-headed Men.
It's worth quite a little fortune to anyman who gets it, and I understand that
there are more vacancies than there aremen, so that the trustees are at their
wits' end what to do with the money.
If my hair would only change colour, here'sa nice little crib all ready for me to step
into.'"'Why, what is it, then?'
I asked.
You see, Mr. Holmes, I am a very stay-at-home man, and as my business came to me
instead of my having to go to it, I wasoften weeks on end without putting my foot
over the door-mat.
In that way I didn't know much of what wasgoing on outside, and I was always glad of
a bit of news.
"'Have you never heard of the League of theRed-headed Men?' he asked with his eyes
open."'Never.'
"'Why, I wonder at that, for you areeligible yourself for one of the
vacancies.'"'And what are they worth?'
I asked.
"'Oh, merely a couple of hundred a year,but the work is slight, and it need not
interfere very much with one's otheroccupations.'
"Well, you can easily think that that mademe prick up my ears, for the business has
not been over-good for some years, and anextra couple of hundred would have been
very handy.
"'Tell me all about it,' said I.
"'Well,' said he, showing me theadvertisement, 'you can see for yourself
that the League has a vacancy, and there isthe address where you should apply for
particulars.
As far as I can make out, the League wasfounded by an American millionaire, Ezekiah
Hopkins, who was very peculiar in his ways.
He was himself red-headed, and he had agreat sympathy for all red-headed men; so
when he died it was found that he had lefthis enormous fortune in the hands of
trustees, with instructions to apply the
interest to the providing of easy berths tomen whose hair is of that colour.
From all I hear it is splendid pay and verylittle to do.'
"'But,' said I, 'there would be millions ofred-headed men who would apply.'
"'Not so many as you might think,' heanswered.
'You see it is really confined toLondoners, and to grown men.
This American had started from London whenhe was young, and he wanted to do the old
town a good turn.
Then, again, I have heard it is no use yourapplying if your hair is light red, or dark
red, or anything but real bright, blazing,fiery red.
Now, if you cared to apply, Mr. Wilson, youwould just walk in; but perhaps it would
hardly be worth your while to put yourselfout of the way for the sake of a few
hundred pounds.'
"Now, it is a fact, gentlemen, as you maysee for yourselves, that my hair is of a
very full and rich tint, so that it seemedto me that if there was to be any
competition in the matter I stood as good achance as any man that I had ever met.
Vincent Spaulding seemed to know so muchabout it that I thought he might prove
useful, so I just ordered him to put up theshutters for the day and to come right away
with me.
He was very willing to have a holiday, sowe shut the business up and started off for
the address that was given us in theadvertisement.
"I never hope to see such a sight as thatagain, Mr. Holmes.
From north, south, east, and west every manwho had a shade of red in his hair had
tramped into the city to answer theadvertisement.
Fleet Street was choked with red-headedfolk, and Pope's Court looked like a
coster's orange barrow.
I should not have thought there were somany in the whole country as were brought
together by that single advertisement.
Every shade of colour they were--straw,lemon, orange, brick, Irish-setter, liver,
clay; but, as Spaulding said, there werenot many who had the real vivid flame-
coloured tint.
When I saw how many were waiting, I wouldhave given it up in despair; but Spaulding
would not hear of it.
How he did it I could not imagine, but hepushed and pulled and butted until he got
me through the crowd, and right up to thesteps which led to the office.
There was a double stream upon the stair,some going up in hope, and some coming back
dejected; but we wedged in as well as wecould and soon found ourselves in the
office."
"Your experience has been a mostentertaining one," remarked Holmes as his
client paused and refreshed his memory witha huge pinch of snuff.
"Pray continue your very interestingstatement."
"There was nothing in the office but acouple of wooden chairs and a deal table,
behind which sat a small man with a headthat was even redder than mine.
He said a few words to each candidate as hecame up, and then he always managed to find
some fault in them which would disqualifythem.
Getting a vacancy did not seem to be such avery easy matter, after all.
However, when our turn came the little manwas much more favourable to me than to any
of the others, and he closed the door as weentered, so that he might have a private
word with us.
"'This is Mr. Jabez Wilson,' said myassistant, 'and he is willing to fill a
vacancy in the League.'"'And he is admirably suited for it,' the
other answered.
'He has every requirement.I cannot recall when I have seen anything
so fine.'
He took a step backward, cocked his head onone side, and gazed at my hair until I felt
quite bashful.
Then suddenly he plunged forward, wrung myhand, and congratulated me warmly on my
success."'It would be injustice to hesitate,' said
he.
'You will, however, I am sure, excuse mefor taking an obvious precaution.'
With that he seized my hair in both hishands, and tugged until I yelled with the
pain.
'There is water in your eyes,' said he ashe released me.
'I perceive that all is as it should be.
But we have to be careful, for we havetwice been deceived by wigs and once by
paint.I could tell you tales of cobbler's wax
which would disgust you with human nature.'
He stepped over to the window and shoutedthrough it at the top of his voice that the
vacancy was filled.
A groan of disappointment came up frombelow, and the folk all trooped away in
different directions until there was not ared-head to be seen except my own and that
of the manager.
"'My name,' said he, 'is Mr. Duncan Ross,and I am myself one of the pensioners upon
the fund left by our noble benefactor.Are you a married man, Mr. Wilson?
Have you a family?'
"I answered that I had not."His face fell immediately.
"'Dear me!' he said gravely, 'that is veryserious indeed!
I am sorry to hear you say that.
The fund was, of course, for thepropagation and spread of the red-heads as
well as for their maintenance.It is exceedingly unfortunate that you
should be a bachelor.'
"My face lengthened at this, Mr. Holmes,for I thought that I was not to have the
vacancy after all; but after thinking itover for a few minutes he said that it
would be all right.
"'In the case of another,' said he, 'theobjection might be fatal, but we must
stretch a point in favour of a man withsuch a head of hair as yours.
When shall you be able to enter upon yournew duties?'
"'Well, it is a little awkward, for I havea business already,' said I.
"'Oh, never mind about that, Mr. Wilson!'said Vincent Spaulding.
'I should be able to look after that foryou.'
"'What would be the hours?'
I asked."'Ten to two.'
"Now a pawnbroker's business is mostly doneof an evening, Mr. Holmes, especially
Thursday and Friday evening, which is justbefore pay-day; so it would suit me very
well to earn a little in the mornings.
Besides, I knew that my assistant was agood man, and that he would see to anything
that turned up."'That would suit me very well,' said I.
'And the pay?'
"'Is 4 pounds a week.'"'And the work?'
"'Is purely nominal.'"'What do you call purely nominal?'
"'Well, you have to be in the office, or atleast in the building, the whole time.
If you leave, you forfeit your wholeposition forever.
The will is very clear upon that point.
You don't comply with the conditions if youbudge from the office during that time.'
"'It's only four hours a day, and I shouldnot think of leaving,' said I.
"'No excuse will avail,' said Mr. DuncanRoss; 'neither sickness nor business nor
anything else.There you must stay, or you lose your
billet.'
"'And the work?'"'Is to copy out the "Encyclopaedia
Britannica."There is the first volume of it in that
press.
You must find your own ink, pens, andblotting-paper, but we provide this table
and chair.Will you be ready to-morrow?'
"'Certainly,' I answered.
"'Then, good-bye, Mr. Jabez Wilson, and letme congratulate you once more on the
important position which you have beenfortunate enough to gain.'
He bowed me out of the room and I went homewith my assistant, hardly knowing what to
say or do, I was so pleased at my own goodfortune.
"Well, I thought over the matter all day,and by evening I was in low spirits again;
for I had quite persuaded myself that thewhole affair must be some great hoax or
fraud, though what its object might be Icould not imagine.
It seemed altogether past belief thatanyone could make such a will, or that they
would pay such a sum for doing anything sosimple as copying out the 'Encyclopaedia
Britannica.'
Vincent Spaulding did what he could tocheer me up, but by bedtime I had reasoned
myself out of the whole thing.
However, in the morning I determined tohave a look at it anyhow, so I bought a
penny bottle of ink, and with a quill-pen,and seven sheets of foolscap paper, I
started off for Pope's Court.
"Well, to my surprise and delight,everything was as right as possible.
The table was set out ready for me, and Mr.Duncan Ross was there to see that I got
fairly to work.
He started me off upon the letter A, andthen he left me; but he would drop in from
time to time to see that all was right withme.
At two o'clock he bade me good-day,complimented me upon the amount that I had
written, and locked the door of the officeafter me.
"This went on day after day, Mr. Holmes,and on Saturday the manager came in and
planked down four golden sovereigns for myweek's work.
It was the same next week, and the same theweek after.
Every morning I was there at ten, and everyafternoon I left at two.
By degrees Mr. Duncan Ross took to comingin only once of a morning, and then, after
a time, he did not come in at all.
Still, of course, I never dared to leavethe room for an instant, for I was not sure
when he might come, and the billet was sucha good one, and suited me so well, that I
would not risk the loss of it.
"Eight weeks passed away like this, and Ihad written about Abbots and Archery and
Armour and Architecture and Attica, andhoped with diligence that I might get on to
the B's before very long.
It cost me something in foolscap, and I hadpretty nearly filled a shelf with my
writings.And then suddenly the whole business came
to an end."
"To an end?""Yes, sir.
And no later than this morning.
I went to my work as usual at ten o'clock,but the door was shut and locked, with a
little square of cardboard hammered on tothe middle of the panel with a tack.
Here it is, and you can read for yourself."
He held up a piece of white cardboard aboutthe size of a sheet of note-paper.
It read in this fashion:THE RED-HEADED LEAGUE
IS
DISSOLVED.October 9, 1890.
Sherlock Holmes and I surveyed this curtannouncement and the rueful face behind it,
until the comical side of the affair socompletely overtopped every other
consideration that we both burst out into aroar of laughter.
"I cannot see that there is anything veryfunny," cried our client, flushing up to
the roots of his flaming head.
"If you can do nothing better than laugh atme, I can go elsewhere."
"No, no," cried Holmes, shoving him backinto the chair from which he had half
risen.
"I really wouldn't miss your case for theworld.
It is most refreshingly unusual.But there is, if you will excuse my saying
so, something just a little funny about it.
Pray what steps did you take when you foundthe card upon the door?"
"I was staggered, sir.I did not know what to do.
Then I called at the offices round, butnone of them seemed to know anything about
it.
Finally, I went to the landlord, who is anaccountant living on the ground-floor, and
I asked him if he could tell me what hadbecome of the Red-headed League.
He said that he had never heard of any suchbody.
Then I asked him who Mr. Duncan Ross was.He answered that the name was new to him.
"'Well,' said I, 'the gentleman at No. 4.'
"'What, the red-headed man?'"'Yes.'
"'Oh,' said he, 'his name was WilliamMorris.
He was a solicitor and was using my room asa temporary convenience until his new
premises were ready.He moved out yesterday.'
"'Where could I find him?'
"'Oh, at his new offices.He did tell me the address.
Yes, 17 King Edward Street, near St.Paul's.'
"I started off, Mr. Holmes, but when I gotto that address it was a manufactory of
artificial knee-caps, and no one in it hadever heard of either Mr. William Morris or
Mr. Duncan Ross."
"And what did you do then?" asked Holmes."I went home to Saxe-Coburg Square, and I
took the advice of my assistant.But he could not help me in any way.
He could only say that if I waited I shouldhear by post.
But that was not quite good enough, Mr.Holmes.
I did not wish to lose such a place withouta struggle, so, as I had heard that you
were good enough to give advice to poorfolk who were in need of it, I came right
away to you."
"And you did very wisely," said Holmes."Your case is an exceedingly remarkable
one, and I shall be happy to look into it.
From what you have told me I think that itis possible that graver issues hang from it
than might at first sight appear.""Grave enough!" said Mr. Jabez Wilson.
"Why, I have lost four pound a week."
"As far as you are personally concerned,"remarked Holmes, "I do not see that you
have any grievance against thisextraordinary league.
On the contrary, you are, as I understand,richer by some 30 pounds, to say nothing of
the minute knowledge which you have gainedon every subject which comes under the
letter A.
You have lost nothing by them.""No, sir.
But I want to find out about them, and whothey are, and what their object was in
playing this prank--if it was a prank--uponme.
It was a pretty expensive joke for them,for it cost them two and thirty pounds."
"We shall endeavour to clear up thesepoints for you.
And, first, one or two questions, Mr.Wilson.
This assistant of yours who first calledyour attention to the advertisement--how
long had he been with you?"
"About a month then.""How did he come?"
"In answer to an advertisement.""Was he the only applicant?"
"No, I had a dozen."
"Why did you pick him?""Because he was handy and would come
cheap.""At half-wages, in fact."
"Yes."
"What is he like, this Vincent Spaulding?""Small, stout-built, very quick in his
ways, no hair on his face, though he's notshort of thirty.
Has a white splash of acid upon hisforehead."
Holmes sat up in his chair in considerableexcitement.
"I thought as much," said he.
"Have you ever observed that his ears arepierced for earrings?"
"Yes, sir.He told me that a gipsy had done it for him
when he was a lad."
"Hum!" said Holmes, sinking back in deepthought.
"He is still with you?""Oh, yes, sir; I have only just left him."
"And has your business been attended to inyour absence?"
"Nothing to complain of, sir.There's never very much to do of a
morning."
"That will do, Mr. Wilson.I shall be happy to give you an opinion
upon the subject in the course of a day ortwo.
To-day is Saturday, and I hope that byMonday we may come to a conclusion."
"Well, Watson," said Holmes when ourvisitor had left us, "what do you make of
it all?"
"I make nothing of it," I answered frankly."It is a most mysterious business."
"As a rule," said Holmes, "the more bizarrea thing is the less mysterious it proves to
be.
It is your commonplace, featureless crimeswhich are really puzzling, just as a
commonplace face is the most difficult toidentify.
But I must be prompt over this matter."
"What are you going to do, then?"I asked.
"To smoke," he answered.
"It is quite a three pipe problem, and Ibeg that you won't speak to me for fifty
minutes."
He curled himself up in his chair, with histhin knees drawn up to his hawk-like nose,
and there he sat with his eyes closed andhis black clay pipe thrusting out like the
bill of some strange bird.
I had come to the conclusion that he haddropped asleep, and indeed was nodding
myself, when he suddenly sprang out of hischair with the gesture of a man who has
made up his mind and put his pipe down uponthe mantelpiece.
"Sarasate plays at the St. James's Hallthis afternoon," he remarked.
"What do you think, Watson?
Could your patients spare you for a fewhours?"
"I have nothing to do to-day.My practice is never very absorbing."
"Then put on your hat and come.
I am going through the City first, and wecan have some lunch on the way.
I observe that there is a good deal ofGerman music on the programme, which is
rather more to my taste than Italian orFrench.
It is introspective, and I want tointrospect.
Come along!"
We travelled by the Underground as far asAldersgate; and a short walk took us to
Saxe-Coburg Square, the scene of thesingular story which we had listened to in
the morning.
It was a poky, little, shabby-genteelplace, where four lines of dingy two-
storied brick houses looked out into asmall railed-in enclosure, where a lawn of
weedy grass and a few clumps of faded
laurel-bushes made a hard fight against asmoke-laden and uncongenial atmosphere.
Three gilt balls and a brown board with"JABEZ WILSON" in white letters, upon a
corner house, announced the place where ourred-headed client carried on his business.
Sherlock Holmes stopped in front of it withhis head on one side and looked it all
over, with his eyes shining brightlybetween puckered lids.
Then he walked slowly up the street, andthen down again to the corner, still
looking keenly at the houses.
Finally he returned to the pawnbroker's,and, having thumped vigorously upon the
pavement with his stick two or three times,he went up to the door and knocked.
It was instantly opened by a bright-looking, clean-shaven young fellow, who
asked him to step in.
"Thank you," said Holmes, "I only wished toask you how you would go from here to the
Strand.""Third right, fourth left," answered the
assistant promptly, closing the door.
"Smart fellow, that," observed Holmes as wewalked away.
"He is, in my judgment, the fourth smartestman in London, and for daring I am not sure
that he has not a claim to be third.
I have known something of him before.""Evidently," said I, "Mr. Wilson's
assistant counts for a good deal in thismystery of the Red-headed League.
I am sure that you inquired your way merelyin order that you might see him."
"Not him.""What then?"
"The knees of his trousers."
"And what did you see?""What I expected to see."
"Why did you beat the pavement?""My dear doctor, this is a time for
observation, not for talk.
We are spies in an enemy's country.We know something of Saxe-Coburg Square.
Let us now explore the parts which liebehind it."
The road in which we found ourselves as weturned round the corner from the retired
Saxe-Coburg Square presented as great acontrast to it as the front of a picture
does to the back.
It was one of the main arteries whichconveyed the traffic of the City to the
north and west.
The roadway was blocked with the immensestream of commerce flowing in a double tide
inward and outward, while the footpathswere black with the hurrying swarm of
pedestrians.
It was difficult to realise as we looked atthe line of fine shops and stately business
premises that they really abutted on theother side upon the faded and stagnant
square which we had just quitted.
"Let me see," said Holmes, standing at thecorner and glancing along the line, "I
should like just to remember the order ofthe houses here.
It is a hobby of mine to have an exactknowledge of London.
There is Mortimer's, the tobacconist, thelittle newspaper shop, the Coburg branch of
the City and Suburban Bank, the VegetarianRestaurant, and McFarlane's carriage-
building depot.
That carries us right on to the otherblock.
And now, Doctor, we've done our work, soit's time we had some play.
A sandwich and a cup of coffee, and thenoff to violin-land, where all is sweetness
and delicacy and harmony, and there are nored-headed clients to vex us with their
conundrums."
My friend was an enthusiastic musician,being himself not only a very capable
performer but a composer of no ordinarymerit.
All the afternoon he sat in the stallswrapped in the most perfect happiness,
gently waving his long, thin fingers intime to the music, while his gently smiling
face and his languid, dreamy eyes were as
unlike those of Holmes the sleuth-hound,Holmes the relentless, keen-witted, ready-
handed criminal agent, as it was possibleto conceive.
In his singular character the dual naturealternately asserted itself, and his
extreme exactness and astutenessrepresented, as I have often thought, the
reaction against the poetic and
contemplative mood which occasionallypredominated in him.
The swing of his nature took him fromextreme languor to devouring energy; and,
as I knew well, he was never so trulyformidable as when, for days on end, he had
been lounging in his armchair amid his
improvisations and his black-lettereditions.
Then it was that the lust of the chasewould suddenly come upon him, and that his
brilliant reasoning power would rise to thelevel of intuition, until those who were
unacquainted with his methods would look
askance at him as on a man whose knowledgewas not that of other mortals.
When I saw him that afternoon so enwrappedin the music at St. James's Hall I felt
that an evil time might be coming uponthose whom he had set himself to hunt down.
"You want to go home, no doubt, Doctor," heremarked as we emerged.
"Yes, it would be as well.""And I have some business to do which will
take some hours.
This business at Coburg Square is serious.""Why serious?"
"A considerable crime is in contemplation.I have every reason to believe that we
shall be in time to stop it.
But to-day being Saturday rathercomplicates matters.
I shall want your help to-night.""At what time?"
"Ten will be early enough."
"I shall be at Baker Street at ten.""Very well.
And, I say, Doctor, there may be somelittle danger, so kindly put your army
revolver in your pocket."
He waved his hand, turned on his heel, anddisappeared in an instant among the crowd.
I trust that I am not more dense than myneighbours, but I was always oppressed with
a sense of my own stupidity in my dealingswith Sherlock Holmes.
Here I had heard what he had heard, I hadseen what he had seen, and yet from his
words it was evident that he saw clearlynot only what had happened but what was
about to happen, while to me the wholebusiness was still confused and grotesque.
As I drove home to my house in Kensington Ithought over it all, from the extraordinary
story of the red-headed copier of the"Encyclopaedia" down to the visit to Saxe-
Coburg Square, and the ominous words withwhich he had parted from me.
What was this nocturnal expedition, and whyshould I go armed?
Where were we going, and what were we todo?
I had the hint from Holmes that thissmooth-faced pawnbroker's assistant was a
formidable man--a man who might play a deepgame.
I tried to puzzle it out, but gave it up indespair and set the matter aside until
night should bring an explanation.
It was a quarter-past nine when I startedfrom home and made my way across the Park,
and so through Oxford Street to BakerStreet.
Two hansoms were standing at the door, andas I entered the passage I heard the sound
of voices from above.
On entering his room I found Holmes inanimated conversation with two men, one of
whom I recognised as Peter Jones, theofficial police agent, while the other was
a long, thin, sad-faced man, with a very
shiny hat and oppressively respectablefrock-coat.
"Ha!
Our party is complete," said Holmes,buttoning up his pea-jacket and taking his
heavy hunting crop from the rack."Watson, I think you know Mr. Jones, of
Scotland Yard?
Let me introduce you to Mr. Merryweather,who is to be our companion in to-night's
adventure."
"We're hunting in couples again, Doctor,you see," said Jones in his consequential
way."Our friend here is a wonderful man for
starting a chase.
All he wants is an old dog to help him todo the running down."
"I hope a wild goose may not prove to bethe end of our chase," observed Mr.
Merryweather gloomily.
"You may place considerable confidence inMr. Holmes, sir," said the police agent
loftily.
"He has his own little methods, which are,if he won't mind my saying so, just a
little too theoretical and fantastic, buthe has the makings of a detective in him.
It is not too much to say that once ortwice, as in that business of the Sholto
murder and the Agra treasure, he has beenmore nearly correct than the official
force."
"Oh, if you say so, Mr. Jones, it is allright," said the stranger with deference.
"Still, I confess that I miss my rubber.
It is the first Saturday night for seven-and-twenty years that I have not had my
rubber."
"I think you will find," said SherlockHolmes, "that you will play for a higher
stake to-night than you have ever done yet,and that the play will be more exciting.
For you, Mr. Merryweather, the stake willbe some 30,000 pounds; and for you, Jones,
it will be the man upon whom you wish tolay your hands."
"John Clay, the murderer, thief, smasher,and forger.
He's a young man, Mr. Merryweather, but heis at the head of his profession, and I
would rather have my bracelets on him thanon any criminal in London.
He's a remarkable man, is young John Clay.
His grandfather was a royal duke, and hehimself has been to Eton and Oxford.
His brain is as cunning as his fingers, andthough we meet signs of him at every turn,
we never know where to find the manhimself.
He'll crack a crib in Scotland one week,and be raising money to build an orphanage
in Cornwall the next.I've been on his track for years and have
never set eyes on him yet."
"I hope that I may have the pleasure ofintroducing you to-night.
I've had one or two little turns also withMr. John Clay, and I agree with you that he
is at the head of his profession.
It is past ten, however, and quite timethat we started.
If you two will take the first hansom,Watson and I will follow in the second."
Sherlock Holmes was not very communicativeduring the long drive and lay back in the
cab humming the tunes which he had heard inthe afternoon.
We rattled through an endless labyrinth ofgas-lit streets until we emerged into
Farrington Street."We are close there now," my friend
remarked.
"This fellow Merryweather is a bankdirector, and personally interested in the
matter.I thought it as well to have Jones with us
also.
He is not a bad fellow, though an absoluteimbecile in his profession.
He has one positive virtue.
He is as brave as a bulldog and astenacious as a lobster if he gets his claws
upon anyone.Here we are, and they are waiting for us."
We had reached the same crowdedthoroughfare in which we had found
ourselves in the morning.
Our cabs were dismissed, and, following theguidance of Mr. Merryweather, we passed
down a narrow passage and through a sidedoor, which he opened for us.
Within there was a small corridor, whichended in a very massive iron gate.
This also was opened, and led down a flightof winding stone steps, which terminated at
another formidable gate.
Mr. Merryweather stopped to light alantern, and then conducted us down a dark,
earth-smelling passage, and so, afteropening a third door, into a huge vault or
cellar, which was piled all round withcrates and massive boxes.
"You are not very vulnerable from above,"Holmes remarked as he held up the lantern
and gazed about him.
"Nor from below," said Mr. Merryweather,striking his stick upon the flags which
lined the floor."Why, dear me, it sounds quite hollow!" he
remarked, looking up in surprise.
"I must really ask you to be a little morequiet!" said Holmes severely.
"You have already imperilled the wholesuccess of our expedition.
Might I beg that you would have thegoodness to sit down upon one of those
boxes, and not to interfere?"
The solemn Mr. Merryweather perched himselfupon a crate, with a very injured
expression upon his face, while Holmes fellupon his knees upon the floor and, with the
lantern and a magnifying lens, began to
examine minutely the cracks between thestones.
A few seconds sufficed to satisfy him, forhe sprang to his feet again and put his
glass in his pocket.
"We have at least an hour before us," heremarked, "for they can hardly take any
steps until the good pawnbroker is safelyin bed.
Then they will not lose a minute, for thesooner they do their work the longer time
they will have for their escape.
We are at present, Doctor--as no doubt youhave divined--in the cellar of the City
branch of one of the principal Londonbanks.
Mr. Merryweather is the chairman ofdirectors, and he will explain to you that
there are reasons why the more daringcriminals of London should take a
considerable interest in this cellar atpresent."
"It is our French gold," whispered thedirector.
"We have had several warnings that anattempt might be made upon it."
"Your French gold?"
"Yes. We had occasion some months ago tostrengthen our resources and borrowed for
that purpose 30,000 napoleons from the Bankof France.
It has become known that we have never hadoccasion to unpack the money, and that it
is still lying in our cellar.
The crate upon which I sit contains 2,000napoleons packed between layers of lead
foil.
Our reserve of bullion is much larger atpresent than is usually kept in a single
branch office, and the directors have hadmisgivings upon the subject."
"Which were very well justified," observedHolmes.
"And now it is time that we arranged ourlittle plans.
I expect that within an hour matters willcome to a head.
In the meantime Mr. Merryweather, we mustput the screen over that dark lantern."
"And sit in the dark?"
"I am afraid so.I had brought a pack of cards in my pocket,
and I thought that, as we were a partiecarre, you might have your rubber after
all.
But I see that the enemy's preparationshave gone so far that we cannot risk the
presence of a light.And, first of all, we must choose our
positions.
These are daring men, and though we shalltake them at a disadvantage, they may do us
some harm unless we are careful.I shall stand behind this crate, and do you
conceal yourselves behind those.
Then, when I flash a light upon them, closein swiftly.
If they fire, Watson, have no compunctionabout shooting them down."
I placed my revolver, cocked, upon the topof the wooden case behind which I crouched.
Holmes shot the slide across the front ofhis lantern and left us in pitch darkness--
such an absolute darkness as I have neverbefore experienced.
The smell of hot metal remained to assureus that the light was still there, ready to
flash out at a moment's notice.
To me, with my nerves worked up to a pitchof expectancy, there was something
depressing and subduing in the suddengloom, and in the cold dank air of the
vault.
"They have but one retreat," whisperedHolmes.
"That is back through the house into Saxe-Coburg Square.
I hope that you have done what I asked you,Jones?"
"I have an inspector and two officerswaiting at the front door."
"Then we have stopped all the holes.
And now we must be silent and wait."What a time it seemed!
From comparing notes afterwards it was butan hour and a quarter, yet it appeared to
me that the night must have almost gone andthe dawn be breaking above us.
My limbs were weary and stiff, for I fearedto change my position; yet my nerves were
worked up to the highest pitch of tension,and my hearing was so acute that I could
not only hear the gentle breathing of my
companions, but I could distinguish thedeeper, heavier in-breath of the bulky
Jones from the thin, sighing note of thebank director.
From my position I could look over the casein the direction of the floor.
Suddenly my eyes caught the glint of alight.
At first it was but a lurid spark upon thestone pavement.
Then it lengthened out until it became ayellow line, and then, without any warning
or sound, a gash seemed to open and a handappeared, a white, almost womanly hand,
which felt about in the centre of thelittle area of light.
For a minute or more the hand, with itswrithing fingers, protruded out of the
floor.
Then it was withdrawn as suddenly as itappeared, and all was dark again save the
single lurid spark which marked a chinkbetween the stones.
Its disappearance, however, was butmomentary.
With a rending, tearing sound, one of thebroad, white stones turned over upon its
side and left a square, gaping hole,through which streamed the light of a
lantern.
Over the edge there peeped a clean-cut,boyish face, which looked keenly about it,
and then, with a hand on either side of theaperture, drew itself shoulder-high and
waist-high, until one knee rested upon theedge.
In another instant he stood at the side ofthe hole and was hauling after him a
companion, lithe and small like himself,with a pale face and a shock of very red
hair.
"It's all clear," he whispered."Have you the chisel and the bags?
Great Scott!Jump, Archie, jump, and I'll swing for it!"
Sherlock Holmes had sprung out and seizedthe intruder by the collar.
The other dived down the hole, and I heardthe sound of rending cloth as Jones
clutched at his skirts.
The light flashed upon the barrel of arevolver, but Holmes' hunting crop came
down on the man's wrist, and the pistolclinked upon the stone floor.
"It's no use, John Clay," said Holmesblandly.
"You have no chance at all.""So I see," the other answered with the
utmost coolness.
"I fancy that my pal is all right, though Isee you have got his coat-tails."
"There are three men waiting for him at thedoor," said Holmes.
"Oh, indeed!
You seem to have done the thing verycompletely.
I must compliment you.""And I you," Holmes answered.
"Your red-headed idea was very new andeffective."
"You'll see your pal again presently," saidJones.
"He's quicker at climbing down holes than Iam.
Just hold out while I fix the derbies."
"I beg that you will not touch me with yourfilthy hands," remarked our prisoner as the
handcuffs clattered upon his wrists."You may not be aware that I have royal
blood in my veins.
Have the goodness, also, when you addressme always to say 'sir' and 'please.'"
"All right," said Jones with a stare and asnigger.
"Well, would you please, sir, marchupstairs, where we can get a cab to carry
your Highness to the police-station?""That is better," said John Clay serenely.
He made a sweeping bow to the three of usand walked quietly off in the custody of
the detective.
"Really, Mr. Holmes," said Mr. Merryweatheras we followed them from the cellar, "I do
not know how the bank can thank you orrepay you.
There is no doubt that you have detectedand defeated in the most complete manner
one of the most determined attempts at bankrobbery that have ever come within my
experience."
"I have had one or two little scores of myown to settle with Mr. John Clay," said
Holmes.
"I have been at some small expense overthis matter, which I shall expect the bank
to refund, but beyond that I am amplyrepaid by having had an experience which is
in many ways unique, and by hearing the
very remarkable narrative of the Red-headedLeague."
"You see, Watson," he explained in theearly hours of the morning as we sat over a
glass of whisky and soda in Baker Street,"it was perfectly obvious from the first
that the only possible object of this
rather fantastic business of theadvertisement of the League, and the
copying of the 'Encyclopaedia,' must be toget this not over-bright pawnbroker out of
the way for a number of hours every day.
It was a curious way of managing it, but,really, it would be difficult to suggest a
better.
The method was no doubt suggested to Clay'singenious mind by the colour of his
accomplice's hair.
The 4 pounds a week was a lure which mustdraw him, and what was it to them, who were
playing for thousands?
They put in the advertisement, one roguehas the temporary office, the other rogue
incites the man to apply for it, andtogether they manage to secure his absence
every morning in the week.
From the time that I heard of the assistanthaving come for half wages, it was obvious
to me that he had some strong motive forsecuring the situation."
"But how could you guess what the motivewas?"
"Had there been women in the house, Ishould have suspected a mere vulgar
intrigue.
That, however, was out of the question.The man's business was a small one, and
there was nothing in his house which couldaccount for such elaborate preparations,
and such an expenditure as they were at.
It must, then, be something out of thehouse.
What could it be?
I thought of the assistant's fondness forphotography, and his trick of vanishing
into the cellar.The cellar!
There was the end of this tangled clue.
Then I made inquiries as to this mysteriousassistant and found that I had to deal with
one of the coolest and most daringcriminals in London.
He was doing something in the cellar--something which took many hours a day for
months on end.What could it be, once more?
I could think of nothing save that he wasrunning a tunnel to some other building.
"So far I had got when we went to visit thescene of action.
I surprised you by beating upon thepavement with my stick.
I was ascertaining whether the cellarstretched out in front or behind.
It was not in front.
Then I rang the bell, and, as I hoped, theassistant answered it.
We have had some skirmishes, but we hadnever set eyes upon each other before.
I hardly looked at his face.
His knees were what I wished to see.You must yourself have remarked how worn,
wrinkled, and stained they were.They spoke of those hours of burrowing.
The only remaining point was what they wereburrowing for.
I walked round the corner, saw the City andSuburban Bank abutted on our friend's
premises, and felt that I had solved myproblem.
When you drove home after the concert Icalled upon Scotland Yard and upon the
chairman of the bank directors, with theresult that you have seen."
"And how could you tell that they wouldmake their attempt to-night?"
I asked.
"Well, when they closed their Leagueoffices that was a sign that they cared no
longer about Mr. Jabez Wilson's presence--in other words, that they had completed
their tunnel.
But it was essential that they should useit soon, as it might be discovered, or the
bullion might be removed.
Saturday would suit them better than anyother day, as it would give them two days
for their escape.For all these reasons I expected them to
come to-night."
"You reasoned it out beautifully," Iexclaimed in unfeigned admiration.
"It is so long a chain, and yet every linkrings true."
"It saved me from ennui," he answered,yawning.
"Alas!I already feel it closing in upon me.
My life is spent in one long effort toescape from the commonplaces of existence.
These little problems help me to do so.""And you are a benefactor of the race,"
said I.
He shrugged his shoulders."Well, perhaps, after all, it is of some
little use," he remarked."'L'homme c'est rien--l'oeuvre c'est tout,'
as Gustave Flaubert wrote to George Sand."
>