There's no fear in my heart
Got nothing left to lose
I saw my loved ones die
Oh, I swear that I won't give in
By God you'll never win
I'll fight for what's right
And nothing can stand in my way
Even if I get knocked down
I will stand my ground
And I'll never
Hide or run away
Love will prevail
By God it will
I refuse to fail
Love will prevail
Life’s become so cheap
So many orphans weep
They forgot how to smile
Oh, I cannot understand
Just how somebody can
Murder an innocent child
I swear their lives won’t be lost in vain
Even if I get knocked down
I will stand my ground
And I'll never
Hide or run away
Love will prevail
By God it will
I refuse to fail
Love will prevail
God made me free
You can’t take that away from me
Freedom is my destiny
I have a dream
And my dream is to see
To see all my people smile
See all of them free and proud
I feel the wind of peace
‘Cause with hardship comes ease
That’s why I won't lose faith
And I know that God is Great
So, I'll never
Hide or run away
Love will prevail
By God it will
I refuse to fail
Love will prevail
I won't run away
By God it will
Love will prevail
I refuse to fail