you ever feel like it's backpedaling even
though your following the rules?
you work long hours tolerated your
boss You get and annual raise and you
try to save money and budget where ever you can
and clearly you're working with no system for financial
success but something is very wrong
the rules are not working the system is
broken down you're barely making ends meet
let alone getting ahead
and retirement forget it your living day by day
You want to build financial security and wealth
but it's just not happening
So where exactly has playing by the rules
Gotten You?
So if you can change your outlook
Change some of your values and change your rules
You find that there is a whole set of rules out there
That are more Conducive for those who want to be rich
Conducive for those who want to be rich
one of the image
financial experts, Educator
successful investor and best-selling
author Robert Kiyosaki is about to give
you the information You need to implement
realistic achievable plan of building
and growing Wealth
Kiyoski is the
new york times selling author of among other
Books Rich Dad Poor Day
to date this series has sold twenty
million plus copies had worldwide
Today Kiyosaki shares his revolutionary
wisdom with You just like his rich dad shared
it with him
it information that can take you from
working for Money to
your money working for you
information that can set you free
The story of Rich Dad Poor Dad
is really a story of two different
fathers with two different sets of
values and completely different sets of
advice
0:01:49.490,0:01:53.000
so i don't mean to insult anybody or
damage your values really that was the
difference for example Poor Dad
Always said
go to school
get good grades
get a high paying job work hard live below your means
save money get out of
get out of debt
have a good retire plan
That was my Poor Dads Values  my rich
dad said you probably won't get rich
doing that because very few people get
rich following that plan
But you thought Saving Money Made You Money?
You take a look at this forty year run on the Dollar
The Dollar is designed
economically to lose money every single
year
so why would you save something
that loses money every year
and what this means was somebody on
retirement plans is that after you
retire The value of your dollar
goes down
and the cost of living keeps going up to
my Rich Dad that was bad advice and made
no sense again he has different values
this goes against everything you've
heard
it's very important that Diagram my Rich Dad
showed me as a little boy
was a diagram known as a cashflow
quadrant
and the quadrant is made up of the four
different people who make up the world
of business so my rich dad said in the
world of business
there's are E's and E's stand for employees
and employees that you can always tell
who will be our
by their core values and what the
0:03:19.139,0:03:22.870
employee whether the president or the janitor
of the company will always say the
same words the words are
i'm looking for safe secure job with
benefits
that's what makes a them an employees 'cause
our core values are security
the other other one of Four is
the S or the small business owner
of the self-employed
and again their core values will cause
them to use the same words which are
if you want it done right
do it by yourself
the S also means are usually Solo
Generally one person act that
tend operate by themselves
on the right side of the quadrant are
the B's
and rich dad said to be stood for was
big business or like Bill Gates Forbe's
defines big business as five hundred employees
are more
and their words are different the will say
I'm looking for a good system
good network and the smartest people I
know to help run my business and their
unlike the S they don't want to run the
company by themselves they want smart
people to run the companies for them
and then the fourth of quadrant is the  I
0:04:19.750,0:04:25.169
and I stands for investor these are
people who have money work hard for them
these people are people that people work
hard for them and these were people that
work hard for the rich
here so early on in my life it was my
my poor dad
who all is said to me you know Robert
go to school and get a high paying job
and so my Poor Dad Poor values was to be
an employee he wanted job security
promotions a steady paycheck and all this
and so it was my Rich Dad who said to
me so Robert
if you really want to be Rich
learn to build businesses it made more
sense to him to work hard to build a
business something you owned and something
that passed on from generation to
generation to your kids
whereas my poor dad said work hard
but by Rich Dad Said why would you work hard
for something you'll never own and you can get
fired from right away again that was a
difference in values
so Rich Dad suggested I learned how to
be a business owner
and learn how to be
an investor
and that's one of the big differences on
this side of the quadrant these people
here were for security
they work for money also
on the side of the here
they're key value that they want is
they want Freedom
they don't want to have to work at a job
anymore that i want to have to work for
the rest of their lives
so the beauty of building a Business and learning
how to invest is very
simply
that this is passive income you work
hard for a few years
but possibly for the rest your life in
income keeps flowing to you
Of All the businesses out there which type
do you choose?
one of the reasons i consider Direct Selling Business
a perfect businesses are simply because
the company will work with you to get
the business skills that make you rich
always remember that is not money that
makes you rich it's business skills and
that's why it's a perfect business they'll work
take as long as you like
0:06:20.360,0:06:22.479
to get the skills to make the money
and that's a lifetime skill thing
the part about it is too low start-up
costs and where else can you get in for
under five hundred dollars and get these
skills
for people who want to make the shift
over to the B Quadratnt which is what i
recommend for people
one of the beauties of the network
marketing company
is that you can do that
for a very low price and that's why i
talk to people about considering
network marketing
if you're to build a microsoft it would take you
few hundreds of millions of
dollars but a network marketing company allows
you to start at a very rate will be
patient within you they'll take their time
to transition over here
and the reason why that time is so
important to most people
is it takes time to change those values
and the most important thing is once you
take the time let's say it takes one year or two
years five years
whatever time the text once you see the
value
for the core values of this side and this
side your unstoppable
today i would never go back and get a
job why should i
i'd rather just stay on this side build
companies pay less taxes make for money
but the key as a person needs to change
to values from my Poor Dad to the values
of my Rich Dad
and that's when the values of network
marketing companies they allow you the time and
and very low cost they'll work with you to make
a transitional over there
the number one asset a person can
build is build a business that is the  smartest thing
you can do
you've been told to corporate ladder is the surest route
To your Success
Years ago I decided not to follow
the Corporate Ladder simple because
again it was values
you know my poor dad always said go to
school and get it high paying job with
the government a big corporation
but my rich dad said why would you
worked so hard at something you'll never
own you can't sell your job you can't pass
it on to your kids
so to me and never made any sense it
made more sense to build my own business
and hire other people
the other reason is that you really
don't have much control if you're in the
corporate ladder world
for example you can get fired at any time
or today we were we have whats Called M&amp;A
Stands for mergers and acquisitions it's when one of
the company buys anther company so you
could be a great employees
but the company that buys your
accomplishes just fires You
wait a minute
this sounds too good to be true
Like one of those Get Rich Quick Schemes
It's  not get-rich-quick formula you don't
just do it overnight it takes time
I still remember the first time I made
that transition was back in nineteen
seventy eight
when i fully quit my job
and i had to depend upon my company that
i was building to support me so I
understand the fear
the beauty
the most important thing to remember is
this
0:09:09.900,0:09:12.470
there's two kinds of people in the world
there are the types that will say you'll
never make it
and I had a lot of friends and family saying that
You're stupid don't do it
and the second type
where the people that said go for it  you
can do it
don't worry about it will cover you
so the most important thing is support
of friends and family
One of the beauties direct
selling company
is that they provide that personal
support to you
for as long as it takes you to make the
journey from the left side to my Rich Dad's
Side
You alway thought being self-employed was
living the American dream
one the challenges of being
self-employed is that
your your own boss here Your the solo act
Like in the S Quadrant your the
individual
you do it on your own
whereas in the B Quadrant you're a team
player you have to depend upon your team
and count on your team
So the problem with being an S let's say
you where in a traffic accident
there goes our income
and let's say you get older and you
haven't set enough money aside to
retire on that means you probably have
to work for the rest of your life
because you don't have anybody else to
fall back on not a team to count on
so one of the problems with the S although
most people say is most satisfying of
all work
It is a Solo Act and your totally on your own
personally i'd rather be a member of the
team
So they can count on me and I can count
on them
It Sounds like a smart move but change
It's So
Difficult
We all know the world has changed but
sometimes the hardest thing to change
Is Ourselves
and being an old guys the older I get
sometimes get more set in my ways
and i think that's one of the things that
a direct selling business offers people
why is the perfect business
they allow you to take your time to make
the mental emotional and physical
changes required
to move from the left side to the Rich
Dad side
I think that's a big thing it's a very
gracious It's a very elegant way it's
a patient way of supporting you in
making the changes of your life so
please remember change always creates
upset
but sometimes we all know
we have to make those changes
and if you know it's time for you to
make that change
than the perfect business may be a
direct selling business for you
direct selling
it is quite possibly the perfect business
for you
for more information contact the person
who gave you this video http://robertgallenariix.com