you
falling cop
copyrighted program and pride and editedinto the program
not primed
moan and all non and
gone and and and and
them and and and and and
weighed one hundred and my mom
there on the mainland
lol
him
corp
there
and
all
pag it
and
on or
then
n
you
the
win
inaudible on bottom of the part is to beefficient and one jump ahead of the law
breakers is essential that they beequipped with and mickey was all of all
the newest scientific equipment zappacoupled with the discovery of prime
identification of the criminal and hisarrest
let the public is willing to end doesspend the money necessary in this
division of law enforcement will resultin handicapping essential police work
not only that
but it will give the criminal anadvantage over the authorities the
chattering results to society
naal the true story all the batman
here
the golden or
flight
you're pretty young to be in a placelike this never mind the horatio alger
step and then we don't tolerate anattitude like yours in this institution
you will obey the rules of the peopleand school and conduct yourself in such
a manner will make your stay in as briefas possible every year to do
all right out to a year
according to your commitment you werefound guilty of petty theft and
impersonating an officer
realize that you're starting the wrongway don't you so i have to stay in the
eighteenth and i think he's talking toyou yet one might expect
i'm not in didn't which
uh... thank god
taking up landlord iraq stop shopping
we've got to do something about theflight kit now i think i'm not
practically everything you ship
money economic apply
work up at the national guard when thekids are having breakfast implied that
was
recipe a picture
which is getting all the attention he'sdoctoral
actually i'd recommend stomach now nowthat the contract and principles and
that
at comment on and we get rid of him todo we expect the line beginning
particulate
federal penitentiary in leavenworthkansas two years later
william edward
at age twenty one served one year forpetty theft impersonation liquor abuser
and that
that invite you think indexing specterwe'll do that
you've been personally a federal officeragain so what
so we'll be with us for three years atyour story look good
we might as well on the stand each othernow i don't think smart talk from
prisoners were don't know why dont
to make up your mind behave yourselfwhen you're here
if certain rules are not particularlyhard but we insist upon the main update
uh... you can do to flee hugo theydidn't get along with us
or you can follow the same court you'lldefinitely been in the habit of doing in
that case we have our old method ofdealing with lot method well if you're
interested it's easy enough to find outto maybe only with wouldn't tap into
your flight ok captain
st
as is the third week in solitary forfraud captain
pretty good well expressed personally idon't think it will be what we call good
how much longer to get to go six-monthmy coworker
with the land
antenna ended
void in court the virus olympus and nowthey have an exhibition is now let's get
'em out here
opioids get it out the atheist that isaid get off your texas into the young
men
wanting this prison doesnt toleratedozens of population
ever but you put it up mugs in thisplace but they stay in line around our
house what try getting out of line andyou'll soon find out that this joining
sub-type that remains to be seen
knocked up if you are not
just in case you decide to startsomething
reminder of the discipline is onspecialty
we're not interested in what you didbefore you came here
why you're here you i'll give you achance
we enough interested
chances are your opinion about methods
it would be rules or suffer theconsequences
in moscow
thanks paddle
exterior getting rid of you today freud
and get pretending need just said
we're getting rid of your ideal youdon't feel uh... wouldn't good riddance
of bedrock issues that we had to pay
make it above
i suppose i should ask what you're goingto do now i'd suppose you should do
which i would be quiet too many ofbusiness
but your way
remember though next time we'll be priyapreview
you won't come back here
you've got out the transaction take it
was hoping to stay out of my sightthanks wouldn't
immediate didn't trying word
earnings a large gap
and this time you're an architect that'swhat it says donut
serial ata baghdad
and don't start the usual line aboutrules and regulations
state interested me how you treatprisoners along i gotta stay here and
what or
saint occurred
right around it
everybody going on
tranny rest up and we're going to havethis alive but don't worry about me
would not do exactly site gender
built incentive that too
according to your education they haven'tgotten back so late may dot obc in you
know what you know that's what i'mafraid of
gin and tonic though floyd
will react and naal ok and don't gettough about it
just making and recession well save
you know those at six weeks to go ratherpresentation
words that i was played pretend and iwas an army officer
right now have a lot like pipe down
it makes him here
conduct going in
so what
unisom houston in san diego
still select
yourselves
communique became
to let you know mom consider season aweek from monday
which is to make it
we can't make it
we've got this name in one of them
see that you can't see
you won't lose nothing by
okay
sapir and
just go to the old record clinton st
and strong women
room floor
it didn't turn out
so tupac
from which you conclude i've learned alesson and then maybe is right
and congratulate yourself warden justnot interested in this joint already
breaking my heart take it easy wouldn'tmaybe back into the lord forbid ella
tell me how you wouldn't
welcome florida do you ever come back toalcatraz images when they could be a man
to spend the rest of your life byyourself
ever come back here it'll be solitaryfrom then on double or a capital they
won't be back i wish i could be surethat take my word for it
i won't be back
just outside the city of walla walla amotorist give the young man a lift
it an hardware and yet walking yet
acute world word dad
on large ideal i'll tell you what itried decided right we'd want to go
beers services radio on everything
at bc what we can get it
and
meanwhile about visible but but but butthe police
alters citizens i want to be on the topof that but i come back to that
license number and the to hold true tosay
that james at the moment all of thatpacking slip of the lapd administrators
of the beating the motorist thatdescribed as being six feet two inches
dot that they have been
why i didn't get that guided once
reflect his ego is hot
if you have to get a transfer
lloyd abandon the gothic another whichabound on the parking lot
itt_ stages he traveled south
holding knowledge among others a
other times of the demand
final in an auto caught me as an easygirl lloyd and his quest
here wanted it
yeah
folio son sent me where you see tom thesame place will be for the next ten
years
alcatraz
go outside and i wanted to hear whoskates line
weakens his might
sparked speculation it
mind you get an the small about thrillerbut usually well away from walla walla
the
and right
where'd you get my promoted it from aguide from texas
unfortunately his license plates were alittle conspicuous sciatic changed
uh... hot and you might call it then
what's the plan that status againstcitizen right money and
and black writing and i will make a hotair
regarding but the uh... in but they canrun into the city see what we can play
that watching kathleen going down hereit's happened yet
bag indicate one
internet radio at least nine extend
that sort of black what's going on
the bedding compounded sometime there'salways that political one hostage orbit
ntbntsb_ now and broadcastedregarding still automobile
and that
nineteen thirty seven bottle
license in the night column
line the nine walked at age six
nine victor water
late six
this license not registered to thiscarpet stolen from another vehicle
is copied but by then described asmiddle americans speed walking but two
which is width one hundred seventy twocollins rest karne documents
so wild ride on the debt right candidatebelated happy was on my lunch time
going into court gangtok anywhere onplace got blasted that's and we blacks
made become monogram
at least
maybe xbox
god
i think i had a we'll expediency look orinaccurate with all the time to get some
medicine persecute harry pottercharacteristic ambition contact
if you're architect the capital
hill activist
i cannot hummus hotdogs password
action kings
has heck
okay
can't
revealed
and and and and
and
mike and i don't know how many ninehundred background on my mind
that i had there
the development dot blot get out
but did not go down
uh...
jeff non justice and i didn't get to adouble whammy after you they'd and i'm
trying to do it as long as i can walk ongeorge okay guy and i sat biological my
money that did the sacraments too hotwe'll have to get another one
and
and aparthotel club good
motorcycle of about shop kidnapped by aband of the problems i think it's up to
that
light by column i'm the sidewalk
the prop
don't look out for this call occupant
that is dangerous
or
within twenty minutes every road leadingfrom the county was located
now the cop cookbook dot proper but thenin a world without being stopped
drive a question
released recover the highway patrolmanan immigration official joined in the
dyg antic manhunt
cross the border mexican off of theweighted eleven on the watch for the
finger minute spending two hours on theman and woman looted elite
and immigration offices by london'sincluding along the roads by the ban
gaya
affect our heart
but had that bit can decade
negation
dot money and and and dot com argumentand road and and and
uh...
the
down
that's what
packing up my conrad
right at and
the
you moment later pre-op riding on thehighway near the border
alone man walking along the road mailedin
okay
somalia again my i did i not get it istime and i am right industry might grab
them on my way home
expect that the belly of adventurebeginning to get
made
and
but the gunman italian
taylormade permanently off
dawn broke off of that would ban on dutyon my part and home with a big needed
rest
other officers with and picked up withit
relentlessly the manhunt went on
annette growing tiger about the planegunman
sometime during the night
lloyd made contact with friend
jainsingles
the ethnic day at the home just outsidethe along
ordered yet
look do you mind if i rest awhile anekshed out back in the house
i said the online the police state andthat's it
anything in your
local panel
within the one i think we are not the
knots
what white
their over there
you know that's not bad for you
vicky que emial
or a beer
thanks i'll try that
spt
but i want to
aryeh yeah i was looking for one monthtennis channel
what did he do
ilmo lisa postal archaic macgregor hadthe wrong play we don't know we're yet
i guess so maybe at some of the placedid you try and that is why i thought
that the other corner maybe work thatuh...
maybe so
attire that sahi faded
it
what i think that basically
our contract
program
done
whitney alice data one and they want tobe an ekg and that your do u that's what
you think i'll hang around here as longas i want
something you wait a minute
you've tried that guys are having a hardtime be able or what
no you're not quite a bit in the paperthis morning acute shuttle delivered to
one or two you can't get me i'm going toquietly make another crack
high-technology bracket combines side
about mexico
uh...
dedicate stakeout legislative actionamicably
it
and
mhm
investment on cap without being kingthat came out
cannot ac magnitude
underclass
unifying orchid
regarded by broadcasting what you meanbroadcast look
we've got a microphone line arepermitted we'd like to broadcast
reported by watch
he'd if you can get a mere from properlyin ladies and gentlemen
this is one of the most thrillingbroadcast we've been able to bring you
from the station
cape cod here that the one that meanthaving limited mimic a shot engineer
protected the opportunity inquirymeaningful unit but the big box
groups that you're going to do it
yes he's about to make it
all quite at what might be a pet shop
the what that mirror the officer wasusing i'd keep packing a change in japan
tobacco we'll try to catch instructionplease netbackup echoed fine
it
peak-to-peak right pocket apart
coffee and after i got up at the topcame up on that glove beginning if you
can't get expecting what i think
the crowded every minute there must beat least pre-op one thousand people here
emigration popular hypertension how todo that then joining the fight what i do
know if you get that all oppositionother countries to bring onto do medical
he steers and san diego dot their thathave been telling and able-bodied part
of a budget that self-confessed
uh... cape cod is getting ready to begetting the route
we thought we would do much but they'll
looked like the part of the white house
added the cattle prod
extremely that they're not act
medical
if i get into the bank
like seems to be everything looked atthe time
coca coca-cola it webinarsecond-guessing
project idea technically they can'tgetting hit flight booking by these
people have a pretty at a time
became fifty fukada
well content an interventional erodedwhite woman companion
but he's going to comply with unitedthen we can pick it up to crank up again
elementary
day
big if i could get there
beside alright plane
and
out
thank you
out part-time way
dot serrano
now can
right either after that
without
that might explode
giving yes wouldn't happen a whole
about how much can split and oppositesaid that i'm not getting that in smoke
document by wait a minute
keypad is going to fight again
what intellect and and and and
everything good w
d mining town my home town
i'm going to walk through the dot if youif you agree you we'd be keen i mean
if you can and then
who will be treated
kit kat at what time is done
walking up to the belt
what is not coming
everyone attends
when you can see the desperado
what did you got it
or that you have to take
but then you would think met with thecuban link
that dont it
it didn't help
he's picking apart again
coming connie pick-up
here
in just a moment to him as a nation ofour story
pl
pal
and real
and and
on
perot
on the
mhm
ingi
gold
mhm mhm
green dl
there's no question that it was the gasbombs was routed out the young men
example of the application of scientificmethod in the apprehension of criminals
resulted in the surrender of thecriminal without by the sacrifice of
human life
well it was combined in the mexicancousin
three apprehended by united statesauthorities and is now serving a
sentence than the federal prison
i am does not say
meinhold
madeline bond and bond and
was made and it's not known to man
the
and
and claire
the and and
the
calling
low-carb copyrighted program created byreal bandi
muscling legally allowed by the nationalguard dog is doing in the millions jane
rooney
but his grand male american by theeleven in time
weighed about one hundred seventy brown
mcmanus gave no longer while hollywoodlaws and within days of the agony and
had been mountain
where the dangers of mental rodent
i know you will all agree that it stop
warman who does not giving them theright kind of to to work with has no
right to complain that they turn outfourteen in perfect working likewise you
are the bulk of your car and if youprovided with an inferior or every
catalina you've no one to blameornamentation motor but yourself but
pollitt with we'll run the fact that imean and you have every right to expect
and you will get a of plain pastagetaway steadier burying exoneration
longer mileage greater reserve power andmaximum speed which the driver the
police problems in other words you canget by always coming up with real bandit
cracked company
because they demand all of the potentialqualities
the officials of thirty meetings citiesand counties identify real than the fact
that the gasoline used exclusively tofather emergency public service call
would be a good bargain give your carthe best governing that his work with
drop in at the red ant bites taken aview of that may be a bandit either
tomorrow morning and give you a call themeans of delivering police comparable
almonds by taking a border kind one ofthe old man the cotton level highly
recommended deafening in the west
it
here
tonight we again take pleasure inpresenting teeth
james e david's of the los angelespolice department keep dates
good evening friends
there seems to be a general there areonly a study of that so-called society
crooks
part of a higher title criminal
this is not true
it is of course
foregone conclusion that any person isgoing to fail at any game
outside the law
he may get by for months or even years
but eventually is going to wind upbehind bars that is certain
but they are not many criminals who willadmit this
only fifty percent of the society cooksintake source for transportation and
hotel bills
he was keep on the move continuously
and uh... the usual rounds of the nightclubs and parties political quiz poses a
big shot
show me a man who spent a lifetimeoutside the law
that i'll show you a man who died apauper
i'm not moralizing in making thisstatement it is a fact
a story that you will your tonightdefinitely shows that crime does not pay
in the hotel in downtown multi-mode
a man or woman are dancing
were very good dancer
her journey
i've been around
they're not that gets out
living in downtown
not only
how many people not many them um...
mending
in many
at present what do you need
i'm thinking of not going back
likening
add outline
here at work tomorrow
where
highs
over here
an awful came together
up and i don't know
and work tomorrow
that mr
i would have trouble getting a key andlet me try it
they are
now for a little drink rain gear alwayshave a full class with me iraq a proper
tonight he felt a little kid
here's a picture of your arm on theirhome yet
there that day
you stand up and i think doctor thatthey are nine we did not a bad looking
hombre gotta get the nation like a bear
really could everyone
and i'm not around
that's my goodness
thank them
sure i do
communion name wait a minute
implant worker and
are respected lieutenant take it easycompared plaque
and even though your name
necessary
online get tired of paying
hey you
you want to call me
won't be far
said health plan
i have to be
yet
grant ferret
julie kavner eisenhower
that'll be our right
i found that will be all
without bond
ice and i know monitoring
it when out
and here you are
used to his look to us
himansu down
that's a tiny
can't take it down
we'll see
it's a nice ring a ring
engagement
lives yeah
animation
mississippi will man that's a prettypenny ali standard
you've got plenty
of me
and again
okay
used to you
hw
men are getting somewhere
uh... sleeping
down
intelligent
coupon for a building
here
had
cellblock
on this
all well ite
it
a few nights later at another hotel inthe downtown district
beg your pardon i didn't see youstanding there
that died
i said to be watching or kaplan
who his words carefully
i don't believe i understand it
raxle and exports
do you mind if i join in the world
gm a stranger here in
and you know how it is handball i do
however i am not taking a walk
i kept going to have a copy of the fileinto my room
and so was i_ your army eyes showed me
baguio thank you
i think the rotor reservoir tapi
yet say actors registered
room on the floor how hide my views onthe eight q
to get better acquainted yet we we'lleverywhere
observatory
on the beach
old-fashioned financing
guru minimum
visit here
reasoning haha
exam rather happy about han
square
and then somebody along that line hereyour honor thank you sir
well cannot
you're young yet
maybe i can make something out
cerebral
into camp
you know i've been losing too much sleepliving that what you felt we'll be
living advice it yet
year
former reagan circles in my
etc
night leading the having
records over your marks of aboard youngwomanhood movement embassy lapping at
the start
i do i think the weather's mine maybethese apparent i've noticed
unity among
removes whom i don't think that thiscame to town within our product you are
not the case here
very probably if you let the dcm
i'll consider it
katie
i think that about the contact
now goodnight well see you safely tuckedin
aware of it
species door
at that
ensign armenia bapak doctor has talkedabout how do nothing but for all of your
shoe will however you have
academic candy just is what causedmoderate
w
us companies
chemical
hours later the bruised and batteredyou're recovering bodies leveling with
the stereo issued by the way to thetelephone
some of the hotel manager and notqualified official called the police and
effective date you models of therobberies one working alone responded to
the call
uh... there's going to try to cutyourself tell me what happened
and looked at me and i don't give them
accompanied by the clinton the lobbyingyou don't deal with it
i didn't think anything up but at thetime probably delivered
everywhere in had a drink at the blind
if they do that on the floor of thedimensional or before seven
ido impacted ltd
well we came up in the elevator thegathering he picked up a about document
with any other proposition one hundrednegative attitude ability in defensive
landmark fidel
or when i do you open the door willstill be into the room
except that i've been doing it struck me
any athlete meirink negativism nobodyproblem i've just been
checked my watch all
an equilibrium ice cream for helpingeach other do you
toria fingerprint of the than it
given to get to a doctor that fix them
allen has not been in the description ofthis man contacting
clinton not attempting to send when hehit me the first time a i thought a
filter once i denied that these his coatpocket
the breast pocket it had a continentwhen i'd told the pocket up held onto
the card
he grabbed a lot of it away from me butbut here the other people who see them
the are
evidently the last part of the news
and had it with this man's name will nothave a standard for
might be anything from them
firmly ingested through an edge to them
fdr_ i want my ring back
i don't care about anything else i don'twant the ring back
uh...
knock at the borders must begin theinterminable top trying to find a man
who was your name and developers fdr_
however we are the portable recordbarbara the market always hoping against
hope but he'll find a named handlingthere
the bar
balkan
bosses
diversion
walsall
linkedin
among dream on record
the neil
sanderson
he didn't headed shitter
here too
needed
view
staging area
that we are true
at a time when shifted charles b fiveeight eleven weight one hundred
seventeen blonde hair blue eyessuspicion robbery
nineteen twenty six nineteen twentyseven that's lemon remember operations
in description programs digital areappreciated
will be addressed even on the recordpart of the past but
okay for
speed detective mark
yair pharmacy seventy mister taylor marksome more sample is robert the chairman
project name shaker
lives a rather than walking around inthe history of the remaining houston
removed at least or no removed two
but none of my business under the coversroom duck pond and of adopting at this
point i think that these trees wipinglet a little over the number of mine
a game
motherhood to clean the place and wherei want to leave the game
opening up in a painted out so it'suh... living in the plot to blow up
but israeli upto
remotely
when he and i think that the templeimportant numbers written on the wall
made america but not really restrictedyou know a thorough going to be sure
that you know that they can you bringyour liver you know anything about the
fellowship in not never paid attentionto biggest coming when they're going to
get ready nobody ran around them
you get people into a dozen yetindependently ronningen you know
anything about his girlfriend neff
militant union were
you know anything about any phone calleach other and he made
system that part of what you placeddon't know that the other i don't the
you know that i just returned here whydon't you and i can find no hempstead
almost one delivering them to bother
with about the roar of approval i didn'tknow the problem
you wouldn't mind that when the barbersomewhere in that room with a will be
working for the overlook
the up but the the return of the balconytime recruitment but
then one day almost a week everybirthday
made the final who
the uh... the again i'd like to thatwere worded with
and invented crazy though with that andhave a group of women room right landing
look i think you have blamed if youwanna you know what i like about you
lose your spirit of cooperation yetlengthened to help them
well-intentioned letting the will leadto it
the then isn't bad but in
the there
rather than martin
with a reporter for the feel likethere's a lot of income
randomly
mondale woman written
that'd be the
the
but alot of the
beaver them too
record number
the ran or for
mine
but the problem
i've got mr shared her write what iwanted
but they've had ordered by detectivemark
employees not private plan for the cap
finally began calling the number sixnine four five
within every possible alternative in
uh... mister schaffer then
remember mom at
work out which should read
uh... what
are lower
i want charlie shavers
action
uh...
really are operable about battle uponthem with all the more they are
it but not normal
them in desperation market the numberand also the album federal investigators
bob either through the telephone company
other than the militant phone number
i've tried everything that was an doesnot want to be a long distance calls
within one hour that number is youhaven't done anything about their
montana than then another million to one
them on the trip is called
problem but you want to know six monthsof luck with the gain surround the
parliament get out of the
report
where we're going to with with theproblem with that they will not or go
far enough
admitted that the pure worker
work as long as you're wonderful onquitting that
what no with a look at that
wellman their demand
six nine four five medford oregon
to seven or template
working outside i think i can rightthrough the content of charlie shape
uh...
people believe liberal
these are the two two seven org andplease
where people charles b shoot
meant one of the rather than a lot andincluded
notify more rabbit forty five minuteslater
the late maybe
at different that
uh... limit that that given by you thatthat position
paul remembered buildup of the mostarmed with with the but that isn't what
bobby caper
in net but are looking into the lead andone day at the railway station in that
book
right annual market collected by thename paper
uh... that it will return habitat birdback for trial but what if something
happens that you'll be able to defenditself would do anything to keep that
get tough rajitha nanum yes but you'vealready spent two days in the hospital
were not well enough to be a no plazawithout the day the perspective of the
of the or k_ hair coating understandableit had
along to your incomplete but doesn'tthat mean that in my life
while at the mild line like into cattleuh... what we know
and back in the butt of panic button ontop of a political beliefs
at allied attorney excitement
market
oh
off but not meant you realize that thismight be next or every one of the right
now
that
handcuff and not a completely lawful areplica lip often there
helpless other major remove mahalbookclub bookclub notifier
happily places in the public by thecredit from top companies article could
be pardoned field
that might get landed eat the scene atthe battle reflects paper prize pickup
little by little didn't include that
upholding prison
about his hand up we cautiouslyhypothetical about his ankle difficult
kind of a pledge to the end of thekingsport and on and off
then no big deal fingers of dawn pushedback the curtain at the white knight
thing they would open up the gradepopping island at the carter he
predicted with the president opened thefront door tv dead and that can help
our political upon the brief thing beginelmwood wiped out the fugitive takes
bargains around
out being shipped
salt of the office of the sort of aprintout
highway patrolman william snail reportfor duty
uh... in england and i might
then they get away from a famous loversare going up but they had to be great
and avoid a man if and when i still intown
bo
that they don't know tomorrow and forthat the cut
description for the npf_ right here
let me let let the customer that thereare likening yeah getting these dead not
to them and we get started
please have a small again
uh... because i have a credit card withan eleventh-hour mailing regular
epidemic
resident determined that the other thingthat did the lead normal lives have been
on the web and moving in the mid levelin the living room the job
rather than by the road and that isgoing to do that
in there that that
word we're going on at that time online
require held up a little while ago drpoint com visit my aunt world events but
they wouldn't find a mile a little aveyou can get ok it
laying around
worker lead right now
well again i thought i know that when weget over that i had
that way
ear yet but in the telephone offices
elected last
but people adam
a command
and i think that it
let me get if you have to be that waywallet was stolen cousin suspects
if they like it was just up with thatthat that was
that way camping
at the license number that uh... cut jobyeah right here dot check on that
about this paper the description and atthat nobody can occur again in a manner
their there
erythromycin may be contacted
bakit located
so i can
became a description of that but nevergot a little more
five eleven
well i think we've got you waiting totake me back or
bedtime get compiler let that get youback with the atlanta
difficulty of it
but
found that uh... you know copper
uh... though
well i think
level by the description
define what that we got it man
and that the coroner
yet
rambo was sentiment is happily
some brands of what you might call fairweather friend but we'll ban the
practice of kind of friend up never letsyou down
no matter how hard the growing after theother demands of unforeseen emergencies
regardless of weather conditions riogrande iquest gives you more than the
maximum performance of with his people
the drivers of your emergency publicserving cause discovered that backed by
testing all brands of motor fuel
then they rolled up fifty five millionmiles of the hottest fastest kind of
driving over california highway usingreal democrat exclusively
if you want that kind of a friend
giving your more than more efficientoperation and save you money in the
bargain
left a man of the red and white riogrande decision in two days
riding tomorrow morning
fill up with real round the clockgasoline
that and that the police car performanceof your neighbors cost
that police caught efficiency in yourown with real vanderkloet a favorite
gasoline of those who died below
and those who think the most
of their proper
now again we hear he faced
desperation of the manchester
and his determination to escapepunishment for his crime
caused him to pay the supreme penaltyfor is the
no stigma attached to be the detectivemorris who lost the fugitive
lecture rentals
who's gonna chairperson actually is everto gain freedom
in most cases the sadness the attackpenitent help us to defend himself at
all events shavers crime failed at thatthank you keep davis
bd
little legal adviser told by the end ofradio broadcast to deny would manage a
window werner
and
the the
but
a
the
letter subject lindley reading of thenight
coriolan
calling
all part of the copyrighted programscreated by real branding
networking returns on the bottom of thereligion card will get to argue that
we're going to bed button
needed in atlanta with world no wound
off a third of the law conduct many ofthe with investigating but it is no
speed record for what it takes fromtheir own brings them back but maximum
be safety an economy
every one of the difficult knows butthis time but it was real bandit back
got believed that there will be on thewall three cards and into the fire
engine
and other public service called whereverhe told than any other brand
yes most of the private limited arenewsreel bambi practical blueprint
but they are not the only one
all the problems of motrin although notwith government is really superior
governing stockport delivers who therecovery and more miles with great
arether power and speak
unique envy your neighbor
if you want police proper format foryour call although that may bring to the
nearest red and white rio grande daytontomorrow morning and getting
take on the paint will be open to crack
and you will understand private minormode if you will of the most highly
recommended governing in the west
or pull measure more complete motoringlater
dot rio grande decrypted kapiti
and
but
do it
is our pleasure to present a method onthe telephone bamberger legal copy
allocate
thank you doctor in peru evening ladiesand humbled
today's so are planned parenthoodwriters telephone
there's not a single outpost of the lawwork out of the lee the envelope
today that i'm going to be no sheriff'soffice
which i have the honor to be the head
is in common with every other lawenforcement office in the city
equipped in a minute
beneath the best of the worst incriminal element
crimes today are of course the thingthat they were years ago
where there is still there
but no longer that the share of helpfulhead of a prostitute second man through
the practice that's it
that scientific method to imply to bringthe criminal to death
better there and patients an intelligentdeduction
coupled with expert analysis
contributed to the solution of the casewe are about to get
asia product that it
at that wilder a coupla get right on topof all pop records by contemporary
little while ago that are bad light backat the back the butcher dot both the
line for twelve
hope
have tried
chicas just a few hours ago
all clout
heartbreak that great
but the quiet fell back already about
no i'm not for a couple of monthsnorvasc dorm data
it
right but what about
date
he's arava right or that the
off about the crime of accounting almostafter five p m hire a state of new york
that update under the command
offered over historic alcohol the top
overturned a woman had been the bobtalked into the purple san fernando
valley
pops picturesque pictorial beepingdefied the meandering mojave
and out into a dusty road that leads tolangford twelve
megan
right over probably or
wait a minute
to go to vote
looks like the man was killed here onthe road and ride over their yet
at the field made those marks near thebig batch of blood
looks like the killer as to the whilehere
bennett fairly small man how do you knowwell i looked at the body this morning
in the following bright they can sellwell anyway we know the two men going to
carry the body
after than just one man and i woulduh... that's what i think it
old worth about it now
what that is left of it
no dental work for the persian influence
brigade whereby um...
certified by a wouldn't do them justabout
cannot go
about bringing everywhere
let me have always been the writtenabout over
historical out about a hundred yards andon the senate that part
you've got a ride on the list of theseclothes and things follow-up i go ahead
there is a suit
knitted sweater ananth
i gotta like it
ochoa
notepad
concept
and two
any labels on the quote
allah
uh... or there
habit a man was killed my commentdragged over here
blood whether in fact the game
planning a puppet nothing
their retirement
and for the last part
the civil that looks like this tobritain on the other side looks like
there she'd off of a memo pad
yes uh... that's just what it isoracle's if they don't know if it were
reflect the and
notes and some figures on that uh...
i can't make 'em out though
i'd like you know
we'll see
the them it so that they could backwhatever little bit magnifying glass
yes that's the best
now let's get busy and their this fellaa lot of taken in march after them
losing any other identification thatmight be here
all
realizing that what the month that wayin the dark but people to come over one
thousand one set up a independent boardwhatever the identity of the victim
but by the on the part of a blueprintfor repair
uh... paper
well that's not a lot of figures i can'tbelieve that seems to be a complete set
right there on the back website
eighty seven
seventeen
that might mean anything that's right
them to the bank memo i figure theymeant that much money moats and natural
assumption head of the total opening aresolution of the case and we were
before and i'm not so sure about thatblaming
and going up to a demonstrate what i canfind out in the security state that at
in building about a recognized this memoshe maybe not but that i got my my
gems
this is the only clearly havegrammatical ekata
and no i'm not going to pass it up uh...
which a lot that banks and even iamthings when i'm gone
good morning they are helping rarely hasa
i'm looking for the president of thisthat played out here right now we're
going to lunch
probably will be back burner to also
maybe i could help me will maybe
animal overstate shipments and then havebeen accounted on a couple of tornado
chip i'm george dot cashier the bank
well maybe you can help me of that
you see we have a little killing downour neck of the woods sometime back
found out about it just after christmas
well we have in got hide nor hair others
a clue as to who committed the murder
anything we found that this little pieceof paper
uh... with that but
faceted
ever see a piece of paper like that
here
and uh... yes of course
at one of our memos
we keep them right here on the counterfor the customer to use actually kept
the same kind of that
so that means i a man was originally adozen of the damage in the best we got
the less chip into these beds but you'veever the first time that we do this
particular time
as a set of
figures on the back
right here
eighty seven and seven m act
no analyst at standard life
but is there a possibility that thosefigures mean anything to you
the city at
lead
i don't know about the other writing butmister stevens the bank president of the
world grows bigger down to one of thecustomers and i've got to know which
customer
figures look familiar
let me think
lol
it would be the one
c
right judge i do remember somethingabout that
seems to me i remember transactioninvolving that amount uh...
right around the holiday
lemme think
as he there was christmas with what iwas thanksgiving
and back close armistice day
right around the early part of the web ado you remember the customer was well he
wasn't exactly a customer you see thisman came in and mister stevens creek
area
i recall the at a bank account beckysomewhere and the weather transfers
funds out here
image of passing through here said he'dbecome strand
there's a telegraphic transfer if iremember rightly do you happen to
remember the name
the laptop and but
i could check up on it
but it was built recall telegraph officeand asked them to go through their piled
up a couple months ago and maybe we canget a double check up
it
kurdish state bank today speaking
ox
and at that
just you will please
is that the name
all right
x
heading out
and let them know
all right thanks a lot
and a man's name rupert hate
cv should have received for the money inthis trial right here
anna's anderson the him
it is
will today
received a security state bank of thenew till eighty seven dollars and
seventy nine cents in telegraphictransfer of funds
at request of peoples state bank detroitmichigan
happen to remember what this fellowlooked like little yes uh... you see
this business with a lot of the ordinaryand i noticed the man rather closely
had reddish brown hair as i recall it
but the way the around eleven thirty ahundred forty rather slight
at long taping fingers seemed ratherrefined
and i'm a blizzard should i believe saywhat his business was
yes i uh... i believe he said he was aprinter going west look for a job that
sounds like the man we found our life
you're a member of the was alone or idon't think so it seems there was
another fellow within i didn't have anyconversation that you have been though
so
president they particularly tensions are
seems like he was smooth shaven seemsort of quiet and reserved
i noticed that needed to be pretty closeattention with a major some british war
bonds yield you don't happen to knowwhere they lived well he was here they
are really gave us the address the grandhotel
volume i talked to japan
he might have a line item well thank you
i'm water straightens and ended incalifornia
and checking up on a couple of barsagain to hear about the first and last
month
domain adm_ another bombing walks thelevity
at at at at the moment the dayton andthat they were in that that few weeks
indicate
uh... epip irritant
any brennan
bout thirty but but but but one
weapons with them
the dramatic i was broken down
headed out of roses verizon whitehead
theater at the record
and characters their pinnacle new yorkit
and checking up on the cat named in oneof the named well
a member of the double booking so thatthat would be it for
look them up but the panic roaming isn'tthe right there
november ninth state for
uh... the un and part of the mca if itis the money to buy food for work and
baby is a good don't have any record ofa woman in this case the one twenty th
at work
that he did it makes the from wyominglet him have biven started on the or
what kind of car was it more thanthrough and go
whatever that was the
germany getting a bit too because therecall how this man walks look with
uh...
there was five nine attendances songnifty way around hundred inflicted on
bomb minimal as muslim yet legal led aduck dot it bracket athletic build a
slight burst out of that and i thinki'll start looking for that young man
therapy return to resolve a dumbartonyou know of any of the compact adaption
of effective edward baca of the poetasking here that the clinton breaking
the movement of the day in law
all with thirteen point big time
me one phone
at the bottom information and then dobusiness with them
intimidate noting about in their kids abig deal
we receive them unless you have to
and felt quite a large quantity of wallbond
in some time ago
you know here for about twenty dollars
that often got the money from thebarnesandnoble savings account
according to our records you talkedabout a hundred dollars another counter
left for california anything more aboutamerica that yeah actually i think that
several programs about his accountantfinally transfer the balance of eighty
seven seventy nine too often with yourrecords show he lived well it was the
vendors to give us respectingsixty-eight ferries g the thing going
over there as they were the landladymight know
uh... you with a buddy yet they arelooking for information in a cat named
heba i haven't been that he think thatlike me
like even talked about filter what sortof public
yun quiet dot boy english nine eateninfo to do in the warrant thank you
how long did it
moving evening about the fact that youlive in
you need to know that that would be anactive sometime around the middle of the
report card september
donna d'amico walked in with a one nightin told me he'd be gaining new robot
it did what they any of the remotecontrol
i got the impression that the plotbarnwell
i didn't see him it any eighty-eightembankment there
and uh...
wanted to do that
doubts about the lack of october
let nick i would have meant a lot
uh... avenue apartment
adeptly e and v
are taking
all yet
day
the
hope
at world
well america that with that the publicthat they
according
i've got an idea about this case
anywhere developer that right bank itwould have done it from quote by the
bank
frontier and but for the telegraph ofwealthy
ready replete dot with randu telegram wethink might have been sent from here on
november the twenty ninth last year
you see if you've got a record of it
complete right for them
we're going to come from
if not move upon them for peoples statebank detroit michigan sent by a fellow
named pain
we are
transfer of power and accountantbirthday activity seven adult laughlin
frankness
that helps a lot
that name they didn't have to have said
elected sold on december fifth one ofour customers into the the mister fadely
opened an account for transferring somefunds from a bank in detroit that's the
one how much money what the standardizedwrote judge it was rejected one of the
students
from london one minimum wage when wouldbe in the last uh... a nineteen no i
don't know
the nine hundred dollar withdrawal ofthe family that the last time for a
political nicely uh...
and all is detected on the twelfththrough the date of december night
endorsed by a manicure others not herewell that would indicate that they would
eleven december ninth emma
systems i don't believe it neverthelessabout even out there for at least amount
that we found that will discuss ruin agood for you
minimal white
at W watch
sent us a statewide san
what that this what's on the flight
five-feet nine of ten digit tong
way to get around a hundred and sixtytwo sixty five pounds lieutenant
reflective
around please
other athletic building well i thinki'll go over to that leaking state
address
bubble jobs back on the late in the bestnow the dome of the information that a
man for the name of what might be abetter but it left sometime in december
bubble viable dot lovely lama beingabout directing that mail a deadly we
probably won't like
involving
but that doesn't mean that that the bestfor the blind repeated on the theory
that the fed over brothers indicatedthat the really did made by hand wake up
ever
lots of other and there were no right
thinking here yes
there's estimate the square the murdercomplete set a date works for the murder
of a perfect
similar to the chief of police and bookwhat has been particularly at that the
other one
at the bank at the front of a policeinvestigating their report and i asked
them to uh... to the post officeanything out
yes delaware up to the motor vehicleapartment aspen the check up on that
overall length of the other stateregistration
but i got a letter of the character ofthe president to
asking to find out my thoughts on thesupport others
about that check tickets for the
and their promise to stardom andcommunication accomplishing
at about a beloved by that
giving a complete description of what'sfrom the mouth all the places up another
coach pat within the special supplied tosan francisco there just to put a well i
guess that are keeping busy for a while
pad
it
hundreds of cooperative at the pump inearnest
detective sergeant carmarthen richard onaccount takeout for making the rounds
for help
elaine
sunblock
one day they confirm whether there was akind of making a big mcdonald in every
window when
for
if he already you transcript
it one left
hectare
settle
legal turkey okay what's the idea that iwould let alone whether individual in
making a big mistake mister ever neverbeen in san bernardino well maybe not
repudiate what waiting to happen in sanbernardino
but we are gone
mob will return the family nobody andlegal machinery began to turn
covering the trial
although he admitted his name and thathe knew well today slightly he's got the
main thing to them
on april ten people talking trial
district attorney george johnson cabinetavailable parade of witnesses kilometers
fellas
escort challenger an expert devotinghandwriting m
actually assembled and ready to defendand walked to the victim over today
i would like to have you examined theuh... and what your butt
eleven running the man at the same asthat but on the hotel register log
on the telegram sent them on
there's no way some of the better watchis the handwriting you walked into that
part of the check marked exhibit beingkept in corona california on december
ninth
the signature objects i'd in sanfrancisco reading the navy
added autocrat
is that the signage or whoever they iwas not
as identical with the handwriting atjake's watch at all
this is all the way
facilitator
you're employed by the western union tolet government yes
and i live in seven muhammed you'llrecognize the defendant what yet
here's a man who sent a telegram detroitband beckett at all
but the government
your may expect a graphic in microscopictests and taken the scene where the body
rupert he was found
and did you make similar analysis ofcentered in the clothing of the
defendant walked i didn't end with asimilar
they were identical thank you
that they had a will you tell the courtand jury does what happened in relation
to the defendant now on trial
on the evening of november twenty fourblasts
well i was on the way the law's biggestlook at the money property i have a
prayer
a car broke down on the road but whenteam up with the biggest
eyes dot blot silver lake
friend of mine that that runs a garage
took care of his garage for that nightdid you see the depended on that night
issit
added that he walked into the garageinto the woods other jessa lee
sold on the roadways
alot for the way down the road with thevienna companion in the government yes
it so man in the car that had to bedescription the officers gave this
mandate that will say anything aboutthis man really fit
i'm riding with the dead
if any reason for this remark note
for george sure at the defendant was inthe copy of a man who went to date
description on the night of novembertwenty fourth i thought this was a
symbolic gesture thank you
another loss
assaults
is the kind of jayesh what's really todo you
he's my brother
if you would anytime introduce yourbrother to any official of the bank of
italy in los angeles
but some of my brother came to losangeles
said he was driving drunk on or thecapsule that some of them seconds
produced some of the bank
guaranteed a signature
what needed to use it opened it up
use google pretty what reason did hegive for using that name
incident at some probably used
much couple
on the use of the bombing
but what's
what is your address at this time
some crippled
and what is the reason for you beingthere
i was convicted los angeles grand lux
connection with my brother spectacleregular stores that as well
attache
euro altercation per cent of thedemocratic ab
if you see the body of the manidentified as we are pretty i'd have
upon what you'll be cured identificationof this bit by a comparison of the
handwriting on the sheet of memorandumpeople from the victim's body
with special needs of the normally whatother meats
comparison of the victims descriptionfurnished by witnesses of your
with that of the dead man then you cansay project
that the man whose body was part of thedesert near langford well
wildblue pretty like that
at all
side of the people case
really generated by the defendant
baking parts
guilty of murder in the russian duringthe
uh... always secure the standards of thebook
people anything you'd like to say at the
built on the crack
is not a special privilege gasoline
is the specified choice of the officialsof thirty leading cities and counties
throughout california and he usedexclusively to power other emergency
call
there seems to want to cut governmentbut what we're reporters in california
the same final copy will the sped policecars and other public service department
over fifty five million miles ofcalifornia highway
through all the hardships and weatherchanges of a single year
as bangalore opium patronage ofthousands of people
i feel confident that real grandpa willwin your approval to when you get to the
trial
saying we open the plane prep
you see swatches police and firedepartment chair of the red ant bites
rio grande a station in yourneighborhood with the same we'll go into
cracked up to mean you will to poweremergency public service call
that's fine you two will begin gettingsqueezed compliments for your call
when you bring them tomorrow morning andi the family we are going to be there
for a pamphlet we'll run the crap
the government prepared by officials foremergency call
the governing prepared by a great armyof workers
all emergency
october fifteenth
two years after his crime
batteries fuel to the state's highestcourts
lofts walked up the steps of thedownload san quentin
sent there by a lot of cheatedmemorandum people
without an apparent on launched thetruck
the brutal murder we'll prepare withevent
today
this case is referred to as anoutstanding one
covering the most circumstantialevidence
and managers on the long haul garlandson hard again they did not get into the
lemon benign and and money and and andnegligently was in indonesia and lynn's
old movies with
the
a
this is an elevator
fabric lends me
hiding you good night
rearmament
guide