This is "like". This is "dislike".
6 years that Thailand's three Muslim provinces
have been under emergency decree
Countless number of people was affected by the unjust power and control from government officers under the decree.
Emergency decree isn't a good law
Those who were arrested got tortured in order to make them confess
This is not right
Because when being tortured, those who couldn't stand the pain,
they just had to admit even though they didn't do anything
This is not right
If they really did wrong, there should be evidence and punishment accordingly
Entering the 8th year of violence in three Muslim provinces
Many groups and civil society organizations have been established with the same objective
and determination to see peace once again in the areas
As well as the Civil Society Network Against Emergency Decree
that has been continuously campaigning against the decree with different activities varied from releasing statements
holding different campaigns like kicking out the decree
by driving classical cars and motorbikes,
to organizing a people's forum against the decree
Recently, the activity has been lifted to international level with "Post Peace Campaign"
by allowing local people to express their opinions and intentions towards this emergency decree on postcards
as reflections of their feelings and make their voices heard among representatives of international organizations.
Today, we're going to make an action by collecting voices of people who want to call for stopping emergency decree
by writing short messages that we want to express to the United Nations on these postcards
and we'll send all of them to the head quarter of U.N. in Thailand on this coming 10 December which is the Thai Constitution Day's and also International Human Rights Day
The campaign to express people's feelings on postcards
has received good response from local people,
especially those working in city area in Pattani that got effects from such decree.
I hope the situation will be normal soon so I can work more conveniently
When going to pray or elsewhere during early morning,
I don't need to worry that I'll be searched by the army or arrested for investigation
I think there must be campaign against emergency decree
This emergency decree has been enforced for a long while
and its enforcement has violated basic rights of local people in our areas
We no longer agree with the emergency decree enforcement in our areas
If it's still necessary to use the emergency decree then there must be justice
If there's no justice, then it should be repealed
The movement of the Civil Society Network Against Emergency Decree doesn't only aim to have the decree repealed
but also to reduce the condition that could lead to endless violence
Time has proven that the emergency decree couldn't reduce the incidents
and it even creates hatred among the people who were affected by the unjust power and control of officers
Therefore, should the New Year present that the current government of Ms. Yingluck Chinnawatra
would give to people who oppose the emergency decree in three Muslim provinces on this coming 19 December be repealing the emergency decree?
We oppose the emergency decree!