Many people take their lives every day because of this taboo.
The Bible is a very dangerous text.
In the FPÖ [Austrian populist party] they said that homosexuality is a culture of death.
If it's not possible to sacrifice just a little bit of tradition in order to give teenagers the feeling that
they live in a less threatening environment and they can therefore avoid taking their own lives,
then you can not really talk about loving your neighbour.
The Bible is a very dangerous text. There are several passages which incite homophobic hatred.
There is one, for example, that says that if two men sleep with each other, both of them must be killed.
It says exactly: "their blood shall be upon themselves". This is in Leviticus. It is of course also in the Torah.
In the Qu'ran it doesn't say that they should be killed, but that they should be punished.
There are crazy and fanatic people everywhere. The probability that someone opens those books and kills someone because of that
is there as a result and will be always there, as long as these texts continue to be blessed as God's word.
There are many priests who speak in favour of homosexual marriage.
but each one reads what he wants and interprets what suits him.
I think homosexuality is illegal in 71 countries and in eight of these countries it is punishable by death.
Acceptance of homosexuality is as low as two percent in some countries.
In India there are temples where you can see figures having homosexual intercourse, and of course those also having heterosexual intercourse.
In Japan and in China it was also like that, you can appreciate it in the arts, and in literature.
In Peru and in Ecuador there are lesbian teenagers who are committed into clinics where they are raped because their parents don't know what else to do with them.
The archbishop of Oaxaca, Mexico, said a short time ago that no clean and honest woman or man would like to be homosexual.
Some others spoke against our right to work as teachers.
Last year between 800 and 1000 rabbis; I don't know if only in the USA or worldwide;
said that homosexuals are to blame for the earthquake in Haiti.
Berlusconi said, for example, that it's better to treat women the way he does, that it's better to treat women the way he does
than to be gay, even though he sleeps with minors!
Not only right-wing politicians speak like that, but also for example, one left-wing politician,
Evo Morales from Bolivia said that the reason why there are so many homosexuals in Europe;
which is of course nonsense because in Bolivia there are just as many as there are here and
they just hide themselves more there because they cannot live as freely,
exactly because of people like him who instigate homophobic ideas like that,
He said that the reason that there are so many homosexuals in Europe is that our food here is genetically altered.
When homosexual marriage got legalized last year in Argentina, the archbishop of Buenos Aires
Said it's a war of God.
Of course he found support in the Bible for that.
They say it's an anomaly and also something unnatural, but they don't know that homosexuality
is documented in detail in 500 species and it was registered in 1500.
We are not so different from the rest of the animals. Homosexuality is observed especially between intelligent species,
for example, between monkeys.
There was no homophobic behaviour found among animals.
The problem is that at school they speak a lot about racism, about acceptance of minorities,
but they don't speak at all about homophobia. They always leave that out.
Most frequent swear words in every school playground, according to the union of teachers of Germany, are "gay" and "faggot".
The teachers don't intervene and many of them even support that.
Excuse me! Couldn't you do that at home? It's disgusting!
"We'll play a joke. Are you ready?" and they say "yes, of course".
For most teenagers it's not so easy because it takes a time till you accept it, since it's so frowned upon in society.
Children don't have contact with other homosexuals or they don't know that they do,
and that's why the suicide rate among homosexual teenagers is much higher than among heterosexuals.
That's why it's very very dangerous to use the word "gay" in a negative sense.
Also lesbian teens suffer a lot because of that.
The Church always speaks against the marriage and says that the sense of marriage is reproduction.
This doesn't make a lot of sense because also other people who aren't able to reproduce are allowed to marry.
50 year old women, for example, can also get married and no one considers it a scandal.
And it's also because of this tradition that homosexuals generally have very low self-confidence
and that's why they don't talk about their rights in public.
and unfortunately only the people who are really concerned are the ones who speak about it.
This was the same in the case of black people in the USA. They were always black people who fought against racism.
In the case of homosexuals it's the same, but I don't completely agree with the way they speak out.
Only one time a year are there parades, in cities around the world, that for me are actually pointless
they only make many people confirm the prejudices they have.
I think many of them mean it ironically. They show exactly the characteristics society ascribes to us.
and you laugh about yourself. But most people don't understand it and think homosexuals
are only those crazy people who walk half-naked on the street.
Many people don't know that we are exactly like others and that we don't always dress in such a strange and conspicuous way.
and that the life we lead is not so different from that most people lead. I wake up in the morning, have breakfast,
I brush my teeth, I have a shower, I go then to the University or to work, after that I go back home
and I don't lead an especially different life from most other people.
But people don't understand it because most of them hide themselves because they don't dare to be open about it
And because of the influence of Saudi Arabia they criminalized it...
Hello! This is an interview. You can take part if you want.
- Did you hear what he said? - What? - "Is this a karaoke show?"