With Hangouts On Air, it's easy to broadcast
your Hangouts live to the world and record
them as YouTube videos.
To begin, click “Start a Hangout”.
Invite people to join your Hangout.
Name your Hangout and click “Enable Hangouts
On Air”.
Review and agree to the legal terms to continue.
You only need to do this once.
The first time you start a Hangout On Air,
we'll ask you to link your YouTube account
so we can record your Hangouts to your YouTube
channel.
Click “Hangout.” Your Hangout will begin,
but don’t worry, you won’t be broadcasting
or recording just yet.
Once you’re in the Hangout, adjust your
lighting and camera angle so you look your best.
To stream your Hangout live on another website,
simply copy and paste the link to embed your Hangout.
When you’re ready, click “Start broadcast”.
At this point, your Hangout is broadcasting
live on your Google+ profile, your YouTube
account and any website where you’ve embedded it.
While you’re broadcasting, your viewers
will see everything you see in the Hangout
except for your chat conversations
and the number of people who are watching
your broadcast.
You can mute people in your Hangout if their
background is noisy.
Or click on a person’s video to make the
main screen stay on that person.
When you're done, a recording of your Hangout
will post publicly, so anyone who missed your
live Hangout can still join in the fun.
So go ahead. Start your first Hangout On Air
today and broadcast your conversation to the world.