Identify complementary and supplementary angles in the image below
So, just as a reminder:
Complementary angles are two angles that add up to 90 degrees,
and supplementary angles add up to 180 degrees.
So let's look at this diagram
First let's look for the complementary angles
so angles that add up to 90 degrees.
And so they drew this right angle over here
so we know that angle FAH is a right angle
because of this half box right over there.
And it's made up of two adjacent angles.
And these two adjacent angles make up a 90 degree angle
so they must add up to 90 degrees.
So the two angles, angle FAC, and angle CAH
are complementary because the measures of these two angles
must add up to 180 degrees, oh sorry...
must add up to this 90 degrees, right over here.
And I think that's all the complementary angles, just these two.
They add up to this right angle - to this 90 degrees.
Now let's think about the supplementary angles.
so supplementary angles
They add up to 180 degrees.
So you have angle FAC, or we could call it CAF- its the same angle
So angle CAF
and then this angle out here
FAB, they're adjacent to each other
and they clearly form a straight angle, which is 180 degrees
when you add their two measures.
So these two are clearly supplementary.
and angle FAB.
CAF and FAB together definitely add up to 180 degrees so they're supplementary.
And the other one:
we could do angle CAH, which is this right over here
that plus HAB clearly add up
they're adjacent, they form a straight angle
so they're clearly adding up to 180 degrees.
So they're also supplementary.
CAH and angle HAB.
And we're done!
These two angles add up to 90
these two add up to 180, these two also add up to 180.