Hi! I'm Michelle, founder of Macchiatto --
a boutique, branding and packaging firm in San Francisco.
I use Evernote Smart Notebook all the time for sketches and inspiration.
Thinking visually can be very cumbersome,
so having Evernote helps me keep everything organized in one place.
I literally take it everywhere because you'll never know
when a design idea will come.
The project I'm working on right now is seasonal greeting cards
that will be sent up to our clients.
I always start by sketching out rough ideas,
then I take the most successful sketches and refine them.
When I want to save my designs to Evernote I tag it with a Smart Sticker.
Then snap a picture with Evernote's Page Camera.
My favorite part is that I can take the sticker with me wherever I want.
This sticker here sends my drawing to a shared notebook.
When I need to find it later
I use Evernote Search to bring it up anytime.
As a visual thinker, sketching on paper is a critical part of the process.
My ideas are everywhere.
Being able to save to Evernote quickly and easily
helps me stay organized and ultimately makes my work better.