There's something going on with you, isn't there?
You're not sleeping?
Don't even think about lying to me.
There's nothing going on.
I want to live here with dad, you and san.
what...?
Why?
And what about Young Master JunPyo,school and everything?
Didn't I say it before? I have nothing to do with Goo JunPyo
Also, after putting up with so much humiliation, you still regret it?
Oh, gee!
So in this small rural town, selling fish, crabs and webfoot octopus, smelling like fish, that's how you want to live?
What's wrong with that?
Oh my gosh...
We're done for ! We're finished ! What hope do we have to live for now ?
Mom..
Forget it!
Yi Jung sunbae....
There's still no news from JanDi?
No. I don't know what she's thinking.
She hasn't called. She just said she went to a fishing village but never said where it is.
She must be doing ok. It's Geum Jandi we're talking about.
You seem to know my friends better than I do.
Like I said before,
I have some knowledge when it comes to girls
How is JunPyo sunbae doing?
He's a mess.
GaEul...
Don't you think it's time we start talking about us?
GaEul
I...I'll go first.
You don't have to feel burdened because of me.I already know how you feel.
So, from now on, I won't look for you anymore.
GaEul!
EunJae teacher said before, that because she did everything that was within her power, that she has no regrets.
Thank you.
For giving me the chance to do everything I could
If I hear from Jandi, I will inform you.
Bye.
What can we do?
Mister, I am so afraid that our Jun-Pyo might really become broken. I'm really afraid.
Miss.. you can't be like this also..
No.
This time...
I have a really bad feeling about this.
Miss?
Dad.... Dad...
DAD!!!!
How could you do this?
Can't you see it's already hard without you screaming about it?
Mom.... no, I don't even want to call you mom anymore.
how..how could a person..how could a person do something like that?!?
What exactly are you talking about??
How could you say that dad was dead when he's still alive?!
- You... - How did I know?
You're wondering about that at a time like this?
I'm asking you.
Leaving Dad buried like that, did you intend to deceive me forever?!
Why did you do that?! WHY?!
This is what your father would have wanted
W... W... What?
I said I will take care of everything, but your dad suddenly collapsed. He isn't different from a living corpse.
The head of the famous ShinHwa Group, I couldn't allow the last memories of him to become like that.
My pride wouldn't allow it.
Pride...Now...
Are you saying that you lied to the world and even to your childrenthat my living father was dead because of your pride?
It was for your dad.
What is this about?
JunPyo....
I'll explain everything. I...
I'm asking what does it mean?
When dad is not around what you have to do?
I have to take care of mother, sister, and Shinhwa group!
Goo Junpyo, can you promise me that as a man to man?
Yes, sir!
Your father tried his hardest till the very end for this group, which you can throw away any minute.
Are you thinking of abandoning him as well?
I'm sorry, young master.
i am really sorry.
This time, it was me who realized that you and I were from two different worlds.
As much as you try to deny it, you are still Shinhwa Group's Goo JunPyo.
I haven't once forgotten that
I have come to the fish market today.Everyone look at the fresh fish here.
The stall is full of fish.
- Look at this octopus.- $10!
- It seems this is the season for octopus.- $10!
Sure! It's drop-dead delicious! I'll give it to you for cheap, so buy some.
You hear that? Why don't you set today's dinner table with this webfoot octopus in season?
This is the Saeuh island.I'm reporter Joh Boram.
I'm going to see dad. Will you go with me?
I'm not going.
Junpyo...
Junpyo
Come talk with Mom.
Mom ?
Do you really think that you were even once my mom?
Why don't you quit with the act of being a mother when it doesn't suit you, Chairwoman Kang.
i have no interest.
What? If you're going to go, go by yourself.
Goo Junpyo
JunPyo, are you serious? Don't be like this. Go and see her once.
I said I'm not interested!
I'll ask you one more time.
Are you sure?
If you miss her so much, you should go.
Then I'm going first. Whether you go or not, you do whatever you want.
When times are like this, don't you need Geum Jan Di the most?
What can I do by bringing her back here?
There is nothing that I can promise her....promising her that I'd always make her laugh,
...that I'd always make her happy so just trust in me I've lost the confidence to keep those kinds of promises.
Jun Pyo.
The fact that I am the son of that kind of person...
...the fact that I am a member of that kind of family...
...even I hate it so much...how do you think she feels?
With all that she's had to endure already, I'm sure she really hates it.
It's Geum JanDi, so the situation can be different.
That's even more reason not to.
Because it's the woman that I love.
That's why it's not going to happen even more now.
It would have been nice if we sold the rest of that
Mom, I'm hungry! Oh, I'm sorry, San. I will have it ready soon.
What's going on?
What's going on? That's what we want to ask you.
There's a limit to your thinking what dumb country folk we are! What kind of scam are you trying to pull?
A scam?
You said you were the future daughter-in-law of ShinHwa Group!
My daughter says that there is someone else who is the future daughter-in-law.
See this? This lady is the heiress to a group much bigger than ShinHwa!
The fact that they were going to get married was even on the news!
That's old news.
What? So you mean you're really the future daughter-in-law of ShinHwa?
Well, that's not quite it either.
We don't care! Just give us back the money that you borrowed right now!!
What? Right now?
Yes! You never know...you just might run away in the middle of the night tonight!
That's right!
Look at what you've already just sat around and received! There's no difference between that and scamming us!
Pay us even the interest right now!!!
Why all of a sudden.....
I'll pay it.
Sunbae..
Oh... that... that... master is...
That money.......I'll repay it.
What should we do?
Did you see that, see that?
I guess it was true that she had a rich future son-in-law!
So is he the heir of ShinHwa Group?
Oh, just look at his face!He had a sense of nobility flowing out of him!
Oh, my...I've never seen such a handsome Young Master..
I envy them.
I'm not going to die alone.I'm not going to die alone!
How did you know that I was here?
I heard it....
...the emergency bell...
I tossed and turned every night afraid that I wouldn't be able to hear it...
How can this happen?
How can a person do such a thing?
I...have received so much from you, Sunbae...
But you have given me more...
How is Grandpa doing?
The usual...attending to work...probably will continue until he collapses again...
That is so like him....
Grandpa gave me this.
It was what my Grandma gave my mother.
Sunbae.
I don't know when I started to feel like this.
but...
I cannot live without you.
I cannot accept this.
Jandi...
I told myself I can forget it....
I thought I had forgotten it all.
However
However...
I can't seem to be able to throw this away.
I just can't seem to let it go....
I can't separate Goo JunPyo from me.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry sunbae.
It's ok.
Jandi...I can't give her up.
Even though I always make things hard for her.
I've sometimes thought it might be better to let her go to you.
no
If I had to give Jandi to another guy
I don't even want to think about it, but if I have to,
I thought you should the one.
It can't be anyone else but you, Jihoo
I've thought about that.
I won't die alone.
I will see to ShinHwa's end!
I won't go down alone.
NO!
Jun Pyo.
JunPyo!
Yah, Goo JunPyo.
Wake up.
Goo JunPyo!
They brought on their own misfortunes.
This isn't your fault.
Goo JunPyo!
Wake up!
Hello?
My friend is dying.
I said my friend is dying!
JunPyo...
Jun Pyo!
Wake up.
Yah!!
Wake Up!!
Breaking news. Tonight at 8 p.m., in a coastal town, the heir to ShinHwa Group, Goo JunPyo, was...
...was the victim of an assault and...
...has sent shock throughout. The assailant who was caught at the scene said he was done wrong by ShinHwa Group
and did it as an act of revenge on hostile takeover.
Are you satisfied? Is this what you wanted?
is this really what you wanted?
Miss, please calm down.
You said in the end, it was all for JunPyo. That you were handing all ShinHwa Group's assets to JunPyo.
Look...look at what your so-called future happiness has done to your son.
Mother, do you have a single idea as to what your son likes to eat, what he likes, what he wants to become?
The surgery went well.
The critical part is over.
That's good.
Let's Go.
What did you say?
There's an urgent meeting in Hong Kong.
Was it not enough with just Dad?
Answer me what is more important to you..ShinHwa or JunPyo.
Answer me!
JunPyo
...he loves rolled up egg and ramen..
He especially loves eating fish cakes from street vendors.
He can eat 20 at one sitting.
He likes packing lunch and going on a picnic...
With the telescope that his parents bought him....
...he also loves to star gaze.
Don't worry...
Goo JunPyo
He's gonna be okay.
JunPyo... JunPyo..
Are you okay?... JunPyo..
JunPyo
JunPyo, it's your sister...
JunPyo got transferred to a room.
Why don't you go?
If he knows you're next to him, he'll wake up soon.
Stop here for a minute.
Mom, do you have any idea what your son likes to eat,
what he likes to do,what he wants to do?
JunPyo....
...he loves rolled up egg and ramen...
He especially likes eating fish cakes from street vendors...
He can eat 20 at one sitting.
Move on.
I don't know when I started to feel this way.But...
I cannot live without you.
JunPyo.. JunPyo
I told you so, didn't I?
If not you, no one else...
Grandfather
Jihoo...
Ok..ok
Say it. Aside from Shinhwa and being a plutocrat...
Have you ever seen me... as just a normal guy?
No
No matter how much you struggle, you're still Shinhwa Group's Goo Jun Pyo.
I never forgot that, not even for a single moment.
Goo JunPyo
Can you hear me?
I lied to you again.
To me, you
no matter what, are Goo JunPyo.
Goo JunPyo...the idiot who likes this Geum Jandi
who's not cute, has no money...no status...
So wake up. Wake up.
wake up Goo junPyo
Goo JunPyo
Hubby..
Oh, Honey! Everything's okay, right?
You're healthy, right?
Us...we're home!
It's all thanks to you...you and all your hard work on that boat!
The landlord..because they felt bad about what happened before....
...rented it back to us for cheap!
Dad! Once I become a pro gamer...
...you don't have to be on the boat so hurry and come home!
Daddy, daddy, daddy...we're okay so don't worry about us and just take care of your health, okay?
I understand honey.
Come home soon!
SunBae
JunPyo woke up.
Oh JanDi..you came
You just woke up and you look perfectly fine!
It definitely isn't like any human's recovery!
Yo..my bro..welcome back.
Thank you
For what?
For being alive.
Did you really think that this Goo JunPyo would leave this life like that?
It is definitely JunPyo.
Look at him, he's saying it was an unnatural death.
JanDi...why are you just standing there?
Come here. You were really worried, weren't you?
All the tests came back normal.
Thank Goodness... Goo JunPyo.
But who is that dorky-looking girl?
JunPyo.
You don't remember Geum Jan Di?
Don't joke around.
Geum JanDi
What's that?
Goo Junpyo
JunPyo, then do you remember your friends?
Are you joking?
Tell me my name.
So Yi Jung
Then me... do you remember me?
psh... Song WooBin.
Do you really not know who Geum Jandi is?
Is she someone I should know?
Ji Hoo, is she your girl?
It's a partial memory loss.
For the patient, anything really stressful before the accident, he's forgotten.
But how is it possible that he can't remember just one person?
It's possible that memories regarding her are too painful or just too important..
so if he concentrates on it too much,
it could be erased selectively.
Then...when might his memories come back?
Who knows..?
Usually it's about six months...but...
...there are cases where it doesn't come back ever.
Goo JunPyo..Hello
The weather's totally awesome, isn't it?
You want to go for a walk?
You
Who do you think you are that you can come in anytime when you please?
Hm?
Are you interested in me or something?
Aren't you supposed to be Ji Hoo's woman?!
Yah! I'm not anyone's girl!
Well...more than JiHoo sunbae's, I'm more...your...
Get lost.
Are you hard of hearing or something?
I said get out! Girls like you bring me bad luck!
Goo JunPyo
Can you go out? I want to rest.
Why aren't you coming out!
Come out! I said come out!!
I said come out!!
Unnie...here you go!
So don't cry anymore, okay?
You got to hit the vending machine only then it works.
Thank you
It seems like you've been admitted at this hospital for a while...
What's your name? Yumi...Jang Yumi. A junior at Korea High.
I'm Geum JanDi
ShinHwa High, Senior.
You go to ShinHwa High?
Oh, that's just so great!
But who are you here to visit?
A friend..,OH, I see..
I broke my leg while skiing...
Wanna sit here?
Yumi...you have such a vibrant personality..
It's just that I get annoyed with people who are at hospitals who are sad or high strung...
I don't like that.
So how should one be towards people like that?
For people how have been admitted for a long time and they're a little high strung and sensitive...
Just naturally....
Naturally?
You over there! Are you ok?
Oppa...your condition looks pretty bad..you really shouldn't walk around like that.
Oppa?
You want to ride a wheelchair?
Don't concern yourself.
Then do you do want to borrow my crutches?
Oppa, do you know how to use crutches?
Hey, you little brat...don't act like we know each other and just go away.
Oppa, your personality is pretty bad, isn't it?
I'm not a little brat. I'm Yumi, Jang Yumi.
What?
You're the oppa that's in that VIP room, aren't you? I don't know what great person you are... but a patient is just another patient.
Oh, wait..not quite. At this hospital, Yumi is a sunbae!
If you don't want to break the remaining leg...
..I'd suggest you lean on me.
No, Yumi! Your leg is injured. Let me help. Why don't you lean on me.
You still haven't left?
Unni, see you next time!
So how about shocking him with something...or...
...recreating some important event in the past?
Such as?
Of all the incidents with Geum JanDi, what was the event that had the most impact?
Goo JunPyo
What's with this girl?
What the hell are you trying to do?!
If you come back to your senses, call me.
What?
Are you some kind of crazy girl?
What kind of woman are you?
JunPyo
Don't you remember anything?
What the hell am I supposed to remember!?
What kind of bad luck is this with this bum-like chick...
Has it been too long ago?
No. I think this incident was too weak.
Next time, let's try something stronger.
Stronger?
Didn't I tell you I was at the limits of my patience?
Yah! Who the hell do you think you're messing with?
Just because you're Ji Hoo's girlfriend, doesn't mean I'm going to hold back!
Goo JunPyo.
I'm warning you. I'm not going to go soft on you!
I've warned you!
Hey JiHoo
I don't ever want to see this crazy girl again!
Do you hear me?
Don't worry.
You're not someone that can be forgotten that easily.
Maybe because it was so hard on him that he wanted to forget.
If it was a bond that could be forgotten just because you want to forget...
...would it have been easier?
No way!
Who in the world gets special crutches??
I'm telling you the truth.
Do you really think Goo JunPyo will use any old crutches?
Here...you hold it.
oh, seriously...why is this thing so light? Doesn't feel like I'm holding anything.
This is what's called titanium.
That's really funny, Oppa.
JunPyo
Oh JiHoo
Oh, you were there?
JanDI unnie
Hello..
Unni, did you see JunPyo oppa's crutches?
It's titanium...pretty funny, huh? It's not like he's Iron Man or anything...
Jandi unni's friend is so handsome.
Hello. I'm Jang Yumi. Nice to meet you.
It's cold. Let's go back inside.
Who is it?
I have brought Pizza.
It'll be so great if I can see it through a telescope or something....
Oppa, do you like stars?
Stars?
The brightest star in winter...
...in other words, like Goo JunPyo.
Then, I am this star.
Oppa. What's wrong? Are you hurting somewhere?
There's something important that I seem to have forgotten.
I can't remember it.
My chest feels so tight that I feel like I'm going to burst...
Don't stress too much over it.
If it's important, then it will come back eventually...
And if it doesn't come back, doesn't it mean that it wasn't really that important to being with?
If you keep stressing about it, it won't be good for you physically.
Yo..What's up?
Are you okay?
Hello..
We meet again.
We are H.C.
H.C.??
Hospital couple.
All the patients and the nurses basically gave us that official title.
What do you think? Do we suit each other?
Jun Pyo
Do you still not remember anything ?
What exactly am I supposed to remember?
Geum JanDi
You don't remember?
So why do you keep talking about Jandi or something?!
I mean why should I remember your girl?
Oh, forget it!
I don't know where you met this girl...so unsophisticated..
What does she think she is...a gang member or something?
Just make sure she doesn't come in and out of my hospital room.
Goo JunPyo
Please Stop.
What is wrong with him?
SunBae
I'll bring tea.
I'm sorry
Why should you be sorry?
I'm the one who is sorry.
I got so mad without even my knowing...
I didn't stop you because I thought JunPyo would be hurt...
If you hit him, I thought you would be hurt more, emotionally.
That's why I stopped you .
How long did you wait outside?
Why are your hands so cold?
Let me see
the one that's cold
is your heart.
You don't have to pretend to be strong in front of me.
I'm not pretending to be strong.
It's because you're here.
You being here gives me strength.
I'll go make tea.
Abracadabra,Gu JunPyo, remember Geum JanDi.
I remember.
The thing I forgot is...
you, right? It's all over now.
That in this ridiculous way...
...you guys are ending....
I can't go along with it.
That girl's facial expression...I can't seem to erase...
In the end...
Geum JanDi and Goo JunPyo...
...only amounted to this...
This is all it amounted to..
We have gathered you all here to announce something special.
Goo JunPyo and Jang Yumi, we have decided to go study in the US next month.