Sociolab Concursos
is a platform for entrepreneurship
and social inovation
that brings together the public sector, private sector, students and
the most vulnerable families in society.
The objective is to develop
products, services and business models
which provide effective solutions to the problems faced by
people who are socially excluded
due to either lack of resources or lack of opportunities.
How can you join in?
This process starts with a challenge:
That's to say, a question without an answer.
In the first stage  "ideation", the users share their ideas with the community.
It is not necessary that the idea is fully developed, or that you are an expert in the field
a sentence is enough
you can add images or video if this will help to communicate your idea
the more evolved your idea is
the more evolved the feedback will be
The community is you
and all the other members of Sociolab Concurso.
the community votes, comments on, and helps to develop the ideas that it likes most.
at the same time, a group of mentors
comprised of professionals and members of the public
support and select, together with the community, the best ideas.
Their votes carry a 30% weighting of the total.
The best ideas then go on to the "co-creation" stage,
where, together with the user, they validate or invalidate the remodeled design.
Once these ideas have been improved and redesigned,
a sustainable business model is designed
then the ideas are tested, presented and evaluated
thereby detecting the entrepreneurs of the future,
which we fund in the final stage of implementation and scaling up.
This is how Sociolab works.
The biggest platform for social innovation in Latin America, aiming to change the world with dignity.