Google Search is incredibly powerful.
You can search for text across the Internet
most of human knowledge, images, books, videos.
But, we realized there was an important part
of the Search experience that we’d overlooked.
Our task as designers
is to get our users the information
they’re looking for
as quickly and as beautifully as possible.
But, until now, we couldn’t always
give users what they’re looking for
Because, sometimes, they’re not looking at all.
My wife and I have a puppy
with so much energy
that we walk her 5 times a day,
and she sniffs around every nook and cranny.
This is how she gets information about her world.
Photo-auditory-olfactory sensory convergence
is a phenomenon that's been promised
in science fiction for decades.
-We’re excited to announce Google NoseBeta
our flagship olfactory knowledge feature
enabling users to search for smells.
Our mobile aroma indexing program
has been able to amass
a 15 million scentibite database
of smells from around the world.
-With an elegant integration
into our existing knowledge panels,
the Google Nose Beta Smell button
seamlessly connects scent to search.
By intersecting photons with infrasound waves,
Google Nose Beta temporarily aligns molecules
to emulate a particular scent.
Google Nose Beta works on nearly all desktops,
laptops,
and quite a few mobile devices.
In the fast paced world that we live in,
we don’t always have time
to stop and smell the roses.
Now, with Google Nose Beta,
the roses are just a click away.
-If you have a question like
"what does a new car smell like?",
who knows the answer?
Google Nose.
-What does a ghost smell like?
What does the inside
of an Egyptian tomb smell like?
Google Nose.
Google Nose...Beta.