Mawlaya salli wa sallim da'iman abadan (My Lord send you  peace and blessings always and forever)
'Ala habibika khayril khalqi kullihimi (Upon Your beloved, the best of the entire creation)
Mawlaya salli wa sallim da'iman abadan (My Lord send you peace and blessings always and forever)
Ya Rabbee salli 'aleeh  (My Lord send your peace upon him)
Salawatu Allahi 'aleeh (May Allah's salutations be upon him)
The moon - like his countenance - a beautiful face
And the sun - like his smile - a comforting shade
He is the servant of Allah, the master of creation and His Chosen One
And he's Allah’s beloved, the best Messenger that came with Allah's revelation
Mawlaya salli wa sallim da'iman abadan (My Lord send you peace and blessings always and forever)
'Ala habibika khayril khalqi kullihimi (Upon Your beloved, the best of the entire creation)
Ya Rabbee salli 'aleeh  (My Lord send your peace upon him)
Salawatu Allahi 'aleeh (May Allah's salutations be upon him)
He is the best of Allah's servants, the best of all creatures
He is alive inside us with his guidance, his teachings are delightful
We ask you, O Allah, to gather us one day together with the Messenger of Allah
And to allow us to drink from his Fountain, O Allah please accept!
Mawlaya salli wa sallim da'iman abadan (My Lord send you peace and blessings always and forever)
'Ala habibika khayril khalqi kullihimi (Upon Your beloved, the best of the entire creation)
Ya Rabbee salli 'aleeh  (My Lord send your peace upon him)
Salawatu Allahi 'aleeh (May Allah's salutations be upon him)
With a clean heart, a pure being, constantly engaged in the remembrance of Allah
The Chosen One, the Elect One, Allah's peace be upon him
His manners and qualities - Glory to He who created him!
He is my role model, my beloved, and my prayer for salvation
O Beloved of Allah! O Messenger of Allah!
Decree for us to meet him, we pray to You O my Lord!
Mawlaya salli wa sallim da'iman abadan (My Lord send you peace and blessings always and forever)
'Ala habibika khayril khalqi kullihimi (Upon Your beloved, the best of the entire creation)
Ya Rabbee salli 'aleeh  (My Lord send your peace upon him)
Salawatu Allahi 'aleeh (May Allah's salutations be upon him)
Mawlaya salli wa sallim da'iman abadan (My Lord send you peace and blessings always and forever)
'Ala habibika khayril khalqi kullihimi (Upon Your beloved, the best of the entire creation)
Ya Rabbee salli 'aleeh  (My Lord send your peace upon him)
Salawatu Allahi 'aleeh (May Allah's salutations be upon him)