We're all born of the same matter
However, we're not all born equal
Who will you be? What will you become?
Some people are born to be leaders, effecting great change amongst their people
Others are born into mediocrity, living unremarkable lives
But for some
Life will be a constant battle offering zero opportunities
So how can nothing... be something?
School was the only place where Zero received attention
He learnt important life lessons like his value in society
And that it was forbidden for his denomination to multiply
Sometimes Zero was made to feel like a much larger number
But the children only wanted to remind him that a zero is a zero no matter which way you face
As Zero grew into an adult, he walked a lonely path
Despite his numerical shortcomings, Zero felt he had something to offer
Zero never allowed bad situations to get him down...
He didn’t want to be a negative number
It was the first time Zero awoke with a battered and bruised body...
But this time was different
For the first time Zero felt unaware of his lowly number
In the company of his new friend, he felt as important as a three...
Or even a four
But the most wonderful sensation
Was the feeling of belonging
A lifetime of loneliness faded into the past
Along with the notion that their love was forbidden
As the world continued without him
Zero wondered how he could ever continue without his love?
The newborn bore the mark of infinity
The largest and most respected number the people had ever seen
Zero knew that for a nothing...
He had created something truly magnificent