I remember Heaven and Hell had a lot of unwritten rules in those days
and match making for the living was still a bit of a wild west.
But I guess that’s where Death comes into the story...
and the guy before me had pushed her too far.
It’s not smart to toy with Death, but there was something hypnotic about her...
and I wasn’t the only one who thought so.
Speak of the Devil, that was me.
It was my first day on the job, and I was ready for...
just about anything...
except maybe this guy.
They say love is blind. But Cupid was over a thousand years and it didn't stop him from flirting with Death.
Now, I could tell he was playing with fate that day.
But little did I know what fate had in store for me.
Up there Death was Judge, Jury and Executioner to all lovers, living or otherwise.
But despite his behavior, Death had a soft spot for him and loved watching him work.
While Cupid was matching up lovers all over the world, I was tasked with breaking them up.
Not exactly what I had in mind.
My demon instincts faced constant temptation
but I wanted so much more than that.
She hid it well, but Death was facing her own demons that day.
I needed to figure out how to impress her.
Huh, turned out to be easier than I thought...
but it’s not every day I put the moves on an Overlord of the Afterlife!
It was my first time and nerves were all over the place.
My instincts were on fire, but not in a good way.
That wasn’t my best move.
While Death's guard was down, Cupid saw an opportunity to take fate into his own hands.
My story didn’t turn out quite the way I’d imagined.
Hey, somebody had to do Cupid’s work, and the job had its perks.