Kang Hwi.
&lt;i&gt; Last Episode &lt;br&gt; - Part 2 - &lt;/i&gt;
The house feels empty.
Kang Hwi-nim?
Not Kang Hwi-nim, but Tae Ik-nim.
Lee Tae Ik, what brings you here?
What do you mean what brings me here?
This is actually my house.
That’s true.
Weren’t you moving in all together tomorrow?
It is tomorrow.
I came today to get you.
Pack your bags quickly.
What?
You need to go ask Grandpa for forgiveness, don’t you?
Aren’t you going back home?
I should...
I must, but…
Hurry, pack your bags and come down.
I will go with you.
- Ah! &lt;br&gt; - Hurry, let’s go in.
First go in and say that you are absolutely sorry.
Then Grandpa will also forgive you.
Lee Tae Ik, you are saying this because you don’t know.
If Grandpa gets angry, he is really scary.
Why did you rebel against him when you knew that? &lt;br /&gt;Fearlessly!
Ah! That is because…
It's because I couldn’t help it then.
Then are you going to keep being in &lt;br&gt;this kind of relationship with Grandpa?
No.
Then... &lt;br /&gt;Hurry, let’s go in.
Ah! Wait a moment.
I tell you I am not yet ready.
What to do then?
Who is being so noisy in front &lt;br /&gt;of someone else’s house?!
Gr… Grandpa!
Grandpa?
Am I your grandpa?
I don’t have a granddaughter like you!
Where do you think this place is &lt;br&gt; that you dare step foot in here?
Grandpa… that is…
Grandpa…
Just once... &lt;br /&gt;Please forgive me just once.
Grandpa!
It wasn’t enough to deceive your grandpa.
You dare go against what I said?
Grandpa.
I wasn’t trying to go against your words.
I had to stay there with him then.
Grandpa, you said that.
A true friend is one who stays by a &lt;br /&gt;friend's side when he is in difficulty.
I... As I learned from you,
I just guarded my loyalty to a friend.
So, Grandpa… &lt;br&gt;Can’t you forgive me just once, please?
You bad thing!
You try to win against your grandpa to the end!
I have no energy.
Let’s have chueotang. &lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;(ground loach in hot bean paste soup)&lt;/i&gt;
Grandpa!
Stylist Jang! Stylist Jang!
Jang Man, good job!
Indeed, my bed is the best!
Wh… what are you doing?
On someone else’s bed?
What?
You said it was nice, so I just lied down.
The cushiony feeling… mine is better.
Really...
I am grateful, Elder.
Still...
Since you are leaving here after &lt;br /&gt;achieving what you wanted,
so, it is highly rewarding to me.
Anyway, when you get back, please take care.
Visit once in awhile
and let's say hello.
- Here. &lt;br&gt; - Yes.
I will visit frequently.
&lt;i&gt; Hey! &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; You are asking me to sleep in a tent? &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Why? I can’t do that?&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Now, I am the owner of the house. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; It is up to the owner to decide &lt;br&gt;where to make you sleep. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; You are a fool. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Why am I a fool? &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; But why have you been continuously saying that since from before? &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I also like you, Lee Tae Ik. &lt;/i&gt;
Lee Tae Ik!
Yes.
Gr... Grandpa!
Do well.
Even when you return, think about your stamina
and keep training diligently.
I will keep an eye on you continuously.
I will bear that in mind.
Then, we will be off, Elder.
Let's go.
Take care on your way back!
Yes.
&lt;i&gt; What is this? &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; It’s the documents to Full House. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I took care of it. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Don’t ever stay apart.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; And stick right next to her. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; “I like you.” &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; “You are pretty.”&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; And say things that give you goose bumps often. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; So that she will never cry over anything at all. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; So that she can always smile. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Guard her by her side. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; No matter how much I try, &lt;br&gt; it is something that I can’t do. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; If it is you, you can make Man Ok happy. &lt;/i&gt;
Lee Tae Ik?
Why? I am on my way to work out.
- Let’s go. &lt;br&gt;- Where?
To have fun!
Why suddenly?
Where are we going?
Some place good!
Wait, then, let me at least change.
What is this? &lt;br /&gt;You said let’s go to some place good.
It’s just here?
You said that you are going to change.
Clothes?
Go to the room, change and come out.
I took all my clothes home, so there aren’t any here.
Then, what is that thrown on top of the bed?
Isn’t that yours, Jang Man?
There is nothing I left behind.
If you go and check, you will know if there is any or not.
Quickly go change, and come back.
What did I leave behind?
Jang Man.
My soup doesn't have cream.
Even the organic juice has disappeared, &lt;br&gt; has disappeared.
Jang Man.
Like this, without you,
I can't do anything at all.
I have become like this.
Why &lt;i&gt;(are you staring)&lt;/i&gt;?
You're really pretty.
When you first came here in some strange chador, &lt;br&gt; I didn’t imagine that this would happen.
Wow! I am crazy.
It’s the same for me, too.
Rude Bastard! &lt;br&gt;The King of Fussiness!
Oh! I am crazy, why?
Be by my side.
Not to Apsala, &lt;br&gt;but I am saying this officially to Jang Man Ok,
The position of my stylist... &lt;br&gt;I would like you to be my stylist, Jang Man.
I don’t want to be apart from you! &lt;br&gt;When I am working and also when I am at home.
Excuse me, Lee Tae Ik…&lt;br&gt;The stylist… I can’t do that.
I registered for classes.
What?
So that I can learn designing, Kang Hwi-nim &lt;br /&gt;left after enrolling me in classes.
So I plan to formally start designing.
This crazy!
Won Kang Hwi told me to give it a shot (with you). &lt;br&gt;What?
Register for classes?
Huh? &lt;br&gt;Give a shot at what?
Forget it.
You needn’t know!
But, Jang Man! &lt;br&gt;Is that institute more important than me now?
That institute?
My future is at stake! &lt;br&gt;How can you say something like that?
Anyway! &lt;br&gt;You continuously did well as Won Kang Hwi’s stylist.
So why won’t you be my stylist?
Why? Why not? &lt;br&gt; Why not?
Oh! How could you!
Won Kang Hwi even registered for me&lt;br /&gt;to study and he worries about me.
Lee Tae Ik, because I won’t be your stylist, &lt;br&gt;you whine like a kid. What are you doing?
What? &lt;br&gt; Kid?
And you!
Why do you call Won Kang Hwi, "Kang Hwi-nim"? &lt;br&gt;But why am I, "Lee Tae Ik"?
Call me also the same!
Huh? Call you what?
Like Wong Kang Hwi!
"Tae Ik-nim."
&lt;i&gt;"Tae Ik-nim"?
Yes, Tae Ik-nim!
You know that thing.
When you call Won Kang Hwi…&lt;br&gt; You put your hand together like this.
With your eyes, like this, &lt;br /&gt; say,
"Tae Ik-nim."
What is this? &lt;br&gt;Why are you laughing?
He said, "Tae Ik-nim!" &lt;br&gt;Tae Ik-nim!
What? &lt;br&gt; Is that funny?
It’s funny. &lt;br&gt;It isn’t even cake-nim but Tae Ik-nim!
It doesn’t suit you.
Hey! Jang Man! &lt;br&gt;Say it once for me! Really!
Ah!
Hey.
Come here!
I'm going to get you!
&lt;i&gt;Tae Ik-nim, Tae Ik- nim. &lt;br&gt; 6 Months Later. &lt;/i&gt;
Jang Man.
Hyung-nim. &lt;br&gt;Let go of this!
Hey.
I am a pure and innocent person without a single scandal.
It will be problematic if you keep doing this.
Are you going to keep talking like that &lt;br /&gt;and making me feel itchy?
Speak like you usually do.
How can a Hallyu star do that?
Haughtily and chic! &lt;br&gt;Don’t you know?
Forget it. &lt;br&gt; Why are you here in the morning?
What do you mean why? &lt;br&gt;Did you forget that we have a schedule for a show?
Hyung! Stop torturing the managers &lt;br&gt;and do well on your own, huh?
Hey! &lt;br&gt; Hey, Baek Go Dong.
Miss Jang Man Ok.
- Yes? &lt;br&gt;- Yes.
Take this, please.
Can you sign here?
- Thank you! &lt;br&gt; - No problem.
&lt;i&gt; Man Ok, have you been well? &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I've been doing well. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Ah! And our Chaton has ascended &lt;br /&gt;to be the most popular cat in this neighborhood. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; The Chaton that is there is also doing well, right? &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; How is everybody doing? &lt;br&gt; I want to see everyone so much! &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Anyway, Man Ok, don’t be sick. &lt;br&gt; Eat well, too! &lt;/i&gt;
Kang Hwi-nim, everyone here is doing well.
&lt;i&gt; You heard about Take 2, haven’t you? &lt;br&gt; Go Dong has become really cool.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; There is one problem though. &lt;br&gt;Go Dong imitates you too much. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; It seems that Lee Tae Ik is having &lt;br&gt;a hard time because of that. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; And, Senior Manager Hwang… no, President Hwang&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; is really busy because of the work at the company. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; International Star, Jin Se Ryeong, Developed Feelings On scene, Dating Director Jang Lee Shin! &lt;/i&gt;
Who said that she isn’t an international star, &lt;br&gt;she publicizes her movie internationally.
Make a positive press release &lt;br&gt;and distribute it to the media.
Yes.
And Senior Manager Kim.
Yes, President.
There aren’t many days left for Take 2’s Showcase, &lt;br&gt; prepare it well without any problems.
I understand, President.
You know that Tae Ik will be absent &lt;br&gt;for some time, don’t you?
Yes. I arranged the ticket. &lt;br&gt;2 tickets.
Now, let’s make a run for it happily &lt;br&gt;and merrily today again!
- Yes! &lt;br&gt; - Yes.
- One. &lt;br&gt; - One.
- Two. &lt;br&gt; - Two.
&lt;i&gt; Grandpa, as a result of the increased number&lt;br /&gt; of students at Man Ok Kwan, is really happy these days. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; My friend, Han Ga Ryeong, my enemy for life. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; All this time, she used to pry into the private &lt;br&gt;lives of stars and write weird articles. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; But thanks to my close watch &lt;br&gt;is getting better little by little. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; SS Magazine or whatever that she established&lt;br&gt; with her two friends she hangs out with, &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I am helping them with exclusive articles on Take 2. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Thanks to that, she is diligently getting reformed. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Ah! And I…&lt;/i&gt;
I'm leaving, bye!
&lt;i&gt;Subtitles by the Maid of the House 2 team at Viki&lt;br&gt;You too can join us and subtitle your favorite dramas.
&lt;i&gt; During the day, I teach kids at the studio. &lt;br&gt; In the afternoon, I go to the institute. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I am really busy, but… &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I think I am born to hold 2 jobs. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Teaching kids and studying design are all fun. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; But, Kang Hwi-nim. &lt;br&gt;Everyone really wants to see you. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; When are you coming back to Korea? &lt;/i&gt;
Young master.
You have a guest.
What? &lt;br /&gt;A guest has come, but you aren’t even looking?
Lee Tae Ik.
It's been a while, Won Kang Hwi.
Hello.
Hello, I am the President of L.J. Entertainment, Lee Jun.
Ah, yes! &lt;br&gt;I heard that you are interested in entertainment.
You thought well.
Have you heard of Hallyu Fever?
Huh? I brought newly-made clothes!
You said your outfit was torn. &lt;br /&gt;But, are you still wearing it?
Hyung, your outfit tore?
Give it here.
It looks fine.
That’s right.
Just… here and here… &lt;br&gt;I don’t like the sewing!
It is fine, why?
Again, you are being fussy for no reason!
Forget it.
I am going to change. &lt;br&gt;Stay outside.
See if you don’t do well today!
&lt;i&gt;Thanks to The Maid of Full House 2 Team @ Viki for subtiltling this drama into nearly 20 languages.
&lt;i&gt; Thanks to the Team Managers Bkiss and Mint00017
♪ Don't say anything. &lt;br&gt; Just stay as you are now.
♪ Be in my embrace. Be my love. &lt;br&gt; Take my hand.
♪ When I see your lips and feel your small breath,
♪ The moment you approached, &lt;br&gt; You are my dream.
♪ I only want you.
♪ Each day, each day, each day, &lt;br&gt; Every minute is exciting.
♪ My smile is only for you. &lt;br&gt; Only look at me.
♪ Hello, Hello. &lt;br&gt; You are my goddess.
♪ I love you. &lt;br&gt; My Love.
♪ Hello. Hello. &lt;br&gt; I only love you.
♪ You are my heaven.
♪ I want to have you. Everyday.
♪ You are with me. Everything.
♪ I can't let you go for even a moment.
♪ You are my heaven.
Now for a very special stage.
A friend who is the most important friend to me.
I prepared a song for that friend.
♪ Whenever I see your eyes, &lt;br&gt; I can't sleep. Tonight.
♪ When I feel your breath, &lt;br&gt; I am thrilled.
♪ I have fallen for you deeply. &lt;br&gt; Look at me.
♪ I want to have you gently. &lt;br&gt; Everything is so sweet.
♪ I don't stop all night. &lt;br&gt; I want to fall asleep in your embrace.
♪ Whispering with moist lips into my ear. &lt;br&gt; I want to hold you.
♪ You can touch. &lt;br&gt; Be my girl.
♪ You can fly. Let me love. &lt;br&gt; Give all.
♪ You can touch. &lt;br&gt;Be my girl.
♪ You can fly. &lt;br&gt;Let me love, love you, tonight.
♪ You make me cool.
♪ You make me hot.
♪ I want you. Baby, tonight.
♪ You make me cool.
♪ You make me hot.
♪ I want you, you can touch.
♪ You can touch.
♪ Hey! Sweety Girl!&lt;br&gt; You know it!
♪ When you see my eyes, &lt;br&gt; I can't breathe.
♪ 'Cause you're so hot! &lt;br&gt; 'Cause you're so beautiful!
♪ You are my addict, girl.
♪ Whenever I see your eyes, &lt;br&gt; I can't sleep at night. Tonight
♪ When I feel your breath, &lt;br&gt;I am thrilled.
♪ I have fallen for you deeply. &lt;br&gt;Look at me.
♪ I want to have you gently. &lt;br&gt; Everything is so sweet, Girl.
♪ I don't stop all night. I want to fall asleep in your embrace.
♪ Whispering with moist lips into my ear, &lt;br&gt; I want to hold you.
♪ You can touch! &lt;br&gt; Be my girl..
♪ You can fly. Let me love. &lt;br&gt; Give all for you!
♪ You can touch. &lt;br&gt; Be my girl!
♪ You can fly. &lt;br&gt; Let me love. love you tonight!
♪ You, you, you make me cool.
♪ You, you, you make me hot.
♪ I want you, you, you, Baby, tonight!
♪ You, you, you make me cool.
♪ You, you, you make me hot.
♪ I want you, you, you. &lt;br&gt; You can touch.
♪ Ready to love. I seduce you. My feelings are on fire.
♪ I tell you that I love you so much.
♪ Wanna come to me! Wanna come to feel!
♪ 1, 2,3. Let's love.
♪ Let's burn this night.
♪ Please hold my hands reaching for you.
♪ You can touch. &lt;br&gt; You can touch.
♪ You can touch.
- You did well. &lt;br&gt; - Indeed, Kang Hwi Hyung!
Yeah!
Kang Hwi-nim!
Man Ok.
I was surprised! You didn’t even say &lt;br /&gt;that you were coming. What happened?
So that I could surprise you, &lt;br /&gt;I appeared like this, "Ta da!"
How was it? Were you surprised?
Hyung-nim!
I missed you!
Go Dong! Go Dong!
But, can you see me?
I can see fine!
You! &lt;br&gt;Who told you to copy Sir Me!’s fashion?
But I will let it slide since it suits you a bit!
Ah, Hyung-nim! &lt;br&gt;I tell you, you can see well!
"I tell you?"
He dresses sophisticatedly, but &lt;br /&gt;his way of speaking is still the same.
I tell you, no! &lt;br&gt; Ah!
No.
I don’t speak like this.
I only use standard language.
Man Ok, I missed you.
I missed you, too.
Hey, where do you think you are?
Hey, what is this? &lt;br /&gt;I'm meeting her after a long time,&lt;br /&gt; let me say hello!
Just say hello with words.
Don’t even shake hands, Jang Man. You don’t know when he will start getting indecent desires for you again.
Indecent desires? &lt;br /&gt;Hey! I am such a pure soul!
Man Ok, tell me. &lt;br&gt;Am I more pure or is that Rude Bastard more pure?
Man Ok, even now is not too late.
Just come back to me. &lt;br&gt;Am I not slightly better than Lee Tae Ik?
What? Are you nuts?
Look, look! &lt;br&gt;Now, he even gets violent!
Man Ok, scold him!
Come here!
- No, I won't. &lt;br&gt; - Oh!
You are finally meeting after a long time, &lt;br /&gt;why are you acting like this again?
Ah! I can’t live!
Hey! Hey!
Oppa, there is only oppa for Ga Ryeong.
Can’t I take a picture with you?
Come quickly!
1,2,3.
Elder, Full House has changed a lot since &lt;br&gt;the first time you came here, hasn’t it?
Yes.
Grandpa, have some wine.
- Thank you, Master Jang! &lt;br&gt; - Yes.
- Here! &lt;br&gt; - Thank you, Elder.
&lt;i&gt; Follow me.
&lt;i&gt; Follow me! &lt;/i&gt;
How is the food?
It's good! It's good!
Enjoy it and have a lot.
I don’t know, we may get scolded &lt;br&gt;because just the 2 of us snuck out?
I am going to take a walk with my girl.
Who is going to scold me?
Now, you say that I am your girl in the open.
Doesn’t this place make you think of anything?
I'm not sure.
Chaton.
Idiot!
Idiot?
&lt;i&gt; I'm a girl! &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Huh? &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I don't know! &lt;br&gt; You, idiot! &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Hey, where are you going?&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I said it is Chaton! &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; -- Idiot! &lt;br&gt; -- Dummy! &lt;/i&gt;
I remember.
That rude boy.
That's right.
That rude boy and the girl who was looking for Chaton.
They met again.
Isn’t it completely fascinating?
It’s really fascinating.
Put your hand into that hole.
Huh?
Aren’t you going to look for your cat?
Oh?
It's really pretty.
Ta Da!
Do it once.
Huh?
What?
"Tae Ik-nim."
Do it like this, "Tae Ik-nim." &lt;br&gt; Do it like that.
Do it once.
Tae Ik-nim.
Jang Man Ok!! &lt;br&gt;You use Man for ‘Plenty’ and Ok for ‘House,’ don’t you?
Yes.
If you change that exactly into English?
Full House.
That's right.
We were meant to be like this.
Jang Man Ok . . .
Let us . . .
live here together continuously. . .
Here in Full House.
&lt;i&gt; ♬ I'm flying to the sky.
&lt;i&gt; ♬ I just fall in love. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;♬ I smile and I smile again.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;♬ My love is coming. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ♬ He's coming closer to me like a dream. &lt;/i&gt;
♬ Let's love.
&lt;i&gt;Thank you for loving Full House 2 until now. &lt;br&gt; Nearly 700,000 viewers as of December 13, 2012&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Thanks to our segmenters: tkadi, cgwm808, subject, honnas, killerbunnies, Nononchii, &lt;/i.&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Segmenters, cont. orangegummybear, shms, coco094, alliesv, and Icehurt&lt;/i.
&lt;i&gt;Thanks to the Korean-English subtitlers; tkadi, cgwm808, subject, Minji0308, sweetdreamzzz. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Kor-Eng Subbers, cont.: Crazynezz, Isabella84, ppa93, and Kwieyopta, &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Thanks to our Editors: AuntieMame and cgwm808 &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Thanks to our Moderators: belyncita, laylays, trucalling, mihaelagh, amitiara, sweetola, Emme257, shaikaye, &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Moderators, cont.: malu_mad, JeNn_nOt, Pappu, aoikurochan, LenaWolf,Katiapouli, Tokki-tok, rakefet365
&lt;i&gt;If you enjoyed this drama on Youtube, join www.Viki, Entertainment without language borders!