It is almost midnight here at Morib Beach, 75kilometres from Kuala Lumpur.
More than a thousand people are eagerly waiting for the arrival
of the Nine Emperor Gods to kick start this year's Vegetarian Festival.
The prayer altars are quickly being set up. Devotees light candles, joss sticks and make food offerings to the Gods.
Mediums go into a trance to welcome the Gods,
it being low tide, they have to walk some 500 metres over soft sand to reach the sea.
In the meantime, devotees continue to pour onto the beach and while waiting for the Chariot to return,
they start to make fire offerings to the Gods, many release hot air lanterns into the air.
The mediums and Chariots return having receive the Gods and are quickly transported back to the Temple in Petaling Jaya
for the start of the Annual nine day Festival known locally as Nine Emperor Gods Festival.