This is another search problem.
Let's assume we have a search graph.
It isn't quite a tree but looks like this.
Obviously in the structure we can reach nodes through multiple paths.
So let's assume that our search never expands the same node twice.
Let's also assume this start node is on top. We search down.
And this over here is our goal node.
So left-to-right search, tell me how many nodes
breadth first would expand--do count the start and goal node in the final answer.
Give me the same result for a depth-first search.
Again counting the start and the goal node in your answer.
And again give me your answer for breadth-first
and for depth-first in the right-to-left search paradigm.