GLOBAL
IMPACT
AWARDS
Google
Imagine if
real-time monitoring technology could improve access to clean water
aerial survey systems could prevent the poaching of endangered animals
Imagine if
DNA indexing could protect rare species from illegal trafficking
direct mobile payments could help lift families from extreme poverty
Imagine if
disadvantaged students could receive equal access to advanced science and math classes
kids could grow up seeing positive portrayals of women and girls in media
At Google
we're providing tens of millions of dollars to innovators who aren't just imagining these ideas but making them a reality
GLOBAL IMPACT AWARDS
Google
g.co/globalimpactawards