Hey, welcome to Twitter
Let's quickly go over some basics
at the heart of Twitter there are
small bursts of information called Tweets
quick updates like a text message
but a Tweet can be more than just text
it can include a photo uploaded to Twitter
a video you can watch inside the Tweet
or a link to great content on the web
the stream of of Tweets is your Twitter
and you create it by following accounts
that are interesting to you
when you first join, your Twitter is empty
but during the signup we'll help you find great accounts
that match your interests.
Just pick categories you like such as
entertainment, news, sports, or enter your favorite hobby
and then we will show you some recommended accounts in those areas
when you click on the Follow button you'll start seeing
Tweets from that account on your Twitter
clicking on someone's name or picture
will tell you more about the account
It will also give you the option to follow or unfollow them
Following is not permanent, you can always
unfollow accounts that you're not that into
or search for accounts that you may have missed
after you're done signing up
It's important to know that you don't need to Tweet
to enjoy Twitter
many use it just to listen, rather than share
Once you finish your Twitter profile
by uploading a picture and completing your bio
consider downloading the app
to take Twitter with you on your smartphone
It's a great way to stay up to date with
everything you care about while you're on the go
So there you have it!
Just click the Next button below
and we'll take you through the rest