We all need a lot ofinformation to
get through our day.
So wouldn't it be cool if it wasjust there for you, right
when you needed it?
Introducing GoogleNow for iOS.
The right information atjust the right time.
On your way to work eachmorning, Google Now shows you
the fastest way to get there.(features limited by country)
When you're heading to theairport, get live updates
about your flight.(features limited by country)
And as soon as you land, checkout local phrases and rates.
During the big game, getupdates in real time.
Or instantly learn about nearbyattractions, movies,
and restaurants.(features limited by country)
Google Now is easy to find.
Open the Google Search app,sign in, and swipe up.
Google Now, the rightinformation at
just the right time.