CHAPTER III.
Gregor's serious wound, from which he
suffered for over a month--since no one
ventured to remove the apple, it remained
in his flesh as a visible reminder--seemed
by itself to have reminded the father that,
in spite of his present unhappy and hateful
appearance, Gregor was a member of the
family, something one should not treat as
an enemy, and that it was, on the contrary,
a requirement of family duty to suppress
one's aversion and to endure--nothing else,
just endure.
And if through his wound Gregor had now
apparently lost for good his ability to
move and for the time being needed many,
many minutes to crawl across his room, like
an aged invalid--so far as creeping up high
was concerned, that was unimaginable--
nevertheless for this worsening of his
condition, in his opinion, he did get
completely satisfactory compensation,
because every day towards evening the door
to the living room, which he was in the
habit of keeping a sharp eye on even one or
two hours beforehand, was opened, so that
he, lying down in the darkness of his room,
invisible from the living room, could see
the entire family at the illuminated table
and listen to their conversation, to a
certain extent with their common
permission, a situation quite different
from what had happened before.
Of course, it was no longer the animated
social interaction of former times, which
Gregor in small hotel rooms had always
thought about with a certain longing, when,
tired out, he had had to throw himself into
the damp bedclothes.
For the most part what went on now was very
quiet.
After the evening meal, the father fell
asleep quickly in his arm chair.
The mother and sister talked guardedly to
each other in the stillness.
Bent far over, the mother sewed fine
undergarments for a fashion shop.
The sister, who had taken on a job as a
salesgirl, in the evening studied
stenography and French, so as perhaps later
to obtain a better position.
Sometimes the father woke up and, as if he
was quite ignorant that he had been asleep,
said to the mother "How long you have been
sewing today?" and went right back to
sleep, while the mother and the sister
smiled tiredly to each other.
With a sort of stubbornness the father
refused to take off his servant's uniform
even at home, and while his sleeping gown
hung unused on the coat hook, the father
dozed completely dressed in his place, as
if he was always ready for his
responsibility and even here was waiting
for the voice of his superior.
As a result, in spite of all the care of
the mother and sister, his uniform, which
even at the start was not new, grew dirty,
and Gregor looked, often for the entire
evening, at this clothing, with stains all
over it and with its gold buttons always
polished, in which the old man, although
very uncomfortable, slept peacefully
nonetheless.
As soon as the clock struck ten, the mother
tried gently encouraging the father to wake
up and then persuading him to go to bed, on
the ground that he couldn't get a proper
sleep here and that the father, who had to
report for service at six o'clock, really
needed a good sleep.
But in his stubbornness, which had gripped
him since he had become a servant, he
insisted always on staying even longer by
the table, although he regularly fell
asleep and then could only be prevailed
upon with the greatest difficulty to trade
his chair for the bed.
No matter how much the mother and sister
might at that point work on him with small
admonitions, for a quarter of an hour he
would remain shaking his head slowly, his
eyes closed, without standing up.
The mother would pull him by the sleeve and
speak flattering words into his ear; the
sister would leave her work to help her
mother, but that would not have the desired
effect on the father.
He would settle himself even more deeply in
his arm chair.
Only when the two women grabbed him under
the armpits would he throw his eyes open,
look back and forth at the mother and
sister, and habitually say "This is a life.
This is the peace and quiet of my old age."
And propped up by both women, he would
heave himself up elaborately, as if for him
it was the greatest trouble, allow himself
to be led to the door by the women, wave
them away there, and proceed on his own
from there, while the mother quickly threw
down her sewing implements and the sister
her pen in order to run after the father
and help him some more.
In this overworked and exhausted family who
had time to worry any longer about Gregor
more than was absolutely necessary?
The household was constantly getting
smaller.
The servant girl was now let go.
A huge bony cleaning woman with white hair
flying all over her head came in the
morning and evening to do the heaviest
work.
The mother took care of everything else in
addition to her considerable sewing work.
It even happened that various pieces of
family jewellery, which previously the
mother and sister had been overjoyed to
wear on social and festive occasions, were
sold, as Gregor found out in the evening
from the general discussion of the prices
they had fetched.
But the greatest complaint was always that
they could not leave this apartment, which
was too big for their present means, since
it was impossible to imagine how Gregor
might be moved.
But Gregor fully recognized that it was not
just consideration for him which was
preventing a move, for he could have been
transported easily in a suitable box with a
few air holes.
The main thing holding the family back from
a change in living quarters was far more
their complete hopelessness and the idea
that they had been struck by a misfortune
like no one else in their entire circle of
relatives and acquaintances.
What the world demands of poor people they
now carried out to an extreme degree.
The father bought breakfast to the petty
officials at the bank, the mother
sacrificed herself for the undergarments of
strangers, the sister behind her desk was
at the beck and call of customers, but the
family's energies did not extend any
further.
And the wound in his back began to pain
Gregor all over again, when now mother and
sister, after they had escorted the father
to bed, came back, let their work lie,
moved close together, and sat cheek to
cheek and when his mother would now say,
pointing to Gregor's room, "Close the door,
Grete," and when Gregor was again in the
darkness, while close by the women mingled
their tears or, quite dry eyed, stared at
the table.
Gregor spent his nights and days with
hardly any sleep.
Sometimes he thought that the next time the
door opened he would take over the family
arrangements just as he had earlier.
In his imagination appeared again, after a
long time, his employer and supervisor and
the apprentices, the excessively spineless
custodian, two or three friends from other
businesses, a chambermaid from a hotel in
the provinces, a loving fleeting memory, a
female cashier from a hat shop, whom he had
seriously but too slowly courted--they all
appeared mixed in with strangers or people
he had already forgotten, but instead of
helping him and his family, they were all
unapproachable, and he was happy to see
them disappear.
But then he was in no mood to worry about
his family.
He was filled with sheer anger over the
wretched care he was getting, even though
he couldn't imagine anything which he might
have an appetite for.
Still, he made plans about how he could
take from the larder what he at all account
deserved, even if he wasn't hungry.
Without thinking any more about how they
might be able to give Gregor special
pleasure, the sister now kicked some food
or other very quickly into his room in the
morning and at noon, before she ran off to
her shop, and in the evening, quite
indifferent to whether the food had perhaps
only been tasted or, what happened most
frequently, remained entirely undisturbed,
she whisked it out with one sweep of her
broom.
The task of cleaning his room, which she
now always carried out in the evening,
could not be done any more quickly.
Streaks of dirt ran along the walls; here
and there lay tangles of dust and garbage.
At first, when his sister arrived, Gregor
positioned himself in a particularly filthy
corner in order with this posture to make
something of a protest.
But he could have well stayed there for
weeks without his sister's changing her
ways.
In fact, she perceived the dirt as much as
he did, but she had decided just to let it
stay.
In this business, with a touchiness which
was quite new to her and which had
generally taken over the entire family, she
kept watch to see that the cleaning of
Gregor's room remained reserved for her.
Once his mother had undertaken a major
cleaning of Gregor's room, which she had
only completed successfully after using a
few buckets of water.
But the extensive dampness made Gregor sick
and he lay supine, embittered and immobile
on the couch.
However, the mother's punishment was not
delayed for long.
For in the evening the sister had hardly
observed the change in Gregor's room before
she ran into the living room mightily
offended and, in spite of her mother's hand
lifted high in entreaty, broke out in a fit
of crying.
Her parents--the father had, of course,
woken up with a start in his arm chair--at
first looked at her astonished and
helpless, until they started to get
agitated.
Turning to his right, the father heaped
reproaches on the mother that she was not
to take over the cleaning of Gregor's room
from the sister and, turning to his left,
he shouted at the sister that she would no
longer be allowed to clean Gregor's room
ever again, while the mother tried to pull
the father, beside himself in his
excitement, into the bed room.
The sister, shaken by her crying fit,
pounded on the table with her tiny fists,
and Gregor hissed at all this, angry that
no one thought about shutting the door and
sparing him the sight of this commotion.
But even when the sister, exhausted from
her daily work, had grown tired of caring
for Gregor as she had before, even then the
mother did not have to come at all on her
behalf.
And Gregor did not have to be neglected.
For now the cleaning woman was there.
This old widow, who in her long life must
have managed to survive the worst with the
help of her bony frame, had no real horror
of Gregor.
Without being in the least curious, she had
once by chance opened Gregor's door.
At the sight of Gregor, who, totally
surprised, began to scamper here and there,
although no one was chasing him, she
remained standing with her hands folded
across her stomach staring at him.
Since then she did not fail to open the
door furtively a little every morning and
evening to look in on Gregor.
At first, she also called him to her with
words which she presumably thought were
friendly, like "Come here for a bit, old
dung beetle!" or "Hey, look at the old dung
beetle!"
Addressed in such a manner, Gregor answered
nothing, but remained motionless in his
place, as if the door had not been opened
at all.
If only, instead of allowing this cleaning
woman to disturb him uselessly whenever she
felt like it, they had given her orders to
clean up his room every day!
One day in the early morning--a hard
downpour, perhaps already a sign of the
coming spring, struck the window panes--
when the cleaning woman started up once
again with her usual conversation, Gregor
was so bitter that he turned towards her,
as if for an attack, although slowly and
weakly.
But instead of being afraid of him, the
cleaning woman merely lifted up a chair
standing close by the door and, as she
stood there with her mouth wide open, her
intention was clear: she would close her
mouth only when the chair in her hand had
been thrown down on Gregor's back.
"This goes no further, all right?" she
asked, as Gregor turned himself around
again, and she placed the chair calmly back
in the corner.
Gregor ate hardly anything any more.
Only when he chanced to move past the food
which had been prepared did he, as a game,
take a bit into his mouth, hold it there
for hours, and generally spit it out again.
At first he thought it might be his sadness
over the condition of his room which kept
him from eating, but he very soon became
reconciled to the alterations in his room.
People had grown accustomed to put into
storage in his room things which they
couldn't put anywhere else, and at this
point there were many such things, now that
they had rented one room of the apartment
to three lodgers.
These solemn gentlemen--all three had full
beards, as Gregor once found out through a
crack in the door--were meticulously intent
on tidiness, not only in their own room
but, since they had now rented a room here,
in the entire household, and particularly
in the kitchen.
They simply did not tolerate any useless or
shoddy stuff.
Moreover, for the most part they had
brought with them their own pieces of
furniture.
Thus, many items had become superfluous,
and these were not really things one could
sell or things people wanted to throw out.
All these items ended up in Gregor's room,
even the box of ashes and the garbage pail
from the kitchen.
The cleaning woman, always in a hurry,
simply flung anything that was momentarily
useless into Gregor's room.
Fortunately Gregor generally saw only the
relevant object and the hand which held it.
The cleaning woman perhaps was intending,
when time and opportunity allowed, to take
the stuff out again or to throw everything
out all at once, but in fact the things
remained lying there, wherever they had
ended up at the first throw, unless Gregor
squirmed his way through the accumulation
of junk and moved it.
At first he was forced to do this because
otherwise there was no room for him to
creep around, but later he did it with a
growing pleasure, although after such
movements, tired to death and feeling
wretched, he didn't budge for hours.
Because the lodgers sometimes also took
their evening meal at home in the common
living room, the door to the living room
stayed shut on many evenings.
But Gregor had no trouble at all going
without the open door.
Already on many evenings when it was open
he had not availed himself of it, but,
without the family noticing, was stretched
out in the darkest corner of his room.
However, once the cleaning woman had left
the door to the living room slightly ajar,
and it remained open even when the lodgers
came in in the evening and the lights were
put on.
They sat down at the head of the table,
where in earlier days the mother, the
father, and Gregor had eaten, unfolded
their serviettes, and picked up their
knives and forks.
The mother immediately appeared in the door
with a dish of meat and right behind her
the sister with a dish piled high with
potatoes.
The food gave off a lot of steam.
The gentlemen lodgers bent over the plate
set before them, as if they wanted to check
it before eating, and in fact the one who
sat in the middle--for the other two he
seemed to serve as the authority--cut off a
piece of meat still on the plate obviously
to establish whether it was sufficiently
tender and whether or not something should
be shipped back to the kitchen.
He was satisfied, and mother and sister,
who had looked on in suspense, began to
breathe easily and to smile.
The family itself ate in the kitchen.
In spite of that, before the father went
into the kitchen, he came into the room and
with a single bow, cap in hand, made a tour
of the table.
The lodgers rose up collectively and
murmured something in their beards.
Then, when they were alone, they ate almost
in complete silence.
It seemed odd to Gregor that, out of all
the many different sorts of sounds of
eating, what was always audible was their
chewing teeth, as if by that Gregor should
be shown that people needed their teeth to
eat and that nothing could be done even
with the most handsome toothless jawbone.
"I really do have an appetite," Gregor said
to himself sorrowfully, "but not for these
things.
How these lodgers stuff themselves, and I
am dying."
On this very evening the violin sounded
from the kitchen.
Gregor didn't remember hearing it all
through this period.
The lodgers had already ended their night
meal, the middle one had pulled out a
newspaper and had given each of the other
two a page, and they were now leaning back,
reading and smoking.
When the violin started playing, they
became attentive, got up, and went on
tiptoe to the hall door, at which they
remained standing pressed up against one
another.
They must have been audible from the
kitchen, because the father called out
"Perhaps the gentlemen don't like the
playing?
It can be stopped at once."
"On the contrary," stated the lodger in the
middle, "might the young woman not come
into us and play in the room here, where it
is really much more comfortable and
cheerful?"
"Oh, thank you," cried out the father, as
if he were the one playing the violin.
The men stepped back into the room and
waited.
Soon the father came with the music stand,
the mother with the sheet music, and the
sister with the violin.
The sister calmly prepared everything for
the recital.
The parents, who had never previously
rented a room and therefore exaggerated
their politeness to the lodgers, dared not
sit on their own chairs.
The father leaned against the door, his
right hand stuck between two buttons of his
buttoned-up uniform.
The mother, however, accepted a chair
offered by one lodger.
Since she left the chair sit where the
gentleman had chanced to put it, she sat to
one side in a corner.
The sister began to play.
The father and mother, one on each side,
followed attentively the movements of her
hands.
Attracted by the playing, Gregor had
ventured to advance a little further
forward and his head was already in the
living room.
He scarcely wondered about the fact that
recently he had had so little consideration
for the others.
Earlier this consideration had been
something he was proud of.
And for that very reason he would have had
at this moment more reason to hide away,
because as a result of the dust which lay
all over his room and flew around with the
slightest movement, he was totally covered
in dirt.
On his back and his sides he carted around
with him dust, threads, hair, and remnants
of food.
His indifference to everything was much too
great for him to lie on his back and scour
himself on the carpet, as he often had done
earlier during the day.
In spite of his condition he had no
timidity about inching forward a bit on the
spotless floor of the living room.
In any case, no one paid him any attention.
The family was all caught up in the violin
playing.
The lodgers, by contrast, who for the
moment had placed themselves, hands in
their trouser pockets, behind the music
stand much too close to the sister, so that
they could all see the sheet music,
something that must certainly bother the
sister, soon drew back to the window
conversing in low voices with bowed heads,
where they then remained, worriedly
observed by the father.
It now seemed really clear that, having
assumed they were to hear a beautiful or
entertaining violin recital, they were
disappointed and were allowing their peace
and quiet to be disturbed only out of
politeness.
The way in which they all blew the smoke
from their cigars out of their noses and
mouths in particular led one to conclude
that they were very irritated.
And yet his sister was playing so
beautifully.
Her face was turned to the side, her gaze
followed the score intently and sadly.
Gregor crept forward still a little
further, keeping his head close against the
floor in order to be able to catch her gaze
if possible.
Was he an animal that music so captivated
him?
For him it was as if the way to the unknown
nourishment he craved was revealing itself.
He was determined to press forward right to
his sister, to tug at her dress, and to
indicate to her in this way that she might
still come with her violin into his room,
because here no one valued the recital as
he wanted to value it.
He did not wish to let her go from his room
any more, at least not as long as he lived.
His frightening appearance would for the
first time become useful for him.
He wanted to be at all the doors of his
room simultaneously and snarl back at the
attackers.
However, his sister should not be compelled
but would remain with him voluntarily.
She would sit next to him on the sofa, bend
down her ear to him, and he would then
confide in her that he firmly intended to
send her to the conservatory and that, if
his misfortune had not arrived in the
interim, he would have declared all this
last Christmas--had Christmas really
already come and gone?--and would have
brooked no argument.
After this explanation his sister would
break out in tears of emotion, and Gregor
would lift himself up to her armpit and
kiss her throat, which she, from the time
she started going to work, had left exposed
without a band or a collar.
"Mr. Samsa," called out the middle lodger
to the father and, without uttering a
further word, pointed his index finger at
Gregor as he was moving slowly forward.
The violin fell silent.
The middle lodger smiled, first shaking his
head once at his friends, and then looked
down at Gregor once more.
Rather than driving Gregor back again, the
father seemed to consider it of prime
importance to calm down the lodgers,
although they were not at all upset and
Gregor seemed to entertain them more than
the violin recital.
The father hurried over to them and with
outstretched arms tried to push them into
their own room and simultaneously to block
their view of Gregor with his own body.
At this point they became really somewhat
irritated, although one no longer knew
whether that was because of the father's
behaviour or because of knowledge they had
just acquired that they had, without
knowing it, a neighbour like Gregor.
They demanded explanations from his father,
raised their arms to make their points,
tugged agitatedly at their beards, and
moved back towards their room quite slowly.
In the meantime, the isolation which had
suddenly fallen upon his sister after the
sudden breaking off of the recital had
overwhelmed her.
She had held onto the violin and bow in her
limp hands for a little while and had
continued to look at the sheet music as if
she was still playing.
All at once she pulled herself together,
placed the instrument in her mother's lap--
the mother was still sitting in her chair
having trouble breathing for her lungs were
labouring--and had run into the next room,
which the lodgers, pressured by the father,
were already approaching more rapidly.
One could observe how under the sister's
practiced hands the sheets and pillows on
the beds were thrown on high and arranged.
Even before the lodgers had reached the
room, she was finished fixing the beds and
was slipping out.
The father seemed so gripped once again
with his stubbornness that he forgot about
the respect which he always owed to his
renters.
He pressed on and on, until at the door of
the room the middle gentleman stamped
loudly with his foot and thus brought the
father to a standstill.
"I hereby declare," the middle lodger said,
raising his hand and casting his glance
both on the mother and the sister, "that
considering the disgraceful conditions
prevailing in this apartment and family"--
with this he spat decisively on the floor--
"I immediately cancel my room.
I will, of course, pay nothing at all for
the days which I have lived here; on the
contrary I shall think about whether or not
I will initiate some sort of action against
you, something which--believe me--will be
very easy to establish."
He fell silent and looked directly in front
of him, as if he was waiting for something.
In fact, his two friends immediately joined
in with their opinions, "We also give
immediate notice."
At that he seized the door handle, banged
the door shut, and locked it.
The father groped his way tottering to his
chair and let himself fall in it.
It looked as if he was stretching out for
his usual evening snooze, but the heavy
nodding of his head, which looked as if it
was without support, showed that he was not
sleeping at all.
Gregor had lain motionless the entire time
in the spot where the lodgers had caught
him.
Disappointment with the collapse of his
plan and perhaps also weakness brought on
by his severe hunger made it impossible for
him to move.
He was certainly afraid that a general
disaster would break over him at any
moment, and he waited.
He was not even startled when the violin
fell from the mother's lap, out from under
her trembling fingers, and gave off a
reverberating tone.
"My dear parents," said the sister banging
her hand on the table by way of an
introduction, "things cannot go on any
longer in this way.
Maybe if you don't understand that, well,
I do.
I will not utter my brother's name in front
of this monster, and thus I say only that
we must try to get rid of it.
We have tried what is humanly possible to
take care of it and to be patient.
I believe that no one can criticize us in
the slightest."
"She is right in a thousand ways," said the
father to himself.
The mother, who was still incapable of
breathing properly, began to cough numbly
with her hand held up over her mouth and a
manic expression in her eyes.
The sister hurried over to her mother and
held her forehead.
The sister's words seemed to have led the
father to certain reflections.
He sat upright, played with his uniform hat
among the plates, which still lay on the
table from the lodgers' evening meal, and
looked now and then at the motionless
Gregor.
"We must try to get rid of it," the sister
now said decisively to the father, for the
mother, in her coughing fit, was not
listening to anything.
"It is killing you both.
I see it coming.
When people have to work as hard as we all
do, they cannot also tolerate this endless
torment at home.
I just can't go on any more."
And she broke out into such a crying fit
that her tears flowed out down onto her
mother's face.
She wiped them off her mother with
mechanical motions of her hands.
"Child," said the father sympathetically
and with obvious appreciation, "then what
should we do?"
The sister only shrugged her shoulders as a
sign of the perplexity which, in contrast
to her previous confidence, had come over
her while she was crying.
"If only he understood us," said the father
in a semi-questioning tone.
The sister, in the midst of her sobbing,
shook her hand energetically as a sign that
there was no point thinking of that.
"If he only understood us," repeated the
father and by shutting his eyes he absorbed
the sister's conviction of the
impossibility of this point, "then perhaps
some compromise would be possible with him.
But as it is.
.
."
"It must be gotten rid of," cried the
sister.
"That is the only way, father.
You must try to get rid of the idea that
this is Gregor.
The fact that we have believed for so long,
that is truly our real misfortune.
But how can it be Gregor?
If it were Gregor, he would have long ago
realized that a communal life among human
beings is not possible with such an animal
and would have gone away voluntarily.
Then we would not have a brother, but we
could go on living and honour his memory.
But this animal plagues us.
It drives away the lodgers, will obviously
take over the entire apartment, and leave
us to spend the night in the alley.
Just look, father," she suddenly cried out,
"he's already starting up again."
With a fright which was totally
incomprehensible to Gregor, the sister even
left the mother, pushed herself away from
her chair, as if she would sooner sacrifice
her mother than remain in Gregor's
vicinity, and rushed behind her father who,
excited merely by her behaviour, also stood
up and half raised his arms in front of the
sister as though to protect her.
But Gregor did not have any notion of
wishing to create problems for anyone and
certainly not for his sister.
He had just started to turn himself around
in order to creep back into his room, quite
a startling sight, since, as a result of
his suffering condition, he had to guide
himself through the difficulty of turning
around with his head, in this process
lifting and banging it against the floor
several times.
He paused and looked around.
His good intentions seem to have been
recognized.
The fright had lasted only for a moment.
Now they looked at him in silence and
sorrow.
His mother lay in her chair, with her legs
stretched out and pressed together; her
eyes were almost shut from weariness.
The father and sister sat next to one
another.
The sister had set her hands around the
father's neck.
"Now perhaps I can actually turn myself
around," thought Gregor and began the task
again.
He couldn't stop puffing at the effort and
had to rest now and then.
Besides, no one was urging him on.
It was all left to him on his own.
When he had completed turning around, he
immediately began to wander straight back.
He was astonished at the great distance
which separated him from his room and did
not understand in the least how in his
weakness he had covered the same distance a
short time before, almost without noticing
it.
Constantly intent only on creeping along
quickly, he hardly paid any attention to
the fact that no word or cry from his
family interrupted him.
Only when he was already in the door did he
turn his head, not completely, because he
felt his neck growing stiff.
At any rate he still saw that behind him
nothing had changed.
Only the sister was standing up.
His last glimpse brushed over the mother
who was now completely asleep.
Hardly was he inside his room when the door
was pushed shut very quickly, bolted fast,
and barred.
Gregor was startled by the sudden commotion
behind him, so much so that his little
limbs bent double under him.
It was his sister who had been in such a
hurry.
She had stood up right away, had waited,
and had then sprung forward nimbly.
Gregor had not heard anything of her
approach.
She cried out "Finally!" to her parents, as
she turned the key in the lock.
"What now?"
Gregor asked himself and looked around him
in the darkness.
He soon made the discovery that he could no
longer move at all.
He was not surprised at that.
On the contrary, it struck him as unnatural
that up to this point he had really been
able up to move around with these thin
little legs.
Besides he felt relatively content.
True, he had pains throughout his entire
body, but it seemed to him that they were
gradually becoming weaker and weaker and
would finally go away completely.
The rotten apple in his back and the
inflamed surrounding area, entirely covered
with white dust, he hardly noticed.
He remembered his family with deep feelings
of love.
In this business, his own thought that he
had to disappear was, if possible, even
more decisive than his sister's.
He remained in this state of empty and
peaceful reflection until the tower clock
struck three o'clock in the morning.
From the window he witnessed the beginning
of the general dawning outside.
Then without willing it, his head sank all
the way down, and from his nostrils flowed
out weakly his last breath.
Early in the morning the cleaning woman
came.
In her sheer energy and haste she banged
all the doors--in precisely the way people
had already asked her to avoid--so much so
that once she arrived a quiet sleep was no
longer possible anywhere in the entire
apartment.
In her customarily brief visit to Gregor
she at first found nothing special.
She thought he lay so immobile there
because he wanted to play the offended
party.
She gave him credit for as complete an
understanding as possible.
Since she happened to be holding the long
broom in her hand, she tried to tickle
Gregor with it from the door.
When that was quite unsuccessful, she
became irritated and poked Gregor a little,
and only when she had shoved him from his
place without any resistance did she become
attentive.
When she quickly realized the true state of
affairs, her eyes grew large, she whistled
to herself.
However, she didn't restrain herself for
long.
She pulled open the door of the bedroom and
yelled in a loud voice into the darkness,
"Come and look.
It's kicked the bucket.
It's lying there, totally snuffed!"
The Samsa married couple sat upright in
their marriage bed and had to get over
their fright at the cleaning woman before
they managed to grasp her message.
But then Mr. and Mrs. Samsa climbed very
quickly out of bed, one on either side.
Mr. Samsa threw the bedspread over his
shoulders, Mrs. Samsa came out only in her
night-shirt, and like this they stepped
into Gregor's room.
Meanwhile, the door of the living room, in
which Grete had slept since the lodgers had
arrived on the scene, had also opened.
She was fully clothed, as if she had not
slept at all; her white face also seem to
indicate that.
"Dead?" said Mrs. Samsa and looked
questioningly at the cleaning woman,
although she could check everything on her
own and even understand without a check.
"I should say so," said the cleaning woman
and, by way of proof, poked Gregor's body
with the broom a considerable distance more
to the side.
Mrs. Samsa made a movement as if she wished
to restrain the broom, but didn't do it.
"Well," said Mr. Samsa, "now we can give
thanks to God."
He crossed himself, and the three women
followed his example.
Grete, who did not take her eyes off the
corpse, said, "Look how thin he was.
He had eaten nothing for such a long time.
The meals which came in here came out again
exactly the same."
In fact, Gregor's body was completely flat
and dry.
That was apparent really for the first
time, now that he was no longer raised on
his small limbs and nothing else distracted
one's gaze.
"Grete, come into us for a moment," said
Mrs. Samsa with a melancholy smile, and
Grete went, not without looking back at the
corpse, behind her parents into the bed
room.
The cleaning woman shut the door and opened
the window wide.
In spite of the early morning, the fresh
air was partly tinged with warmth.
It was already the end of March.
The three lodgers stepped out of their room
and looked around for their breakfast,
astonished that they had been forgotten.
"Where is the breakfast?" asked the middle
one of the gentlemen grumpily to the
cleaning woman.
However, she laid her finger to her lips
and then quickly and silently indicated to
the lodgers that they could come into
Gregor's room.
So they came and stood in the room, which
was already quite bright, around Gregor's
corpse, their hands in the pockets of their
somewhat worn jackets.
Then the door of the bed room opened, and
Mr. Samsa appeared in his uniform, with his
wife on one arm and his daughter on the
other.
All were a little tear stained.
Now and then Grete pressed her face onto
her father's arm.
"Get out of my apartment immediately," said
Mr. Samsa and pulled open the door, without
letting go of the women.
"What do you mean?" said the middle lodger,
somewhat dismayed and with a sugary smile.
The two others kept their hands behind them
and constantly rubbed them against each
other, as if in joyful anticipation of a
great squabble which must end up in their
favour.
"I mean exactly what I say," replied Mr.
Samsa and went directly with his two female
companions up to the lodger.
The latter at first stood there motionless
and looked at the floor, as if matters were
arranging themselves in a new way in his
head.
"All right, then we'll go," he said and
looked up at Mr. Samsa as if, suddenly
overcome by humility, he was asking fresh
permission for this decision.
Mr. Samsa merely nodded to him repeatedly
with his eyes open wide.
Following that, the lodger actually went
with long strides immediately out into the
hall.
His two friends had already been listening
for a while with their hands quite still,
and now they hopped smartly after him, as
if afraid that Mr. Samsa could step into
the hall ahead of them and disturb their
reunion with their leader.
In the hall all three of them took their
hats from the coat rack, pulled their canes
from the cane holder, bowed silently, and
left the apartment.
In what turned out to be an entirely
groundless mistrust, Mr. Samsa stepped with
the two women out onto the landing, leaned
against the railing, and looked over as the
three lodgers slowly but steadily made
their way down the long staircase,
disappeared on each floor in a certain turn
of the stairwell, and in a few seconds came
out again.
The deeper they proceeded, the more the
Samsa family lost interest in them, and
when a butcher with a tray on his head come
to meet them and then with a proud bearing
ascended the stairs high above them, Mr.
Samsa., together with the women, left the
banister, and they all returned, as if
relieved, back into their apartment.
They decided to pass that day resting and
going for a stroll.
Not only had they earned this break from
work, but there was no question that they
really needed it.
And so they sat down at the table and wrote
three letters of apology: Mr. Samsa to his
supervisor, Mrs. Samsa to her client, and
Grete to her proprietor.
During the writing the cleaning woman came
in to say that she was going off, for her
morning work was finished.
The three people writing at first merely
nodded, without glancing up.
Only when the cleaning woman was still
unwilling to depart, did they look up
angrily.
"Well?" asked Mr. Samsa.
The cleaning woman stood smiling in the
doorway, as if she had a great stroke of
luck to report to the family but would only
do it if she was asked directly.
The almost upright small ostrich feather in
her hat, which had irritated Mr. Samsa
during her entire service, swayed lightly
in all directions.
"All right then, what do you really want?"
asked Mrs. Samsa, whom the cleaning lady
still usually respected.
"Well," answered the cleaning woman,
smiling so happily she couldn't go on
speaking right away, "about how that
rubbish from the next room should be thrown
out, you mustn't worry about it.
It's all taken care of."
Mrs. Samsa and Grete bent down to their
letters, as though they wanted to go on
writing.
Mr. Samsa, who noticed that the cleaning
woman wanted to start describing everything
in detail, decisively prevented her with an
outstretched hand.
But since she was not allowed to explain,
she remembered the great hurry she was in,
and called out, clearly insulted, "Bye bye,
everyone," turned around furiously and left
the apartment with a fearful slamming of
the door.
"This evening she'll be let go," said Mr.
Samsa, but he got no answer from either his
wife or from his daughter, because the
cleaning woman seemed to have upset once
again the tranquillity they had just
attained.
They got up, went to the window, and
remained there, with their arms about each
other.
Mr. Samsa turned around in his chair in
their direction and observed them quietly
for a while.
Then he called out, "All right, come here
then.
Let's finally get rid of old things.
And have a little consideration for me."
The women attended to him at once.
They rushed to him, caressed him, and
quickly ended their letters.
Then all three left the apartment together,
something they had not done for months now,
and took the electric tram into the open
air outside the city.
The car in which they were sitting by
themselves was totally engulfed by the warm
sun.
Leaning back comfortably in their seats,
they talked to each other about future
prospects, and they discovered that on
closer observation these were not at all
bad, for the three of them had employment,
about which they had not really questioned
each other at all, which was extremely
favourable and with especially promising
prospects.
The greatest improvement in their situation
at this moment, of course, had to come from
a change of dwelling.
Now they wanted to rent an apartment
smaller and cheaper but better situated and
generally more practical than the present
one, which Gregor had found.
While they amused themselves in this way,
it struck Mr. and Mrs. Samsa, almost at the
same moment, how their daughter, who was
getting more animated all the time, had
blossomed recently, in spite of all the
troubles which had made her cheeks pale,
into a beautiful and voluptuous young
woman.
Growing more silent and almost
unconsciously understanding each other in
their glances, they thought that the time
was now at hand to seek out a good honest
man for her.
And it was something of a confirmation of
their new dreams and good intentions when
at the end of their journey their daughter
got up first and stretched her young body.