The first thing I do when I wake up in the morning…I get on my computer, and I open
up Google. That’s my homepage, and that’s where I start.
I type in ‘Weather,’ ‘Cincinnati,’ and it comes up instantly.
The first thing I do is check out the 49ers. The Bears.
The Cowboys! The Saints.
I’m following the presidential race, and ‘Narrowing by Time’ keeps me up to date,
fast.
I just type in what movie and my zip code, and it’ll pop up. There’s this theater,
with this time. It’s so fast.
My mind still works in Celsius sometimes. It’s really helpful for us to have the conversion
function.
I use the calculator a lot. I’m constantly giving out price quotes.
I’m always putting in, like, how many ounces are in a cup. Or, you know, things like that.
I like to try new restaurants. Finding it on Google is really easily done.
We found a number of recipes that use pineapples. Maddy doesn’t like raisins, so we actually
de-selected the recipes with raisins…so what came up were foods that the kids liked.
I always come back to my tried and true Google.
I like to use the Google Voice function to do my searches. There’s a little thing that
looks like a microphone…so I’ll press that and then just speak right into it
"Waikiki Beach."
It comes up with a search just like you would get when you type something in.
I saw this plant that I really, really loved. And we took a picture, and we were able to
figure out what it was. So it’s now on our balcony.
I use Google Search to search by subject. Getting black and white pictures instead of
just colored photos
Google can make you look like a genius.
Google makes things so easy.
Now if Google could just make my son eat his vegetables...
It’s truly amazing.