Magnets can be created by running currents
through wires, finding a suitable material
that naturally has all the magnetic fields
of its atoms aligned, or forcing the magnetic
fields of atoms to align.
But there's one more kind of magnetism that
all materials exhibit, even those whose constituent
atoms aren't magnetic - though it's so weak
that the other kinds of magnetism often overwhelm
it. Basically, an external magnetic field
causes the electrons around atoms in a material
to change course, and their new motion generates
an opposing magnetic field. This field is
pretty weak, but it does cause the material
to be repulsed from the magnet a little bit
- for example, if you hang a wooden toothpick
in a magnetic field, the ends will repel the
field and it will end up aligning across the
magnetic field. This is a convenient way to
remember the name of this kind of magnetism
- diamagnetism - since "dia" means across,
like the "diameter" measured across a circle.
Diamagnetic materials will repel a magnet,
and a diamagnetic "compass" will point across
the magnetic field - that is, it will orient
east/west.
As weak as it is, diamagnetism is pretty darn
awesome because it's a repulsive effect: any
diamagnetic material will levitate in a strong
enough magnetic field! Like this chunk of
graphene, or, since water is diamagnetic,
this frog. In principle, humans could also
be levitated this way, though the magnetic
fields required would be enormous.
There are also a lot of subtleties we've skated
over, like the fact that nitrogen is diamagnetic
even though as an atom it has unpaired electrons
- one might think that it *should* be at the
very least paramagnetic. But nitrogen atoms
bond to form N2 molecules which have full
outer electron shells and are thus only diamagnetic.
On the other hand, molecular O2, as we've
seen, still has unpaired electrons, and it's
paramagnetic.
You've probably also seen how superconductors
can levitate in a magnetic field, which is
a kind of perfect diamagnetism - not only
do the currents in a superconductor create
opposing magnetic fields, they expel magnetic
fields from the material entirely. But the
root cause is very very different, and that's
a journey for another day.