The screenplay on your home computer
The presentation at work
Those vacation photos and videos on your phone
The trip itinerary on your tablet
resumes, recipes, videos
With Google Drive, you can now access your files from wherever you are
Even the big ones
Whichever program you're using, just drag and drop
And there are all of your files ready to be opened by you
And shared with anyone you want
Forget files being too big to email
Just share them with Drive and everyone has the same file, automatically
That they can edit together, from anywhere
Now all your stuff, work or play, is in one place
Easy to find and easy to share
Google Drive. Keep everything. Share anything.