ETYMOLOGY and EXTRACTSETYMOLOGY.
(Supplied by a Late Consumptive Usher to aGrammar School)
The pale Usher--threadbare in coat, heart,body, and brain; I see him now.
He was ever dusting his old lexicons andgrammars, with a queer handkerchief,
mockingly embellished with all the gayflags of all the known nations of the
world.
He loved to dust his old grammars; itsomehow mildly reminded him of his
mortality.
"While you take in hand to school others,and to teach them by what name a whale-fish
is to be called in our tongue leaving out,through ignorance, the letter H, which
almost alone maketh the signification of
the word, you deliver that which is nottrue."
--HACKLUYT
"WHALE....Sw. and Dan. HVAL. This animal isnamed from roundness or rolling; for in
Dan. HVALT is arched or vaulted."--WEBSTER'S DICTIONARY
"WHALE....It is more immediately from theDut. and Ger. WALLEN; A.S. WALW-IAN, to
roll, to wallow."--RICHARDSON'S DICTIONARY
KETOS,GREEK.CETUS,LATIN.
WHOEL,ANGLO-SAXON.HVALT,DANISH.
WAL,DUTCH.HWAL,SWEDISH.
WHALE,ICELANDIC.WHALE,ENGLISH.
BALEINE,FRENCH.BALLENA,SPANISH.
PEKEE-NUEE-NUEE,FEGEE.PEKEE-NUEE-NUEE,ERROMANGOAN.
EXTRACTS (Supplied by a Sub-Sub-Librarian).
It will be seen that this mere painstakingburrower and grub-worm of a poor devil of a
Sub-Sub appears to have gone through thelong Vaticans and street-stalls of the
earth, picking up whatever random allusions
to whales he could anyways find in any bookwhatsoever, sacred or profane.
Therefore you must not, in every case atleast, take the higgledy-piggledy whale
statements, however authentic, in theseextracts, for veritable gospel cetology.
Far from it.
As touching the ancient authors generally,as well as the poets here appearing, these
extracts are solely valuable orentertaining, as affording a glancing
bird's eye view of what has been
promiscuously said, thought, fancied, andsung of Leviathan, by many nations and
generations, including our own.So fare thee well, poor devil of a Sub-Sub,
whose commentator I am.
Thou belongest to that hopeless, sallowtribe which no wine of this world will ever
warm; and for whom even Pale Sherry wouldbe too rosy-strong; but with whom one
sometimes loves to sit, and feel poor-
devilish, too; and grow convivial upontears; and say to them bluntly, with full
eyes and empty glasses, and in notaltogether unpleasant sadness--Give it up,
Sub-Subs!
For by how much the more pains ye take toplease the world, by so much the more shall
ye for ever go thankless!Would that I could clear out Hampton Court
and the Tuileries for ye!
But gulp down your tears and hie aloft tothe royal-mast with your hearts; for your
friends who have gone before are clearingout the seven-storied heavens, and making
refugees of long-pampered Gabriel, Michael,and Raphael, against your coming.
Here ye strike but splintered heartstogether--there, ye shall strike
unsplinterable glasses!
EXTRACTS."And God created great whales."
--GENESIS.
"Leviathan maketh a path to shine afterhim; One would think the deep to be hoary."
--JOB.
"Now the Lord had prepared a great fish toswallow up Jonah."
--JONAH.
"There go the ships; there is thatLeviathan whom thou hast made to play
therein."--PSALMS.
"In that day, the Lord with his sore, andgreat, and strong sword, shall punish
Leviathan the piercing serpent, evenLeviathan that crooked serpent; and he
shall slay the dragon that is in the sea."
--ISAIAH
"And what thing soever besides comethwithin the chaos of this monster's mouth,
be it beast, boat, or stone, down it goesall incontinently that foul great swallow
of his, and perisheth in the bottomlessgulf of his paunch."
--HOLLAND'S PLUTARCH'S MORALS.
"The Indian Sea breedeth the most and thebiggest fishes that are: among which the
Whales and Whirlpooles called Balaene, takeup as much in length as four acres or
arpens of land."
--HOLLAND'S PLINY.
"Scarcely had we proceeded two days on thesea, when about sunrise a great many Whales
and other monsters of the sea, appeared.Among the former, one was of a most
monstrous size....
This came towards us, open-mouthed, raisingthe waves on all sides, and beating the sea
before him into a foam."--TOOKE'S LUCIAN.
"THE TRUE HISTORY."
"He visited this country also with a viewof catching horse-whales, which had bones
of very great value for their teeth, ofwhich he brought some to the king....
The best whales were catched in his owncountry, of which some were forty-eight,
some fifty yards long.He said that he was one of six who had
killed sixty in two days."
--OTHER OR OTHER'S VERBAL NARRATIVE TAKENDOWN FROM HIS MOUTH BY KING ALFRED, A.D.
890.
"And whereas all the other things, whetherbeast or vessel, that enter into the
dreadful gulf of this monster's (whale's)mouth, are immediately lost and swallowed
up, the sea-gudgeon retires into it ingreat security, and there sleeps."
--MONTAIGNE.--APOLOGY FOR RAIMOND SEBOND.
"Let us fly, let us fly!Old Nick take me if is not Leviathan
described by the noble prophet Moses in thelife of patient Job."
--RABELAIS.
"This whale's liver was two cartloads."--STOWE'S ANNALS.
"The great Leviathan that maketh the seasto seethe like boiling pan."
--LORD BACON'S VERSION OF THE PSALMS.
"Touching that monstrous bulk of the whaleor ork we have received nothing certain.
They grow exceeding fat, insomuch that anincredible quantity of oil will be
extracted out of one whale."
--IBID."HISTORY OF LIFE AND DEATH."
"The sovereignest thing on earth isparmacetti for an inward bruise."
--KING HENRY.
"Very like a whale."--HAMLET.
"Which to secure, no skill of leach's artMote him availle, but to returne againe
To his wound's worker, that with lowly dart
Dinting his breast,had bred his restless paine,
Like as the wounded whaleto shore flies thro' the maine."
--THE FAERIE QUEEN.
"Immense as whales, the motion of whosevast bodies can in a peaceful calm trouble
the ocean til it boil."--SIR WILLIAM DAVENANT.
PREFACE TO GONDIBERT.
"What spermacetti is, men might justlydoubt, since the learned Hosmannus in his
work of thirty years, saith plainly, Nescioquid sit."
--SIR T. BROWNE. OF SPERMA CETI AND THESPERMA CETI WHALE. VIDE HIS V. E.
"Like Spencer's Talus with his modern flailHe threatens ruin with his ponderous tail.
Their fixed jav'lins in his side he wears,And on his back a grove of pikes appears."
--WALLER'S BATTLE OF THE SUMMER ISLANDS.
"By art is created that great Leviathan,called a Commonwealth or State--(in Latin,
Civitas) which is but an artificial man."--OPENING SENTENCE OF HOBBES'S LEVIATHAN.
"Silly Mansoul swallowed it withoutchewing, as if it had been a sprat in the
mouth of a whale."--PILGRIM'S PROGRESS.
"That sea beast Leviathan, which God of allhis works Created hugest that swim the
ocean stream."--PARADISE LOST.
---"There Leviathan, Hugest of livingcreatures, in the deep Stretched like a
promontory sleeps or swims, And seems amoving land; and at his gills Draws in, and
at his breath spouts out a sea."
--IBID.
"The mighty whales which swim in a sea ofwater, and have a sea of oil swimming in
them."--FULLLER'S PROFANE AND HOLY STATE.
"So close behind some promontory lieThe huge Leviathan to attend their prey,
And give no chance, but swallow in the fry,Which through their gaping jaws
mistake the way."--DRYDEN'S ANNUS MIRABILIS.
"While the whale is floating at the sternof the ship, they cut off his head, and tow
it with a boat as near the shore as it willcome; but it will be aground in twelve or
thirteen feet water."
--THOMAS EDGE'S TEN VOYAGES TO SPITZBERGEN,IN PURCHAS.
"In their way they saw many whales sportingin the ocean, and in wantonness fuzzing up
the water through their pipes and vents,which nature has placed on their
shoulders."
--SIR T. HERBERT'S VOYAGES INTO ASIA ANDAFRICA. HARRIS COLL.
"Here they saw such huge troops of whales,that they were forced to proceed with a
great deal of caution for fear they shouldrun their ship upon them."
--SCHOUTEN'S SIXTH CIRCUMNAVIGATION.
"We set sail from the Elbe, wind N.E. inthe ship called The Jonas-in-the-Whale....
Some say the whale can't open his mouth,but that is a fable....
They frequently climb up the masts to seewhether they can see a whale, for the first
discoverer has a ducat for his pains....
I was told of a whale taken near Shetland,that had above a barrel of herrings in his
belly....
One of our harpooneers told me that hecaught once a whale in Spitzbergen that was
white all over."--A VOYAGE TO GREENLAND, A.D. 1671 HARRIS
COLL.
"Several whales have come in upon thiscoast (Fife) Anno 1652, one eighty feet in
length of the whale-bone kind came in,which (as I was informed), besides a vast
quantity of oil, did afford 500 weight ofbaleen.
The jaws of it stand for a gate in thegarden of Pitferren."
--SIBBALD'S FIFE AND KINROSS.
"Myself have agreed to try whether I canmaster and kill this Sperma-ceti whale, for
I could never hear of any of that sort thatwas killed by any man, such is his
fierceness and swiftness."
--RICHARD STRAFFORD'S LETTER FROM THEBERMUDAS. PHIL. TRANS. A.D. 1668.
"Whales in the sea God's voice obey."--N. E. PRIMER.
"We saw also abundance of large whales,there being more in those southern seas, as
I may say, by a hundred to one; than wehave to the northward of us."
--CAPTAIN COWLEY'S VOYAGE ROUND THE GLOBE,A.D. 1729.
"... and the breath of the whale isfrequently attended with such an
insupportable smell, as to bring on adisorder of the brain."
--ULLOA'S SOUTH AMERICA.
"To fifty chosen sylphsof special note,
We trust the important charge,the petticoat.
Oft have we knownthat seven-fold fence to fail,
Tho' stuffed with hoopsand armed with ribs of whale."
--RAPE OF THE LOCK.
"If we compare land animals in respect tomagnitude, with those that take up their
abode in the deep, we shall find they willappear contemptible in the comparison.
The whale is doubtless the largest animalin creation."
--GOLDSMITH, NAT. HIST.
"If you should write a fable for littlefishes, you would make them speak like
great wales."--GOLDSMITH TO JOHNSON.
"In the afternoon we saw what was supposedto be a rock, but it was found to be a dead
whale, which some Asiatics had killed, andwere then towing ashore.
They seemed to endeavor to concealthemselves behind the whale, in order to
avoid being seen by us."--COOK'S VOYAGES.
"The larger whales, they seldom venture toattack.
They stand in so great dread of some ofthem, that when out at sea they are afraid
to mention even their names, and carrydung, lime-stone, juniper-wood, and some
other articles of the same nature in their
boats, in order to terrify and preventtheir too near approach."
--UNO VON TROIL'S LETTERS ON BANKS'S ANDSOLANDER'S VOYAGE TO ICELAND IN 1772.
"The Spermacetti Whale found by theNantuckois, is an active, fierce animal,
and requires vast address and boldness inthe fishermen."
--THOMAS JEFFERSON'S WHALE MEMORIAL TO THEFRENCH MINISTER IN 1778.
"And pray, sir, what in the world is equalto it?"
--EDMUND BURKE'S REFERENCE IN PARLIAMENT TOTHE NANTUCKET WHALE-FISHERY.
"Spain--a great whale stranded on theshores of Europe."
--EDMUND BURKE. (SOMEWHERE.)
"A tenth branch of the king's ordinaryrevenue, said to be grounded on the
consideration of his guarding andprotecting the seas from pirates and
robbers, is the right to royal fish, whichare whale and sturgeon.
And these, when either thrown ashore orcaught near the coast, are the property of
the king."
--BLACKSTONE.
"Soon to the sport of deaththe crews repair:
Rodmond unerring o'er his head suspendsThe barbed steel, and every turn attends."
--FALCONER'S SHIPWRECK.
"Bright shone the roofs,the domes, the spires,
And rockets blew self driven,To hang their momentary fire
Around the vault of heaven.
"So fire with water to compare,The ocean serves on high,
Up-spouted by a whale in air,To express unwieldy joy."
--COWPER, ON THE QUEEN'S VISIT TO LONDON.
"Ten or fifteen gallons of blood are thrownout of the heart at a stroke, with immense
velocity."--JOHN HUNTER'S ACCOUNT OF THE DISSECTION
OF A WHALE. (A SMALL SIZED ONE.)
"The aorta of a whale is larger in the borethan the main pipe of the water-works at
London Bridge, and the water roaring in itspassage through that pipe is inferior in
impetus and velocity to the blood gushingfrom the whale's heart."
--PALEY'S THEOLOGY.
"The whale is a mammiferous animal withouthind feet."
--BARON CUVIER.
"In 40 degrees south, we saw SpermacettiWhales, but did not take any till the first
of May, the sea being then covered withthem."
--COLNETT'S VOYAGE FOR THE PURPOSE OFEXTENDING THE SPERMACETI WHALE FISHERY.
"In the free element beneath me swam,Floundered and dived,
in play, in chace, in battle,Fishes of every colour, form, and kind;
Which language cannot paint, and marinerHad never seen; from dread Leviathan
To insect millions peopling every wave:
Gather'd in shoals immense,like floating islands,
Led by mysterious instinctsthrough that waste
And trackless region, though on every sideAssaulted by voracious enemies,
Whales, sharks, and monsters,arm'd in front or jaw,
With swords, saws, spiral horns,or hooked fangs."
--MONTGOMERY'S WORLD BEFORE THE FLOOD.
"Io! Paean! Io! sing.To the finny people's king.
Not a mightier whale than thisIn the vast Atlantic is;
Not a fatter fish than he,Flounders round the Polar Sea."
--CHARLES LAMB'S TRIUMPH OF THE WHALE.
"In the year 1690 some persons were on ahigh hill observing the whales spouting and
sporting with each other, when oneobserved: there--pointing to the sea--is a
green pasture where our children's grand-children will go for bread."
--OBED MACY'S HISTORY OF NANTUCKET.
"I built a cottage for Susan and myself andmade a gateway in the form of a Gothic
Arch, by setting up a whale's jaw bones."--HAWTHORNE'S TWICE TOLD TALES.
"She came to bespeak a monument for herfirst love, who had been killed by a whale
in the Pacific ocean, no less than fortyyears ago."
--IBID.
"No, Sir, 'tis a Right Whale," answeredTom; "I saw his sprout; he threw up a pair
of as pretty rainbows as a Christian wouldwish to look at.
He's a raal oil-butt, that fellow!"
--COOPER'S PILOT.
"The papers were brought in, and we saw inthe Berlin Gazette that whales had been
introduced on the stage there."--ECKERMANN'S CONVERSATIONS WITH GOETHE.
"My God! Mr. Chace, what is the matter?"I answered, "we have been stove by a
whale."
--"NARRATIVE OF THE SHIPWRECK OF THE WHALESHIP ESSEX OF NANTUCKET, WHICH WAS ATTACKED
AND FINALLY DESTROYED BY A LARGE SPERMWHALE IN THE PACIFIC OCEAN."
BY OWEN CHACE OF NANTUCKET, FIRST MATE OFSAID VESSEL.
NEW YORK, 1821.
"A mariner sat in the shrouds one night,The wind was piping free;
Now bright, now dimmed, was the moonlightpale,
And the phospher gleamed in the wake ofthe whale,
As it floundered in the sea."
--ELIZABETH OAKES SMITH.
"The quantity of line withdrawn from theboats engaged in the capture of this one
whale, amounted altogether to 10,440 yardsor nearly six English miles....
"Sometimes the whale shakes its tremendoustail in the air, which, cracking like a
whip, resounds to the distance of three orfour miles."
--SCORESBY.
"Mad with the agonies he endures from thesefresh attacks, the infuriated Sperm Whale
rolls over and over; he rears his enormoushead, and with wide expanded jaws snaps at
everything around him; he rushes at the
boats with his head; they are propelledbefore him with vast swiftness, and
sometimes utterly destroyed....
It is a matter of great astonishment thatthe consideration of the habits of so
interesting, and, in a commercial point ofview, so important an animal (as the Sperm
Whale) should have been so entirely
neglected, or should have excited so littlecuriosity among the numerous, and many of
them competent observers, that of lateyears, must have possessed the most
abundant and the most convenient
opportunities of witnessing theirhabitudes."
--THOMAS BEALE'S HISTORY OF THE SPERMWHALE, 1839.
"The Cachalot" (Sperm Whale) "is not onlybetter armed than the True Whale"
(Greenland or Right Whale) "in possessing aformidable weapon at either extremity of
its body, but also more frequently displays
a disposition to employ these weaponsoffensively and in manner at once so
artful, bold, and mischievous, as to leadto its being regarded as the most dangerous
to attack of all the known species of thewhale tribe."
--FREDERICK DEBELL BENNETT'S WHALING VOYAGEROUND THE GLOBE, 1840.
October 13."There she blows," was sung out from the
mast-head."Where away?" demanded the captain.
"Three points off the lee bow, sir."
"Raise up your wheel.Steady!"
"Steady, sir.""Mast-head ahoy!
Do you see that whale now?"
"Ay ay, sir!A shoal of Sperm Whales!
There she blows!There she breaches!"
"Sing out! sing out every time!"
"Ay Ay, sir!There she blows! there--there--THAR she
blows--bowes--bo-o-os!""How far off?"
"Two miles and a half."
"Thunder and lightning! so near!Call all hands."
--J. ROSS BROWNE'S ETCHINGS OF A WHALINGCRUIZE. 1846.
"The Whale-ship Globe, on board of whichvessel occurred the horrid transactions we
are about to relate, belonged to the islandof Nantucket."
--"NARRATIVE OF THE GLOBE," BY LAY ANDHUSSEY SURVIVORS. A.D. 1828.
Being once pursued by a whale which he hadwounded, he parried the assault for some
time with a lance; but the furious monsterat length rushed on the boat; himself and
comrades only being preserved by leaping
into the water when they saw the onset wasinevitable."
--MISSIONARY JOURNAL OF TYERMAN ANDBENNETT.
"Nantucket itself," said Mr. Webster, "is avery striking and peculiar portion of the
National interest.
There is a population of eight or ninethousand persons living here in the sea,
adding largely every year to the Nationalwealth by the boldest and most persevering
industry."
--REPORT OF DANIEL WEBSTER'S SPEECH IN THEU. S. SENATE, ON THE APPLICATION FOR THE
ERECTION OF A BREAKWATER AT NANTUCKET.1828.
"The whale fell directly over him, andprobably killed him in a moment."
--"THE WHALE AND HIS CAPTORS, OR THEWHALEMAN'S ADVENTURES AND THE WHALE'S
BIOGRAPHY, GATHERED ON THE HOMEWARD CRUISEOF THE COMMODORE PREBLE." BY REV. HENRY T.
CHEEVER.
"If you make the least damn bit of noise,"replied Samuel, "I will send you to hell."
--LIFE OF SAMUEL COMSTOCK (THE MUTINEER),BY HIS BROTHER, WILLIAM COMSTOCK.
ANOTHER VERSION OF THE WHALE-SHIP GLOBENARRATIVE.
"The voyages of the Dutch and English tothe Northern Ocean, in order, if possible,
to discover a passage through it to India,though they failed of their main object,
laid-open the haunts of the whale."
--MCCULLOCH'S COMMERCIAL DICTIONARY.
"These things are reciprocal; the ballrebounds, only to bound forward again; for
now in laying open the haunts of the whale,the whalemen seem to have indirectly hit
upon new clews to that same mystic North-West Passage."
--FROM "SOMETHING" UNPUBLISHED.
"It is impossible to meet a whale-ship onthe ocean without being struck by her near
appearance.
The vessel under short sail, with look-outsat the mast-heads, eagerly scanning the
wide expanse around them, has a totallydifferent air from those engaged in regular
voyage."
--CURRENTS AND WHALING. U.S. EX. EX.
"Pedestrians in the vicinity of London andelsewhere may recollect having seen large
curved bones set upright in the earth,either to form arches over gateways, or
entrances to alcoves, and they may perhaps
have been told that these were the ribs ofwhales."
--TALES OF A WHALE VOYAGER TO THE ARCTICOCEAN.
"It was not till the boats returned fromthe pursuit of these whales, that the
whites saw their ship in bloody possessionof the savages enrolled among the crew."
--NEWSPAPER ACCOUNT OF THE TAKING ANDRETAKING OF THE WHALE-SHIP HOBOMACK.
"It is generally well known that out of thecrews of Whaling vessels (American) few
ever return in the ships on board of whichthey departed."
--CRUISE IN A WHALE BOAT.
"Suddenly a mighty mass emerged from thewater, and shot up perpendicularly into the
air.It was the while."
--MIRIAM COFFIN OR THE WHALE FISHERMAN.
"The Whale is harpooned to be sure; butbethink you, how you would manage a
powerful unbroken colt, with the mereappliance of a rope tied to the root of his
tail."
--A CHAPTER ON WHALING IN RIBS AND TRUCKS.
"On one occasion I saw two of thesemonsters (whales) probably male and female,
slowly swimming, one after the other,within less than a stone's throw of the
shore" (Terra Del Fuego), "over which thebeech tree extended its branches."
--DARWIN'S VOYAGE OF A NATURALIST.
"'Stern all!' exclaimed the mate, as uponturning his head, he saw the distended jaws
of a large Sperm Whale close to the head ofthe boat, threatening it with instant
destruction;--'Stern all, for your lives!'"
--WHARTON THE WHALE KILLER.
"So be cheery, my lads, let your heartsnever fail, While the bold harpooneer is
striking the whale!"--NANTUCKET SONG.
"Oh, the rare old Whale, mid storm and galeIn his ocean home will be
A giant in might, where might is right,And King of the boundless sea."
--WHALE SONG.
>
-Chapter 1.Loomings.
Call me Ishmael.
Some years ago--never mind how longprecisely--having little or no money in my
purse, and nothing particular to interestme on shore, I thought I would sail about a
little and see the watery part of theworld.
It is a way I have of driving off thespleen and regulating the circulation.
Whenever I find myself growing grim aboutthe mouth; whenever it is a damp, drizzly
November in my soul; whenever I find myselfinvoluntarily pausing before coffin
warehouses, and bringing up the rear of
every funeral I meet; and especiallywhenever my hypos get such an upper hand of
me, that it requires a strong moralprinciple to prevent me from deliberately
stepping into the street, and methodically
knocking people's hats off--then, I accountit high time to get to sea as soon as I
can.This is my substitute for pistol and ball.
With a philosophical flourish Cato throwshimself upon his sword; I quietly take to
the ship.There is nothing surprising in this.
If they but knew it, almost all men intheir degree, some time or other, cherish
very nearly the same feelings towards theocean with me.
There now is your insular city of theManhattoes, belted round by wharves as
Indian isles by coral reefs--commercesurrounds it with her surf.
Right and left, the streets take youwaterward.
Its extreme downtown is the battery, wherethat noble mole is washed by waves, and
cooled by breezes, which a few hoursprevious were out of sight of land.
Look at the crowds of water-gazers there.
Circumambulate the city of a dreamy Sabbathafternoon.
Go from Corlears Hook to Coenties Slip, andfrom thence, by Whitehall, northward.
What do you see?--Posted like silentsentinels all around the town, stand
thousands upon thousands of mortal menfixed in ocean reveries.
Some leaning against the spiles; someseated upon the pier-heads; some looking
over the bulwarks of ships from China; somehigh aloft in the rigging, as if striving
to get a still better seaward peep.
But these are all landsmen; of week dayspent up in lath and plaster--tied to
counters, nailed to benches, clinched todesks.
How then is this?
Are the green fields gone?What do they here?
But look! here come more crowds, pacingstraight for the water, and seemingly bound
for a dive.
Strange!Nothing will content them but the extremest
limit of the land; loitering under theshady lee of yonder warehouses will not
suffice.
No. They must get just as nigh the water asthey possibly can without falling in.
And there they stand--miles of them--leagues.
Inlanders all, they come from lanes andalleys, streets and avenues--north, east,
south, and west.Yet here they all unite.
Tell me, does the magnetic virtue of theneedles of the compasses of all those ships
attract them thither?Once more.
Say you are in the country; in some highland of lakes.
Take almost any path you please, and ten toone it carries you down in a dale, and
leaves you there by a pool in the stream.
There is magic in it.
Let the most absent-minded of men beplunged in his deepest reveries--stand that
man on his legs, set his feet a-going, andhe will infallibly lead you to water, if
water there be in all that region.
Should you ever be athirst in the greatAmerican desert, try this experiment, if
your caravan happen to be supplied with ametaphysical professor.
Yes, as every one knows, meditation andwater are wedded for ever.
But here is an artist.
He desires to paint you the dreamiest,shadiest, quietest, most enchanting bit of
romantic landscape in all the valley of theSaco.
What is the chief element he employs?
There stand his trees, each with a hollowtrunk, as if a hermit and a crucifix were
within; and here sleeps his meadow, andthere sleep his cattle; and up from yonder
cottage goes a sleepy smoke.
Deep into distant woodlands winds a mazyway, reaching to overlapping spurs of
mountains bathed in their hill-side blue.
But though the picture lies thus tranced,and though this pine-tree shakes down its
sighs like leaves upon this shepherd'shead, yet all were vain, unless the
shepherd's eye were fixed upon the magicstream before him.
Go visit the Prairies in June, when forscores on scores of miles you wade knee-
deep among Tiger-lilies--what is the onecharm wanting?--Water--there is not a drop
of water there!
Were Niagara but a cataract of sand, wouldyou travel your thousand miles to see it?
Why did the poor poet of Tennessee, uponsuddenly receiving two handfuls of silver,
deliberate whether to buy him a coat, whichhe sadly needed, or invest his money in a
pedestrian trip to Rockaway Beach?
Why is almost every robust healthy boy witha robust healthy soul in him, at some time
or other crazy to go to sea?
Why upon your first voyage as a passenger,did you yourself feel such a mystical
vibration, when first told that you andyour ship were now out of sight of land?
Why did the old Persians hold the sea holy?
Why did the Greeks give it a separatedeity, and own brother of Jove?
Surely all this is not without meaning.
And still deeper the meaning of that storyof Narcissus, who because he could not
grasp the tormenting, mild image he saw inthe fountain, plunged into it and was
drowned.
But that same image, we ourselves see inall rivers and oceans.
It is the image of the ungraspable phantomof life; and this is the key to it all.
Now, when I say that I am in the habit ofgoing to sea whenever I begin to grow hazy
about the eyes, and begin to be overconscious of my lungs, I do not mean to
have it inferred that I ever go to sea as apassenger.
For to go as a passenger you must needshave a purse, and a purse is but a rag
unless you have something in it.
Besides, passengers get sea-sick--growquarrelsome--don't sleep of nights--do not
enjoy themselves much, as a general thing;--no, I never go as a passenger; nor, though
I am something of a salt, do I ever go to
sea as a Commodore, or a Captain, or aCook.
I abandon the glory and distinction of suchoffices to those who like them.
For my part, I abominate all honourablerespectable toils, trials, and tribulations
of every kind whatsoever.
It is quite as much as I can do to takecare of myself, without taking care of
ships, barques, brigs, schooners, and whatnot.
And as for going as cook,--though I confessthere is considerable glory in that, a cook
being a sort of officer on ship-board--yet,somehow, I never fancied broiling fowls;--
though once broiled, judiciously buttered,
and judgmatically salted and peppered,there is no one who will speak more
respectfully, not to say reverentially, ofa broiled fowl than I will.
It is out of the idolatrous dotings of theold Egyptians upon broiled ibis and roasted
river horse, that you see the mummies ofthose creatures in their huge bake-houses
the pyramids.
No, when I go to sea, I go as a simplesailor, right before the mast, plumb down
into the forecastle, aloft there to theroyal mast-head.
True, they rather order me about some, andmake me jump from spar to spar, like a
grasshopper in a May meadow.And at first, this sort of thing is
unpleasant enough.
It touches one's sense of honour,particularly if you come of an old
established family in the land, the VanRensselaers, or Randolphs, or Hardicanutes.
And more than all, if just previous toputting your hand into the tar-pot, you
have been lording it as a countryschoolmaster, making the tallest boys stand
in awe of you.
The transition is a keen one, I assure you,from a schoolmaster to a sailor, and
requires a strong decoction of Seneca andthe Stoics to enable you to grin and bear
it.
But even this wears off in time.What of it, if some old hunks of a sea-
captain orders me to get a broom and sweepdown the decks?
What does that indignity amount to,weighed, I mean, in the scales of the New
Testament?
Do you think the archangel Gabriel thinksanything the less of me, because I promptly
and respectfully obey that old hunks inthat particular instance?
Who ain't a slave?
Tell me that.
Well, then, however the old sea-captainsmay order me about--however they may thump
and punch me about, I have the satisfactionof knowing that it is all right; that
everybody else is one way or other served
in much the same way--either in a physicalor metaphysical point of view, that is; and
so the universal thump is passed round, andall hands should rub each other's shoulder-
blades, and be content.
Again, I always go to sea as a sailor,because they make a point of paying me for
my trouble, whereas they never paypassengers a single penny that I ever heard
of.
On the contrary, passengers themselves mustpay.
And there is all the difference in theworld between paying and being paid.
The act of paying is perhaps the mostuncomfortable infliction that the two
orchard thieves entailed upon us.But BEING PAID,--what will compare with it?
The urbane activity with which a manreceives money is really marvellous,
considering that we so earnestly believemoney to be the root of all earthly ills,
and that on no account can a monied manenter heaven.
Ah! how cheerfully we consign ourselves toperdition!
Finally, I always go to sea as a sailor,because of the wholesome exercise and pure
air of the fore-castle deck.
For as in this world, head winds are farmore prevalent than winds from astern (that
is, if you never violate the Pythagoreanmaxim), so for the most part the Commodore
on the quarter-deck gets his atmosphere at
second hand from the sailors on theforecastle.
He thinks he breathes it first; but not so.
In much the same way do the commonalty leadtheir leaders in many other things, at the
same time that the leaders little suspectit.
But wherefore it was that after havingrepeatedly smelt the sea as a merchant
sailor, I should now take it into my headto go on a whaling voyage; this the
invisible police officer of the Fates, who
has the constant surveillance of me, andsecretly dogs me, and influences me in some
unaccountable way--he can better answerthan any one else.
And, doubtless, my going on this whalingvoyage, formed part of the grand programme
of Providence that was drawn up a long timeago.
It came in as a sort of brief interlude andsolo between more extensive performances.
I take it that this part of the bill musthave run something like this:
"GRAND CONTESTED ELECTION FOR THEPRESIDENCY OF THE UNITED STATES.
"WHALING VOYAGE BY ONE ISHMAEL."BLOODY BATTLE IN AFFGHANISTAN."
Though I cannot tell why it was exactlythat those stage managers, the Fates, put
me down for this shabby part of a whalingvoyage, when others were set down for
magnificent parts in high tragedies, and
short and easy parts in genteel comedies,and jolly parts in farces--though I cannot
tell why this was exactly; yet, now that Irecall all the circumstances, I think I can
see a little into the springs and motives
which being cunningly presented to me undervarious disguises, induced me to set about
performing the part I did, besides cajolingme into the delusion that it was a choice
resulting from my own unbiased freewill anddiscriminating judgment.
Chief among these motives was theoverwhelming idea of the great whale
himself.
Such a portentous and mysterious monsterroused all my curiosity.
Then the wild and distant seas where herolled his island bulk; the undeliverable,
nameless perils of the whale; these, withall the attending marvels of a thousand
Patagonian sights and sounds, helped tosway me to my wish.
With other men, perhaps, such things wouldnot have been inducements; but as for me,
I am tormented with an everlasting itch forthings remote.
I love to sail forbidden seas, and land onbarbarous coasts.
Not ignoring what is good, I am quick toperceive a horror, and could still be
social with it--would they let me--since itis but well to be on friendly terms with
all the inmates of the place one lodges in.
By reason of these things, then, thewhaling voyage was welcome; the great
flood-gates of the wonder-world swung open,and in the wild conceits that swayed me to
my purpose, two and two there floated into
my inmost soul, endless processions of thewhale, and, mid most of them all, one grand
hooded phantom, like a snow hill in theair.
Chapter 2.The Carpet-Bag.
I stuffed a shirt or two into my oldcarpet-bag, tucked it under my arm, and
started for Cape Horn and the Pacific.Quitting the good city of old Manhatto, I
duly arrived in New Bedford.
It was a Saturday night in December.
Much was I disappointed upon learning thatthe little packet for Nantucket had already
sailed, and that no way of reaching thatplace would offer, till the following
Monday.
As most young candidates for the pains andpenalties of whaling stop at this same New
Bedford, thence to embark on their voyage,it may as well be related that I, for one,
had no idea of so doing.
For my mind was made up to sail in no otherthan a Nantucket craft, because there was a
fine, boisterous something about everythingconnected with that famous old island,
which amazingly pleased me.
Besides though New Bedford has of late beengradually monopolising the business of
whaling, and though in this matter poor oldNantucket is now much behind her, yet
Nantucket was her great original--the Tyre
of this Carthage;--the place where thefirst dead American whale was stranded.
Where else but from Nantucket did thoseaboriginal whalemen, the Red-Men, first
sally out in canoes to give chase to theLeviathan?
And where but from Nantucket, too, did thatfirst adventurous little sloop put forth,
partly laden with imported cobblestones--sogoes the story--to throw at the whales, in
order to discover when they were nighenough to risk a harpoon from the bowsprit?
Now having a night, a day, and stillanother night following before me in New
Bedford, ere I could embark for my destinedport, it became a matter of concernment
where I was to eat and sleep meanwhile.
It was a very dubious-looking, nay, a verydark and dismal night, bitingly cold and
cheerless.I knew no one in the place.
With anxious grapnels I had sounded mypocket, and only brought up a few pieces of
silver,--So, wherever you go, Ishmael, saidI to myself, as I stood in the middle of a
dreary street shouldering my bag, and
comparing the gloom towards the north withthe darkness towards the south--wherever in
your wisdom you may conclude to lodge forthe night, my dear Ishmael, be sure to
inquire the price, and don't be tooparticular.
With halting steps I paced the streets, andpassed the sign of "The Crossed Harpoons"--
but it looked too expensive and jollythere.
Further on, from the bright red windows ofthe "Sword-Fish Inn," there came such
fervent rays, that it seemed to have meltedthe packed snow and ice from before the
house, for everywhere else the congealed
frost lay ten inches thick in a hard,asphaltic pavement,--rather weary for me,
when I struck my foot against the flintyprojections, because from hard, remorseless
service the soles of my boots were in amost miserable plight.
Too expensive and jolly, again thought I,pausing one moment to watch the broad glare
in the street, and hear the sounds of thetinkling glasses within.
But go on, Ishmael, said I at last; don'tyou hear? get away from before the door;
your patched boots are stopping the way.So on I went.
I now by instinct followed the streets thattook me waterward, for there, doubtless,
were the cheapest, if not the cheeriestinns.
Such dreary streets! blocks of blackness,not houses, on either hand, and here and
there a candle, like a candle moving aboutin a tomb.
At this hour of the night, of the last dayof the week, that quarter of the town
proved all but deserted.
But presently I came to a smoky lightproceeding from a low, wide building, the
door of which stood invitingly open.
It had a careless look, as if it were meantfor the uses of the public; so, entering,
the first thing I did was to stumble overan ash-box in the porch.
Ha! thought I, ha, as the flying particlesalmost choked me, are these ashes from that
destroyed city, Gomorrah?
But "The Crossed Harpoons," and "The Sword-Fish?"--this, then must needs be the sign
of "The Trap."
However, I picked myself up and hearing aloud voice within, pushed on and opened a
second, interior door.It seemed the great Black Parliament
sitting in Tophet.
A hundred black faces turned round in theirrows to peer; and beyond, a black Angel of
Doom was beating a book in a pulpit.
It was a negro church; and the preacher'stext was about the blackness of darkness,
and the weeping and wailing and teeth-gnashing there.
Ha, Ishmael, muttered I, backing out,Wretched entertainment at the sign of 'The
Trap!'
Moving on, I at last came to a dim sort oflight not far from the docks, and heard a
forlorn creaking in the air; and lookingup, saw a swinging sign over the door with
a white painting upon it, faintly
representing a tall straight jet of mistyspray, and these words underneath--"The
Spouter Inn:--Peter Coffin."Coffin?--Spouter?--Rather ominous in that
particular connexion, thought I.
But it is a common name in Nantucket, theysay, and I suppose this Peter here is an
emigrant from there.
As the light looked so dim, and the place,for the time, looked quiet enough, and the
dilapidated little wooden house itselflooked as if it might have been carted here
from the ruins of some burnt district, and
as the swinging sign had a poverty-strickensort of creak to it, I thought that here
was the very spot for cheap lodgings, andthe best of pea coffee.
It was a queer sort of place--a gable-endedold house, one side palsied as it were, and
leaning over sadly.
It stood on a sharp bleak corner, wherethat tempestuous wind Euroclydon kept up a
worse howling than ever it did about poorPaul's tossed craft.
Euroclydon, nevertheless, is a mightypleasant zephyr to any one in-doors, with
his feet on the hob quietly toasting forbed.
"In judging of that tempestuous wind calledEuroclydon," says an old writer--of whose
works I possess the only copy extant--"itmaketh a marvellous difference, whether
thou lookest out at it from a glass window
where the frost is all on the outside, orwhether thou observest it from that
sashless window, where the frost is on bothsides, and of which the wight Death is the
only glazier."
True enough, thought I, as this passageoccurred to my mind--old black-letter, thou
reasonest well.Yes, these eyes are windows, and this body
of mine is the house.
What a pity they didn't stop up the chinksand the crannies though, and thrust in a
little lint here and there.But it's too late to make any improvements
now.
The universe is finished; the copestone ison, and the chips were carted off a million
years ago.
Poor Lazarus there, chattering his teethagainst the curbstone for his pillow, and
shaking off his tatters with hisshiverings, he might plug up both ears with
rags, and put a corn-cob into his mouth,
and yet that would not keep out thetempestuous Euroclydon.
Euroclydon! says old Dives, in his redsilken wrapper--(he had a redder one
afterwards) pooh, pooh!
What a fine frosty night; how Orionglitters; what northern lights!
Let them talk of their oriental summerclimes of everlasting conservatories; give
me the privilege of making my own summerwith my own coals.
But what thinks Lazarus?
Can he warm his blue hands by holding themup to the grand northern lights?
Would not Lazarus rather be in Sumatra thanhere?
Would he not far rather lay him downlengthwise along the line of the equator;
yea, ye gods! go down to the fiery pititself, in order to keep out this frost?
Now, that Lazarus should lie stranded thereon the curbstone before the door of Dives,
this is more wonderful than that an icebergshould be moored to one of the Moluccas.
Yet Dives himself, he too lives like a Czarin an ice palace made of frozen sighs, and
being a president of a temperance society,he only drinks the tepid tears of orphans.
But no more of this blubbering now, we aregoing a-whaling, and there is plenty of
that yet to come.
Let us scrape the ice from our frostedfeet, and see what sort of a place this
"Spouter" may be.
>
-Chapter 3.The Spouter-Inn.
Entering that gable-ended Spouter-Inn, youfound yourself in a wide, low, straggling
entry with old-fashioned wainscots,reminding one of the bulwarks of some
condemned old craft.
On one side hung a very large oilpaintingso thoroughly besmoked, and every way
defaced, that in the unequal crosslights bywhich you viewed it, it was only by
diligent study and a series of systematic
visits to it, and careful inquiry of theneighbors, that you could any way arrive at
an understanding of its purpose.
Such unaccountable masses of shades andshadows, that at first you almost thought
some ambitious young artist, in the time ofthe New England hags, had endeavored to
delineate chaos bewitched.
But by dint of much and earnestcontemplation, and oft repeated ponderings,
and especially by throwing open the littlewindow towards the back of the entry, you
at last come to the conclusion that such an
idea, however wild, might not be altogetherunwarranted.
But what most puzzled and confounded youwas a long, limber, portentous, black mass
of something hovering in the centre of thepicture over three blue, dim, perpendicular
lines floating in a nameless yeast.
A boggy, soggy, squitchy picture truly,enough to drive a nervous man distracted.
Yet was there a sort of indefinite, half-attained, unimaginable sublimity about it
that fairly froze you to it, till youinvoluntarily took an oath with yourself to
find out what that marvellous paintingmeant.
Ever and anon a bright, but, alas,deceptive idea would dart you through.--
It's the Black Sea in a midnight gale.--It's the unnatural combat of the four
primal elements.--It's a blasted heath.--
It's a Hyperborean winter scene.--It's thebreaking-up of the icebound stream of Time.
But at last all these fancies yielded tothat one portentous something in the
picture's midst.
THAT once found out, and all the rest wereplain.
But stop; does it not bear a faintresemblance to a gigantic fish? even the
great leviathan himself?
In fact, the artist's design seemed this: afinal theory of my own, partly based upon
the aggregated opinions of many agedpersons with whom I conversed upon the
subject.
The picture represents a Cape-Horner in agreat hurricane; the half-foundered ship
weltering there with its three dismantledmasts alone visible; and an exasperated
whale, purposing to spring clean over the
craft, is in the enormous act of impalinghimself upon the three mast-heads.
The opposite wall of this entry was hungall over with a heathenish array of
monstrous clubs and spears.
Some were thickly set with glittering teethresembling ivory saws; others were tufted
with knots of human hair; and one wassickle-shaped, with a vast handle sweeping
round like the segment made in the new-mowngrass by a long-armed mower.
You shuddered as you gazed, and wonderedwhat monstrous cannibal and savage could
ever have gone a death-harvesting with sucha hacking, horrifying implement.
Mixed with these were rusty old whalinglances and harpoons all broken and
deformed.Some were storied weapons.
With this once long lance, now wildlyelbowed, fifty years ago did Nathan Swain
kill fifteen whales between a sunrise and asunset.
And that harpoon--so like a corkscrew now--was flung in Javan seas, and run away with
by a whale, years afterwards slain off theCape of Blanco.
The original iron entered nigh the tail,and, like a restless needle sojourning in
the body of a man, travelled full fortyfeet, and at last was found imbedded in the
hump.
Crossing this dusky entry, and on throughyon low-arched way--cut through what in old
times must have been a great centralchimney with fireplaces all round--you
enter the public room.
A still duskier place is this, with suchlow ponderous beams above, and such old
wrinkled planks beneath, that you wouldalmost fancy you trod some old craft's
cockpits, especially of such a howling
night, when this corner-anchored old arkrocked so furiously.
On one side stood a long, low, shelf-liketable covered with cracked glass cases,
filled with dusty rarities gathered fromthis wide world's remotest nooks.
Projecting from the further angle of theroom stands a dark-looking den--the bar--a
rude attempt at a right whale's head.
Be that how it may, there stands the vastarched bone of the whale's jaw, so wide, a
coach might almost drive beneath it.
Within are shabby shelves, ranged roundwith old decanters, bottles, flasks; and in
those jaws of swift destruction, likeanother cursed Jonah (by which name indeed
they called him), bustles a little withered
old man, who, for their money, dearly sellsthe sailors deliriums and death.
Abominable are the tumblers into which hepours his poison.
Though true cylinders without--within, thevillanous green goggling glasses
deceitfully tapered downwards to a cheatingbottom.
Parallel meridians rudely pecked into theglass, surround these footpads' goblets.
Fill to THIS mark, and your charge is but apenny; to THIS a penny more; and so on to
the full glass--the Cape Horn measure,which you may gulp down for a shilling.
Upon entering the place I found a number ofyoung seamen gathered about a table,
examining by a dim light divers specimensof SKRIMSHANDER.
I sought the landlord, and telling him Idesired to be accommodated with a room,
received for answer that his house wasfull--not a bed unoccupied.
"But avast," he added, tapping hisforehead, "you haint no objections to
sharing a harpooneer's blanket, have ye?I s'pose you are goin' a-whalin', so you'd
better get used to that sort of thing."
I told him that I never liked to sleep twoin a bed; that if I should ever do so, it
would depend upon who the harpooneer mightbe, and that if he (the landlord) really
had no other place for me, and the
harpooneer was not decidedly objectionable,why rather than wander further about a
strange town on so bitter a night, I wouldput up with the half of any decent man's
blanket.
"I thought so.All right; take a seat.
Supper?--you want supper?Supper'll be ready directly."
I sat down on an old wooden settle, carvedall over like a bench on the Battery.
At one end a ruminating tar was stillfurther adorning it with his jack-knife,
stooping over and diligently working awayat the space between his legs.
He was trying his hand at a ship under fullsail, but he didn't make much headway, I
thought.At last some four or five of us were
summoned to our meal in an adjoining room.
It was cold as Iceland--no fire at all--thelandlord said he couldn't afford it.
Nothing but two dismal tallow candles, eachin a winding sheet.
We were fain to button up our monkeyjackets, and hold to our lips cups of
scalding tea with our half frozen fingers.
But the fare was of the most substantialkind--not only meat and potatoes, but
dumplings; good heavens! dumplings forsupper!
One young fellow in a green box coat,addressed himself to these dumplings in a
most direful manner."My boy," said the landlord, "you'll have
the nightmare to a dead sartainty."
"Landlord," I whispered, "that aint theharpooneer is it?"
"Oh, no," said he, looking a sort ofdiabolically funny, "the harpooneer is a
dark complexioned chap.
He never eats dumplings, he don't--he eatsnothing but steaks, and he likes 'em rare."
"The devil he does," says I."Where is that harpooneer?
Is he here?"
"He'll be here afore long," was the answer.I could not help it, but I began to feel
suspicious of this "dark complexioned"harpooneer.
At any rate, I made up my mind that if itso turned out that we should sleep
together, he must undress and get into bedbefore I did.
Supper over, the company went back to thebar-room, when, knowing not what else to do
with myself, I resolved to spend the restof the evening as a looker on.
Presently a rioting noise was heardwithout.
Starting up, the landlord cried, "That'sthe Grampus's crew.
I seed her reported in the offing thismorning; a three years' voyage, and a full
ship.Hurrah, boys; now we'll have the latest
news from the Feegees."
A tramping of sea boots was heard in theentry; the door was flung open, and in
rolled a wild set of mariners enough.
Enveloped in their shaggy watch coats, andwith their heads muffled in woollen
comforters, all bedarned and ragged, andtheir beards stiff with icicles, they
seemed an eruption of bears from Labrador.
They had just landed from their boat, andthis was the first house they entered.
No wonder, then, that they made a straightwake for the whale's mouth--the bar--when
the wrinkled little old Jonah, thereofficiating, soon poured them out brimmers
all round.
One complained of a bad cold in his head,upon which Jonah mixed him a pitch-like
potion of gin and molasses, which he sworewas a sovereign cure for all colds and
catarrhs whatsoever, never mind of how long
standing, or whether caught off the coastof Labrador, or on the weather side of an
ice-island.
The liquor soon mounted into their heads,as it generally does even with the
arrantest topers newly landed from sea, andthey began capering about most
obstreperously.
I observed, however, that one of them heldsomewhat aloof, and though he seemed
desirous not to spoil the hilarity of hisshipmates by his own sober face, yet upon
the whole he refrained from making as muchnoise as the rest.
This man interested me at once; and sincethe sea-gods had ordained that he should
soon become my shipmate (though but asleeping-partner one, so far as this
narrative is concerned), I will hereventure upon a little description of him.
He stood full six feet in height, withnoble shoulders, and a chest like a coffer-
dam.
I have seldom seen such brawn in a man.
His face was deeply brown and burnt, makinghis white teeth dazzling by the contrast;
while in the deep shadows of his eyesfloated some reminiscences that did not
seem to give him much joy.
His voice at once announced that he was aSoutherner, and from his fine stature, I
thought he must be one of those tallmountaineers from the Alleghanian Ridge in
Virginia.
When the revelry of his companions hadmounted to its height, this man slipped
away unobserved, and I saw no more of himtill he became my comrade on the sea.
In a few minutes, however, he was missed byhis shipmates, and being, it seems, for
some reason a huge favourite with them,they raised a cry of "Bulkington!
Bulkington! where's Bulkington?" and dartedout of the house in pursuit of him.
It was now about nine o'clock, and the roomseeming almost supernaturally quiet after
these orgies, I began to congratulatemyself upon a little plan that had occurred
to me just previous to the entrance of theseamen.
No man prefers to sleep two in a bed.In fact, you would a good deal rather not
sleep with your own brother.
I don't know how it is, but people like tobe private when they are sleeping.
And when it comes to sleeping with anunknown stranger, in a strange inn, in a
strange town, and that stranger aharpooneer, then your objections
indefinitely multiply.
Nor was there any earthly reason why I as asailor should sleep two in a bed, more than
anybody else; for sailors no more sleep twoin a bed at sea, than bachelor Kings do
ashore.
To be sure they all sleep together in oneapartment, but you have your own hammock,
and cover yourself with your own blanket,and sleep in your own skin.
The more I pondered over this harpooneer,the more I abominated the thought of
sleeping with him.
It was fair to presume that being aharpooneer, his linen or woollen, as the
case might be, would not be of the tidiest,certainly none of the finest.
I began to twitch all over.
Besides, it was getting late, and my decentharpooneer ought to be home and going
bedwards.
Suppose now, he should tumble in upon me atmidnight--how could I tell from what vile
hole he had been coming?"Landlord!
I've changed my mind about thatharpooneer.--I shan't sleep with him.
I'll try the bench here."
"Just as you please; I'm sorry I cant spareye a tablecloth for a mattress, and it's a
plaguy rough board here"--feeling of theknots and notches.
"But wait a bit, Skrimshander; I've got acarpenter's plane there in the bar--wait,
I say, and I'll make ye snug enough."
So saying he procured the plane; and withhis old silk handkerchief first dusting the
bench, vigorously set to planing away at mybed, the while grinning like an ape.
The shavings flew right and left; till atlast the plane-iron came bump against an
indestructible knot.
The landlord was near spraining his wrist,and I told him for heaven's sake to quit--
the bed was soft enough to suit me, and Idid not know how all the planing in the
world could make eider down of a pineplank.
So gathering up the shavings with anothergrin, and throwing them into the great
stove in the middle of the room, he wentabout his business, and left me in a brown
study.
I now took the measure of the bench, andfound that it was a foot too short; but
that could be mended with a chair.
But it was a foot too narrow, and the otherbench in the room was about four inches
higher than the planed one--so there was noyoking them.
I then placed the first bench lengthwisealong the only clear space against the
wall, leaving a little interval between,for my back to settle down in.
But I soon found that there came such adraught of cold air over me from under the
sill of the window, that this plan wouldnever do at all, especially as another
current from the rickety door met the one
from the window, and both together formed aseries of small whirlwinds in the immediate
vicinity of the spot where I had thought tospend the night.
The devil fetch that harpooneer, thought I,but stop, couldn't I steal a march on him--
bolt his door inside, and jump into hisbed, not to be wakened by the most violent
knockings?
It seemed no bad idea; but upon secondthoughts I dismissed it.
For who could tell but what the nextmorning, so soon as I popped out of the
room, the harpooneer might be standing inthe entry, all ready to knock me down!
Still, looking round me again, and seeingno possible chance of spending a sufferable
night unless in some other person's bed, Ibegan to think that after all I might be
cherishing unwarrantable prejudices againstthis unknown harpooneer.
Thinks I, I'll wait awhile; he must bedropping in before long.
I'll have a good look at him then, andperhaps we may become jolly good bedfellows
after all--there's no telling.
But though the other boarders kept comingin by ones, twos, and threes, and going to
bed, yet no sign of my harpooneer."Landlord!" said I, "what sort of a chap is
he--does he always keep such late hours?"
It was now hard upon twelve o'clock.The landlord chuckled again with his lean
chuckle, and seemed to be mightily tickledat something beyond my comprehension.
"No," he answered, "generally he's an earlybird--airley to bed and airley to rise--
yes, he's the bird what catches the worm.
But to-night he went out a peddling, yousee, and I don't see what on airth keeps
him so late, unless, may be, he can't sellhis head."
"Can't sell his head?--What sort of abamboozingly story is this you are telling
me?" getting into a towering rage.
"Do you pretend to say, landlord, that thisharpooneer is actually engaged this blessed
Saturday night, or rather Sunday morning,in peddling his head around this town?"
"That's precisely it," said the landlord,"and I told him he couldn't sell it here,
the market's overstocked.""With what?" shouted I.
"With heads to be sure; ain't there toomany heads in the world?"
"I tell you what it is, landlord," said Iquite calmly, "you'd better stop spinning
that yarn to me--I'm not green."
"May be not," taking out a stick andwhittling a toothpick, "but I rayther guess
you'll be done BROWN if that ere harpooneerhears you a slanderin' his head."
"I'll break it for him," said I, now flyinginto a passion again at this unaccountable
farrago of the landlord's."It's broke a'ready," said he.
"Broke," said I--"BROKE, do you mean?"
"Sartain, and that's the very reason hecan't sell it, I guess."
"Landlord," said I, going up to him as coolas Mt. Hecla in a snow-storm--"landlord,
stop whittling.
You and I must understand one another, andthat too without delay.
I come to your house and want a bed; youtell me you can only give me half a one;
that the other half belongs to a certainharpooneer.
And about this harpooneer, whom I have notyet seen, you persist in telling me the
most mystifying and exasperating storiestending to beget in me an uncomfortable
feeling towards the man whom you design for
my bedfellow--a sort of connexion,landlord, which is an intimate and
confidential one in the highest degree.
I now demand of you to speak out and tellme who and what this harpooneer is, and
whether I shall be in all respects safe tospend the night with him.
And in the first place, you will be so goodas to unsay that story about selling his
head, which if true I take to be goodevidence that this harpooneer is stark mad,
and I've no idea of sleeping with a madman;
and you, sir, YOU I mean, landlord, YOU,sir, by trying to induce me to do so
knowingly, would thereby render yourselfliable to a criminal prosecution."
"Wall," said the landlord, fetching a longbreath, "that's a purty long sarmon for a
chap that rips a little now and then.
But be easy, be easy, this here harpooneerI have been tellin' you of has just arrived
from the south seas, where he bought up alot of 'balmed New Zealand heads (great
curios, you know), and he's sold all on 'em
but one, and that one he's trying to sellto-night, cause to-morrow's Sunday, and it
would not do to be sellin' human headsabout the streets when folks is goin' to
churches.
He wanted to, last Sunday, but I stoppedhim just as he was goin' out of the door
with four heads strung on a string, for allthe airth like a string of inions."
This account cleared up the otherwiseunaccountable mystery, and showed that the
landlord, after all, had had no idea offooling me--but at the same time what could
I think of a harpooneer who stayed out of a
Saturday night clean into the holy Sabbath,engaged in such a cannibal business as
selling the heads of dead idolators?"Depend upon it, landlord, that harpooneer
is a dangerous man."
"He pays reg'lar," was the rejoinder."But come, it's getting dreadful late, you
had better be turning flukes--it's a nicebed; Sal and me slept in that ere bed the
night we were spliced.
There's plenty of room for two to kickabout in that bed; it's an almighty big bed
that.
Why, afore we give it up, Sal used to putour Sam and little Johnny in the foot of
it.
But I got a dreaming and sprawling aboutone night, and somehow, Sam got pitched on
the floor, and came near breaking his arm.Arter that, Sal said it wouldn't do.
Come along here, I'll give ye a glim in ajiffy;" and so saying he lighted a candle
and held it towards me, offering to leadthe way.
But I stood irresolute; when looking at aclock in the corner, he exclaimed "I vum
it's Sunday--you won't see that harpooneerto-night; he's come to anchor somewhere--
come along then; DO come; WON'T ye come?"
I considered the matter a moment, and thenup stairs we went, and I was ushered into a
small room, cold as a clam, and furnished,sure enough, with a prodigious bed, almost
big enough indeed for any four harpooneersto sleep abreast.
"There," said the landlord, placing thecandle on a crazy old sea chest that did
double duty as a wash-stand and centretable; "there, make yourself comfortable
now, and good night to ye."
I turned round from eyeing the bed, but hehad disappeared.
Folding back the counterpane, I stoopedover the bed.
Though none of the most elegant, it yetstood the scrutiny tolerably well.
I then glanced round the room; and besidesthe bedstead and centre table, could see no
other furniture belonging to the place, buta rude shelf, the four walls, and a papered
fireboard representing a man striking awhale.
Of things not properly belonging to theroom, there was a hammock lashed up, and
thrown upon the floor in one corner; also alarge seaman's bag, containing the
harpooneer's wardrobe, no doubt in lieu ofa land trunk.
Likewise, there was a parcel of outlandishbone fish hooks on the shelf over the fire-
place, and a tall harpoon standing at thehead of the bed.
But what is this on the chest?
I took it up, and held it close to thelight, and felt it, and smelt it, and tried
every way possible to arrive at somesatisfactory conclusion concerning it.
I can compare it to nothing but a largedoor mat, ornamented at the edges with
little tinkling tags something like thestained porcupine quills round an Indian
moccasin.
There was a hole or slit in the middle ofthis mat, as you see the same in South
American ponchos.
But could it be possible that any soberharpooneer would get into a door mat, and
parade the streets of any Christian town inthat sort of guise?
I put it on, to try it, and it weighed medown like a hamper, being uncommonly shaggy
and thick, and I thought a little damp, asthough this mysterious harpooneer had been
wearing it of a rainy day.
I went up in it to a bit of glass stuckagainst the wall, and I never saw such a
sight in my life.I tore myself out of it in such a hurry
that I gave myself a kink in the neck.
I sat down on the side of the bed, andcommenced thinking about this head-peddling
harpooneer, and his door mat.
After thinking some time on the bed-side,I got up and took off my monkey jacket, and
then stood in the middle of the roomthinking.
I then took off my coat, and thought alittle more in my shirt sleeves.
But beginning to feel very cold now, halfundressed as I was, and remembering what
the landlord said about the harpooneer'snot coming home at all that night, it being
so very late, I made no more ado, but
jumped out of my pantaloons and boots, andthen blowing out the light tumbled into
bed, and commended myself to the care ofheaven.
Whether that mattress was stuffed withcorn-cobs or broken crockery, there is no
telling, but I rolled about a good deal,and could not sleep for a long time.
At last I slid off into a light doze, andhad pretty nearly made a good offing
towards the land of Nod, when I heard aheavy footfall in the passage, and saw a
glimmer of light come into the room fromunder the door.
Lord save me, thinks I, that must be theharpooneer, the infernal head-peddler.
But I lay perfectly still, and resolved notto say a word till spoken to.
Holding a light in one hand, and thatidentical New Zealand head in the other,
the stranger entered the room, and withoutlooking towards the bed, placed his candle
a good way off from me on the floor in one
corner, and then began working away at theknotted cords of the large bag I before
spoke of as being in the room.
I was all eagerness to see his face, but hekept it averted for some time while
employed in unlacing the bag's mouth.This accomplished, however, he turned
round--when, good heavens! what a sight!
Such a face!It was of a dark, purplish, yellow colour,
here and there stuck over with largeblackish looking squares.
Yes, it's just as I thought, he's aterrible bedfellow; he's been in a fight,
got dreadfully cut, and here he is, justfrom the surgeon.
But at that moment he chanced to turn hisface so towards the light, that I plainly
saw they could not be sticking-plasters atall, those black squares on his cheeks.
They were stains of some sort or other.
At first I knew not what to make of this;but soon an inkling of the truth occurred
to me.
I remembered a story of a white man--awhaleman too--who, falling among the
cannibals, had been tattooed by them.
I concluded that this harpooneer, in thecourse of his distant voyages, must have
met with a similar adventure.And what is it, thought I, after all!
It's only his outside; a man can be honestin any sort of skin.
But then, what to make of his unearthlycomplexion, that part of it, I mean, lying
round about, and completely independent ofthe squares of tattooing.
To be sure, it might be nothing but a goodcoat of tropical tanning; but I never heard
of a hot sun's tanning a white man into apurplish yellow one.
However, I had never been in the SouthSeas; and perhaps the sun there produced
these extraordinary effects upon the skin.
Now, while all these ideas were passingthrough me like lightning, this harpooneer
never noticed me at all.
But, after some difficulty having openedhis bag, he commenced fumbling in it, and
presently pulled out a sort of tomahawk,and a seal-skin wallet with the hair on.
Placing these on the old chest in themiddle of the room, he then took the New
Zealand head--a ghastly thing enough--andcrammed it down into the bag.
He now took off his hat--a new beaver hat--when I came nigh singing out with fresh
surprise.
There was no hair on his head--none tospeak of at least--nothing but a small
scalp-knot twisted up on his forehead.His bald purplish head now looked for all
the world like a mildewed skull.
Had not the stranger stood between me andthe door, I would have bolted out of it
quicker than ever I bolted a dinner.
Even as it was, I thought something ofslipping out of the window, but it was the
second floor back.
I am no coward, but what to make of thishead-peddling purple rascal altogether
passed my comprehension.
Ignorance is the parent of fear, and beingcompletely nonplussed and confounded about
the stranger, I confess I was now as muchafraid of him as if it was the devil
himself who had thus broken into my room atthe dead of night.
In fact, I was so afraid of him that I wasnot game enough just then to address him,
and demand a satisfactory answer concerningwhat seemed inexplicable in him.
Meanwhile, he continued the business ofundressing, and at last showed his chest
and arms.
As I live, these covered parts of him werecheckered with the same squares as his
face; his back, too, was all over the samedark squares; he seemed to have been in a
Thirty Years' War, and just escaped from itwith a sticking-plaster shirt.
Still more, his very legs were marked, asif a parcel of dark green frogs were
running up the trunks of young palms.
It was now quite plain that he must be someabominable savage or other shipped aboard
of a whaleman in the South Seas, and solanded in this Christian country.
I quaked to think of it.
A peddler of heads too--perhaps the headsof his own brothers.
He might take a fancy to mine--heavens!look at that tomahawk!
But there was no time for shuddering, fornow the savage went about something that
completely fascinated my attention, andconvinced me that he must indeed be a
heathen.
Going to his heavy grego, or wrapall, ordreadnaught, which he had previously hung
on a chair, he fumbled in the pockets, andproduced at length a curious little
deformed image with a hunch on its back,
and exactly the colour of a three days' oldCongo baby.
Remembering the embalmed head, at first Ialmost thought that this black manikin was
a real baby preserved in some similarmanner.
But seeing that it was not at all limber,and that it glistened a good deal like
polished ebony, I concluded that it must benothing but a wooden idol, which indeed it
proved to be.
For now the savage goes up to the emptyfire-place, and removing the papered fire-
board, sets up this little hunch-backedimage, like a tenpin, between the andirons.
The chimney jambs and all the bricks insidewere very sooty, so that I thought this
fire-place made a very appropriate littleshrine or chapel for his Congo idol.
I now screwed my eyes hard towards the halfhidden image, feeling but ill at ease
meantime--to see what was next to follow.
First he takes about a double handful ofshavings out of his grego pocket, and
places them carefully before the idol; thenlaying a bit of ship biscuit on top and
applying the flame from the lamp, he
kindled the shavings into a sacrificialblaze.
Presently, after many hasty snatches intothe fire, and still hastier withdrawals of
his fingers (whereby he seemed to bescorching them badly), he at last succeeded
in drawing out the biscuit; then blowing
off the heat and ashes a little, he made apolite offer of it to the little negro.
But the little devil did not seem to fancysuch dry sort of fare at all; he never
moved his lips.
All these strange antics were accompaniedby still stranger guttural noises from the
devotee, who seemed to be praying in asing-song or else singing some pagan
psalmody or other, during which his face
twitched about in the most unnaturalmanner.
At last extinguishing the fire, he took theidol up very unceremoniously, and bagged it
again in his grego pocket as carelessly asif he were a sportsman bagging a dead
woodcock.
All these queer proceedings increased myuncomfortableness, and seeing him now
exhibiting strong symptoms of concludinghis business operations, and jumping into
bed with me, I thought it was high time,
now or never, before the light was put out,to break the spell in which I had so long
been bound.But the interval I spent in deliberating
what to say, was a fatal one.
Taking up his tomahawk from the table, heexamined the head of it for an instant, and
then holding it to the light, with hismouth at the handle, he puffed out great
clouds of tobacco smoke.
The next moment the light was extinguished,and this wild cannibal, tomahawk between
his teeth, sprang into bed with me.
I sang out, I could not help it now; andgiving a sudden grunt of astonishment he
began feeling me.
Stammering out something, I knew not what,I rolled away from him against the wall,
and then conjured him, whoever or whateverhe might be, to keep quiet, and let me get
up and light the lamp again.
But his guttural responses satisfied me atonce that he but ill comprehended my
meaning."Who-e debel you?"--he at last said--"you
no speak-e, dam-me, I kill-e."
And so saying the lighted tomahawk beganflourishing about me in the dark.
"Landlord, for God's sake, Peter Coffin!"shouted I.
"Landlord! Watch! Coffin! Angels! save me!"
"Speak-e! tell-ee me who-ee be, or dam-me,I kill-e!" again growled the cannibal,
while his horrid flourishings of thetomahawk scattered the hot tobacco ashes
about me till I thought my linen would geton fire.
But thank heaven, at that moment thelandlord came into the room light in hand,
and leaping from the bed I ran up to him.
"Don't be afraid now," said he, grinningagain, "Queequeg here wouldn't harm a hair
of your head."
"Stop your grinning," shouted I, "and whydidn't you tell me that that infernal
harpooneer was a cannibal?"
"I thought ye know'd it;--didn't I tell ye,he was a peddlin' heads around town?--but
turn flukes again and go to sleep.
Queequeg, look here--you sabbee me, Isabbee--you this man sleepe you--you
sabbee?"
"Me sabbee plenty"--grunted Queequeg,puffing away at his pipe and sitting up in
bed.
"You gettee in," he added, motioning to mewith his tomahawk, and throwing the clothes
to one side.He really did this in not only a civil but
a really kind and charitable way.
I stood looking at him a moment.For all his tattooings he was on the whole
a clean, comely looking cannibal.
What's all this fuss I have been makingabout, thought I to myself--the man's a
human being just as I am: he has just asmuch reason to fear me, as I have to be
afraid of him.
Better sleep with a sober cannibal than adrunken Christian.
"Landlord," said I, "tell him to stash histomahawk there, or pipe, or whatever you
call it; tell him to stop smoking, inshort, and I will turn in with him.
But I don't fancy having a man smoking inbed with me.
It's dangerous.Besides, I ain't insured."
This being told to Queequeg, he at oncecomplied, and again politely motioned me to
get into bed--rolling over to one side asmuch as to say--"I won't touch a leg of
ye."
"Good night, landlord," said I, "you maygo."
I turned in, and never slept better in mylife.
>
-Chapter 4.The Counterpane.
Upon waking next morning about daylight, Ifound Queequeg's arm thrown over me in the
most loving and affectionate manner.You had almost thought I had been his wife.
The counterpane was of patchwork, full ofodd little parti-coloured squares and
triangles; and this arm of his tattooed allover with an interminable Cretan labyrinth
of a figure, no two parts of which were of
one precise shade--owing I suppose to hiskeeping his arm at sea unmethodically in
sun and shade, his shirt sleevesirregularly rolled up at various times--
this same arm of his, I say, looked for all
the world like a strip of that samepatchwork quilt.
Indeed, partly lying on it as the arm didwhen I first awoke, I could hardly tell it
from the quilt, they so blended their huestogether; and it was only by the sense of
weight and pressure that I could tell thatQueequeg was hugging me.
My sensations were strange.Let me try to explain them.
When I was a child, I well remember asomewhat similar circumstance that befell
me; whether it was a reality or a dream, Inever could entirely settle.
The circumstance was this.
I had been cutting up some caper or other--I think it was trying to crawl up the
chimney, as I had seen a little sweep do afew days previous; and my stepmother who,
somehow or other, was all the time whipping
me, or sending me to bed supperless,--mymother dragged me by the legs out of the
chimney and packed me off to bed, though itwas only two o'clock in the afternoon of
the 21st June, the longest day in the yearin our hemisphere.
I felt dreadfully.
But there was no help for it, so up stairsI went to my little room in the third
floor, undressed myself as slowly aspossible so as to kill time, and with a
bitter sigh got between the sheets.
I lay there dismally calculating thatsixteen entire hours must elapse before I
could hope for a resurrection.Sixteen hours in bed! the small of my back
ached to think of it.
And it was so light too; the sun shining inat the window, and a great rattling of
coaches in the streets, and the sound ofgay voices all over the house.
I felt worse and worse--at last I got up,dressed, and softly going down in my
stockinged feet, sought out my stepmother,and suddenly threw myself at her feet,
beseeching her as a particular favour to
give me a good slippering for mymisbehaviour; anything indeed but
condemning me to lie abed such anunendurable length of time.
But she was the best and most conscientiousof stepmothers, and back I had to go to my
room.
For several hours I lay there broad awake,feeling a great deal worse than I have ever
done since, even from the greatestsubsequent misfortunes.
At last I must have fallen into a troublednightmare of a doze; and slowly waking from
it--half steeped in dreams--I opened myeyes, and the before sun-lit room was now
wrapped in outer darkness.
Instantly I felt a shock running throughall my frame; nothing was to be seen, and
nothing was to be heard; but a supernaturalhand seemed placed in mine.
My arm hung over the counterpane, and thenameless, unimaginable, silent form or
phantom, to which the hand belonged, seemedclosely seated by my bed-side.
For what seemed ages piled on ages, I laythere, frozen with the most awful fears,
not daring to drag away my hand; yet everthinking that if I could but stir it one
single inch, the horrid spell would bebroken.
I knew not how this consciousness at lastglided away from me; but waking in the
morning, I shudderingly remembered it all,and for days and weeks and months
afterwards I lost myself in confoundingattempts to explain the mystery.
Nay, to this very hour, I often puzzlemyself with it.
Now, take away the awful fear, and mysensations at feeling the supernatural hand
in mine were very similar, in theirstrangeness, to those which I experienced
on waking up and seeing Queequeg's paganarm thrown round me.
But at length all the past night's eventssoberly recurred, one by one, in fixed
reality, and then I lay only alive to thecomical predicament.
For though I tried to move his arm--unlockhis bridegroom clasp--yet, sleeping as he
was, he still hugged me tightly, as thoughnaught but death should part us twain.
I now strove to rouse him--"Queequeg!"--buthis only answer was a snore.
I then rolled over, my neck feeling as ifit were in a horse-collar; and suddenly
felt a slight scratch.
Throwing aside the counterpane, there laythe tomahawk sleeping by the savage's side,
as if it were a hatchet-faced baby.
A pretty pickle, truly, thought I; abedhere in a strange house in the broad day,
with a cannibal and a tomahawk!"Queequeg!--in the name of goodness,
Queequeg, wake!"
At length, by dint of much wriggling, andloud and incessant expostulations upon the
unbecomingness of his hugging a fellow malein that matrimonial sort of style, I
succeeded in extracting a grunt; and
presently, he drew back his arm, shookhimself all over like a Newfoundland dog
just from the water, and sat up in bed,stiff as a pike-staff, looking at me, and
rubbing his eyes as if he did not
altogether remember how I came to be there,though a dim consciousness of knowing
something about me seemed slowly dawningover him.
Meanwhile, I lay quietly eyeing him, havingno serious misgivings now, and bent upon
narrowly observing so curious a creature.
When, at last, his mind seemed made uptouching the character of his bedfellow,
and he became, as it were, reconciled tothe fact; he jumped out upon the floor, and
by certain signs and sounds gave me to
understand that, if it pleased me, he woulddress first and then leave me to dress
afterwards, leaving the whole apartment tomyself.
Thinks I, Queequeg, under thecircumstances, this is a very civilized
overture; but, the truth is, these savageshave an innate sense of delicacy, say what
you will; it is marvellous how essentiallypolite they are.
I pay this particular compliment toQueequeg, because he treated me with so
much civility and consideration, while Iwas guilty of great rudeness; staring at
him from the bed, and watching all his
toilette motions; for the time my curiositygetting the better of my breeding.
Nevertheless, a man like Queequeg you don'tsee every day, he and his ways were well
worth unusual regarding.
He commenced dressing at top by donning hisbeaver hat, a very tall one, by the by, and
then--still minus his trowsers--he huntedup his boots.
What under the heavens he did it for, Icannot tell, but his next movement was to
crush himself--boots in hand, and hat on--under the bed; when, from sundry violent
gaspings and strainings, I inferred he was
hard at work booting himself; though by nolaw of propriety that I ever heard of, is
any man required to be private when puttingon his boots.
But Queequeg, do you see, was a creature inthe transition stage--neither caterpillar
nor butterfly.
He was just enough civilized to show offhis outlandishness in the strangest
possible manners.His education was not yet completed.
He was an undergraduate.
If he had not been a small degreecivilized, he very probably would not have
troubled himself with boots at all; butthen, if he had not been still a savage, he
never would have dreamt of getting underthe bed to put them on.
At last, he emerged with his hat very muchdented and crushed down over his eyes, and
began creaking and limping about the room,as if, not being much accustomed to boots,
his pair of damp, wrinkled cowhide ones--
probably not made to order either--ratherpinched and tormented him at the first go
off of a bitter cold morning.
Seeing, now, that there were no curtains tothe window, and that the street being very
narrow, the house opposite commanded aplain view into the room, and observing
more and more the indecorous figure that
Queequeg made, staving about with littleelse but his hat and boots on; I begged him
as well as I could, to accelerate histoilet somewhat, and particularly to get
into his pantaloons as soon as possible.
He complied, and then proceeded to washhimself.
At that time in the morning any Christianwould have washed his face; but Queequeg,
to my amazement, contented himself withrestricting his ablutions to his chest,
arms, and hands.
He then donned his waistcoat, and taking upa piece of hard soap on the wash-stand
centre table, dipped it into water andcommenced lathering his face.
I was watching to see where he kept hisrazor, when lo and behold, he takes the
harpoon from the bed corner, slips out thelong wooden stock, unsheathes the head,
whets it a little on his boot, and striding
up to the bit of mirror against the wall,begins a vigorous scraping, or rather
harpooning of his cheeks.Thinks I, Queequeg, this is using Rogers's
best cutlery with a vengeance.
Afterwards I wondered the less at thisoperation when I came to know of what fine
steel the head of a harpoon is made, andhow exceedingly sharp the long straight
edges are always kept.
The rest of his toilet was soon achieved,and he proudly marched out of the room,
wrapped up in his great pilot monkeyjacket, and sporting his harpoon like a
marshal's baton.
Chapter 5.Breakfast.
I quickly followed suit, and descendinginto the bar-room accosted the grinning
landlord very pleasantly.
I cherished no malice towards him, thoughhe had been skylarking with me not a little
in the matter of my bedfellow.
However, a good laugh is a mighty goodthing, and rather too scarce a good thing;
the more's the pity.
So, if any one man, in his own properperson, afford stuff for a good joke to
anybody, let him not be backward, but lethim cheerfully allow himself to spend and
be spent in that way.
And the man that has anything bountifullylaughable about him, be sure there is more
in that man than you perhaps think for.
The bar-room was now full of the boarderswho had been dropping in the night
previous, and whom I had not as yet had agood look at.
They were nearly all whalemen; chief mates,and second mates, and third mates, and sea
carpenters, and sea coopers, and seablacksmiths, and harpooneers, and ship
keepers; a brown and brawny company, with
bosky beards; an unshorn, shaggy set, allwearing monkey jackets for morning gowns.
You could pretty plainly tell how long eachone had been ashore.
This young fellow's healthy cheek is like asun-toasted pear in hue, and would seem to
smell almost as musky; he cannot have beenthree days landed from his Indian voyage.
That man next him looks a few shadeslighter; you might say a touch of satin
wood is in him.
In the complexion of a third still lingersa tropic tawn, but slightly bleached
withal; HE doubtless has tarried wholeweeks ashore.
But who could show a cheek like Queequeg?which, barred with various tints, seemed
like the Andes' western slope, to showforth in one array, contrasting climates,
zone by zone.
"Grub, ho!" now cried the landlord,flinging open a door, and in we went to
breakfast.
They say that men who have seen the world,thereby become quite at ease in manner,
quite self-possessed in company.
Not always, though: Ledyard, the great NewEngland traveller, and Mungo Park, the
Scotch one; of all men, they possessed theleast assurance in the parlor.
But perhaps the mere crossing of Siberia ina sledge drawn by dogs as Ledyard did, or
the taking a long solitary walk on an emptystomach, in the negro heart of Africa,
which was the sum of poor Mungo's
performances--this kind of travel, I say,may not be the very best mode of attaining
a high social polish.Still, for the most part, that sort of
thing is to be had anywhere.
These reflections just here are occasionedby the circumstance that after we were all
seated at the table, and I was preparing tohear some good stories about whaling; to my
no small surprise, nearly every manmaintained a profound silence.
And not only that, but they lookedembarrassed.
Yes, here were a set of sea-dogs, many ofwhom without the slightest bashfulness had
boarded great whales on the high seas--entire strangers to them--and duelled them
dead without winking; and yet, here they
sat at a social breakfast table--all of thesame calling, all of kindred tastes--
looking round as sheepishly at each otheras though they had never been out of sight
of some sheepfold among the GreenMountains.
A curious sight; these bashful bears, thesetimid warrior whalemen!
But as for Queequeg--why, Queequeg satthere among them--at the head of the table,
too, it so chanced; as cool as an icicle.To be sure I cannot say much for his
breeding.
His greatest admirer could not havecordially justified his bringing his
harpoon into breakfast with him, and usingit there without ceremony; reaching over
the table with it, to the imminent jeopardy
of many heads, and grappling the beefsteakstowards him.
But THAT was certainly very coolly done byhim, and every one knows that in most
people's estimation, to do anything coollyis to do it genteelly.
We will not speak of all Queequeg'speculiarities here; how he eschewed coffee
and hot rolls, and applied his undividedattention to beefsteaks, done rare.
Enough, that when breakfast was over hewithdrew like the rest into the public
room, lighted his tomahawk-pipe, and wassitting there quietly digesting and smoking
with his inseparable hat on, when I salliedout for a stroll.
Chapter 6.The Street.
If I had been astonished at first catchinga glimpse of so outlandish an individual as
Queequeg circulating among the politesociety of a civilized town, that
astonishment soon departed upon taking my
first daylight stroll through the streetsof New Bedford.
In thoroughfares nigh the docks, anyconsiderable seaport will frequently offer
to view the queerest looking nondescriptsfrom foreign parts.
Even in Broadway and Chestnut streets,Mediterranean mariners will sometimes
jostle the affrighted ladies.
Regent Street is not unknown to Lascars andMalays; and at Bombay, in the Apollo Green,
live Yankees have often scared the natives.But New Bedford beats all Water Street and
Wapping.
In these last-mentioned haunts you see onlysailors; but in New Bedford, actual
cannibals stand chatting at street corners;savages outright; many of whom yet carry on
their bones unholy flesh.
It makes a stranger stare.
But, besides the Feegeeans, Tongatobooarrs,Erromanggoans, Pannangians, and
Brighggians, and, besides the wildspecimens of the whaling-craft which
unheeded reel about the streets, you will
see other sights still more curious,certainly more comical.
There weekly arrive in this town scores ofgreen Vermonters and New Hampshire men, all
athirst for gain and glory in the fishery.
They are mostly young, of stalwart frames;fellows who have felled forests, and now
seek to drop the axe and snatch the whale-lance.
Many are as green as the Green Mountainswhence they came.
In some things you would think them but afew hours old.
Look there! that chap strutting round thecorner.
He wears a beaver hat and swallow-tailedcoat, girdled with a sailor-belt and
sheath-knife.
Here comes another with a sou'-wester and abombazine cloak.
No town-bred dandy will compare with acountry-bred one--I mean a downright
bumpkin dandy--a fellow that, in the dog-days, will mow his two acres in buckskin
gloves for fear of tanning his hands.
Now when a country dandy like this takes itinto his head to make a distinguished
reputation, and joins the great whale-fishery, you should see the comical things
he does upon reaching the seaport.
In bespeaking his sea-outfit, he ordersbell-buttons to his waistcoats; straps to
his canvas trowsers.
Ah, poor Hay-Seed! how bitterly will burstthose straps in the first howling gale,
when thou art driven, straps, buttons, andall, down the throat of the tempest.
But think not that this famous town hasonly harpooneers, cannibals, and bumpkins
to show her visitors.Not at all.
Still New Bedford is a queer place.
Had it not been for us whalemen, that tractof land would this day perhaps have been in
as howling condition as the coast ofLabrador.
As it is, parts of her back country areenough to frighten one, they look so bony.
The town itself is perhaps the dearestplace to live in, in all New England.
It is a land of oil, true enough: but notlike Canaan; a land, also, of corn and
wine.
The streets do not run with milk; nor inthe spring-time do they pave them with
fresh eggs.
Yet, in spite of this, nowhere in allAmerica will you find more patrician-like
houses; parks and gardens more opulent,than in New Bedford.
Whence came they? how planted upon thisonce scraggy scoria of a country?
Go and gaze upon the iron emblematicalharpoons round yonder lofty mansion, and
your question will be answered.
Yes; all these brave houses and flowerygardens came from the Atlantic, Pacific,
and Indian oceans.
One and all, they were harpooned anddragged up hither from the bottom of the
sea.Can Herr Alexander perform a feat like
that?
In New Bedford, fathers, they say, givewhales for dowers to their daughters, and
portion off their nieces with a fewporpoises a-piece.
You must go to New Bedford to see abrilliant wedding; for, they say, they have
reservoirs of oil in every house, and everynight recklessly burn their lengths in
spermaceti candles.
In summer time, the town is sweet to see;full of fine maples--long avenues of green
and gold.
And in August, high in air, the beautifuland bountiful horse-chestnuts, candelabra-
wise, proffer the passer-by their taperingupright cones of congregated blossoms.
So omnipotent is art; which in many adistrict of New Bedford has superinduced
bright terraces of flowers upon the barrenrefuse rocks thrown aside at creation's
final day.
And the women of New Bedford, they bloomlike their own red roses.
But roses only bloom in summer; whereas thefine carnation of their cheeks is perennial
as sunlight in the seventh heavens.
Elsewhere match that bloom of theirs, yecannot, save in Salem, where they tell me
the young girls breathe such musk, theirsailor sweethearts smell them miles off
shore, as though they were drawing nigh the
odorous Moluccas instead of the Puritanicsands.
Chapter 7.The Chapel.
In this same New Bedford there stands aWhaleman's Chapel, and few are the moody
fishermen, shortly bound for the IndianOcean or Pacific, who fail to make a Sunday
visit to the spot.
I am sure that I did not.Returning from my first morning stroll, I
again sallied out upon this special errand.The sky had changed from clear, sunny cold,
to driving sleet and mist.
Wrapping myself in my shaggy jacket of thecloth called bearskin, I fought my way
against the stubborn storm.
Entering, I found a small scatteredcongregation of sailors, and sailors' wives
and widows.A muffled silence reigned, only broken at
times by the shrieks of the storm.
Each silent worshipper seemed purposelysitting apart from the other, as if each
silent grief were insular andincommunicable.
The chaplain had not yet arrived; and therethese silent islands of men and women sat
steadfastly eyeing several marble tablets,with black borders, masoned into the wall
on either side the pulpit.
Three of them ran something like thefollowing, but I do not pretend to quote:--
SACRED TO THE MEMORY OF JOHN TALBOT, Who,at the age of eighteen, was lost overboard,
Near the Isle of Desolation, off Patagonia,November 1st, 1836.
THIS TABLET Is erected to his Memory BY HISSISTER.
SACRED TO THE MEMORY OF ROBERT LONG, WILLISELLERY, NATHAN COLEMAN, WALTER CANNY, SETH
MACY, AND SAMUEL GLEIG, Forming one of theboats' crews OF THE SHIP ELIZA Who were
towed out of sight by a Whale, On the Off-
shore Ground in the PACIFIC, December 31st,1839.
THIS MARBLE Is here placed by theirsurviving SHIPMATES.
SACRED TO THE MEMORY OF The late CAPTAINEZEKIEL HARDY, Who in the bows of his boat
was killed by a Sperm Whale on the coast ofJapan, AUGUST 3d, 1833.
THIS TABLET Is erected to his Memory BY HISWIDOW.
Shaking off the sleet from my ice-glazedhat and jacket, I seated myself near the
door, and turning sideways was surprised tosee Queequeg near me.
Affected by the solemnity of the scene,there was a wondering gaze of incredulous
curiosity in his countenance.
This savage was the only person present whoseemed to notice my entrance; because he
was the only one who could not read, and,therefore, was not reading those frigid
inscriptions on the wall.
Whether any of the relatives of the seamenwhose names appeared there were now among
the congregation, I knew not; but so manyare the unrecorded accidents in the
fishery, and so plainly did several women
present wear the countenance if not thetrappings of some unceasing grief, that I
feel sure that here before me wereassembled those, in whose unhealing hearts
the sight of those bleak tablets
sympathetically caused the old wounds tobleed afresh.
Oh! ye whose dead lie buried beneath thegreen grass; who standing among flowers can
say--here, HERE lies my beloved; ye knownot the desolation that broods in bosoms
like these.
What bitter blanks in those black-borderedmarbles which cover no ashes!
What despair in those immovableinscriptions!
What deadly voids and unbidden infidelitiesin the lines that seem to gnaw upon all
Faith, and refuse resurrections to thebeings who have placelessly perished
without a grave.
As well might those tablets stand in thecave of Elephanta as here.
In what census of living creatures, thedead of mankind are included; why it is
that a universal proverb says of them, thatthey tell no tales, though containing more
secrets than the Goodwin Sands; how it is
that to his name who yesterday departed forthe other world, we prefix so significant
and infidel a word, and yet do not thusentitle him, if he but embarks for the
remotest Indies of this living earth; why
the Life Insurance Companies pay death-forfeitures upon immortals; in what
eternal, unstirring paralysis, and deadly,hopeless trance, yet lies antique Adam who
died sixty round centuries ago; how it is
that we still refuse to be comforted forthose who we nevertheless maintain are
dwelling in unspeakable bliss; why all theliving so strive to hush all the dead;
wherefore but the rumor of a knocking in atomb will terrify a whole city.
All these things are not without theirmeanings.
But Faith, like a jackal, feeds among thetombs, and even from these dead doubts she
gathers her most vital hope.
It needs scarcely to be told, with whatfeelings, on the eve of a Nantucket voyage,
I regarded those marble tablets, and by themurky light of that darkened, doleful day
read the fate of the whalemen who had gonebefore me.
Yes, Ishmael, the same fate may be thine.But somehow I grew merry again.
Delightful inducements to embark, finechance for promotion, it seems--aye, a
stove boat will make me an immortal bybrevet.
Yes, there is death in this business ofwhaling--a speechlessly quick chaotic
bundling of a man into Eternity.But what then?
Methinks we have hugely mistaken thismatter of Life and Death.
Methinks that what they call my shadow hereon earth is my true substance.
Methinks that in looking at thingsspiritual, we are too much like oysters
observing the sun through the water, andthinking that thick water the thinnest of
air.
Methinks my body is but the lees of mybetter being.
In fact take my body who will, take it Isay, it is not me.
And therefore three cheers for Nantucket;and come a stove boat and stove body when
they will, for stave my soul, Jove himselfcannot.
>
-Chapter 8.The Pulpit.
I had not been seated very long ere a manof a certain venerable robustness entered;
immediately as the storm-pelted door flewback upon admitting him, a quick regardful
eyeing of him by all the congregation,
sufficiently attested that this fine oldman was the chaplain.
Yes, it was the famous Father Mapple, socalled by the whalemen, among whom he was a
very great favourite.
He had been a sailor and a harpooneer inhis youth, but for many years past had
dedicated his life to the ministry.
At the time I now write of, Father Mapplewas in the hardy winter of a healthy old
age; that sort of old age which seemsmerging into a second flowering youth, for
among all the fissures of his wrinkles,
there shone certain mild gleams of a newlydeveloping bloom--the spring verdure
peeping forth even beneath February's snow.
No one having previously heard his history,could for the first time behold Father
Mapple without the utmost interest, becausethere were certain engrafted clerical
peculiarities about him, imputable to thatadventurous maritime life he had led.
When he entered I observed that he carriedno umbrella, and certainly had not come in
his carriage, for his tarpaulin hat randown with melting sleet, and his great
pilot cloth jacket seemed almost to drag
him to the floor with the weight of thewater it had absorbed.
However, hat and coat and overshoes wereone by one removed, and hung up in a little
space in an adjacent corner; when, arrayedin a decent suit, he quietly approached the
pulpit.
Like most old fashioned pulpits, it was avery lofty one, and since a regular stairs
to such a height would, by its long anglewith the floor, seriously contract the
already small area of the chapel, the
architect, it seemed, had acted upon thehint of Father Mapple, and finished the
pulpit without a stairs, substituting aperpendicular side ladder, like those used
in mounting a ship from a boat at sea.
The wife of a whaling captain had providedthe chapel with a handsome pair of red
worsted man-ropes for this ladder, which,being itself nicely headed, and stained
with a mahogany colour, the whole
contrivance, considering what manner ofchapel it was, seemed by no means in bad
taste.
Halting for an instant at the foot of theladder, and with both hands grasping the
ornamental knobs of the man-ropes, FatherMapple cast a look upwards, and then with a
truly sailor-like but still reverential
dexterity, hand over hand, mounted thesteps as if ascending the main-top of his
vessel.
The perpendicular parts of this sideladder, as is usually the case with
swinging ones, were of cloth-covered rope,only the rounds were of wood, so that at
every step there was a joint.
At my first glimpse of the pulpit, it hadnot escaped me that however convenient for
a ship, these joints in the presentinstance seemed unnecessary.
For I was not prepared to see Father Mappleafter gaining the height, slowly turn
round, and stooping over the pulpit,deliberately drag up the ladder step by
step, till the whole was deposited within,
leaving him impregnable in his littleQuebec.
I pondered some time without fullycomprehending the reason for this.
Father Mapple enjoyed such a widereputation for sincerity and sanctity, that
I could not suspect him of courtingnotoriety by any mere tricks of the stage.
No, thought I, there must be some soberreason for this thing; furthermore, it must
symbolize something unseen.
Can it be, then, that by that act ofphysical isolation, he signifies his
spiritual withdrawal for the time, from alloutward worldly ties and connexions?
Yes, for replenished with the meat and wineof the word, to the faithful man of God,
this pulpit, I see, is a self-containingstronghold--a lofty Ehrenbreitstein, with a
perennial well of water within the walls.
But the side ladder was not the onlystrange feature of the place, borrowed from
the chaplain's former sea-farings.
Between the marble cenotaphs on either handof the pulpit, the wall which formed its
back was adorned with a large paintingrepresenting a gallant ship beating against
a terrible storm off a lee coast of blackrocks and snowy breakers.
But high above the flying scud and dark-rolling clouds, there floated a little isle
of sunlight, from which beamed forth anangel's face; and this bright face shed a
distinct spot of radiance upon the ship's
tossed deck, something like that silverplate now inserted into the Victory's plank
where Nelson fell.
"Ah, noble ship," the angel seemed to say,"beat on, beat on, thou noble ship, and
bear a hardy helm; for lo! the sun isbreaking through; the clouds are rolling
off--serenest azure is at hand."
Nor was the pulpit itself without a traceof the same sea-taste that had achieved the
ladder and the picture.
Its panelled front was in the likeness of aship's bluff bows, and the Holy Bible
rested on a projecting piece of scrollwork, fashioned after a ship's fiddle-
headed beak.
What could be more full of meaning?--forthe pulpit is ever this earth's foremost
part; all the rest comes in its rear; thepulpit leads the world.
From thence it is the storm of God's quickwrath is first descried, and the bow must
bear the earliest brunt.
From thence it is the God of breezes fairor foul is first invoked for favourable
winds.
Yes, the world's a ship on its passage out,and not a voyage complete; and the pulpit
is its prow.
Chapter 9.The Sermon.
Father Mapple rose, and in a mild voice ofunassuming authority ordered the scattered
people to condense."Starboard gangway, there! side away to
larboard--larboard gangway to starboard!
Midships! midships!"There was a low rumbling of heavy sea-boots
among the benches, and a still slightershuffling of women's shoes, and all was
quiet again, and every eye on the preacher.
He paused a little; then kneeling in thepulpit's bows, folded his large brown hands
across his chest, uplifted his closed eyes,and offered a prayer so deeply devout that
he seemed kneeling and praying at thebottom of the sea.
This ended, in prolonged solemn tones, likethe continual tolling of a bell in a ship
that is foundering at sea in a fog--in suchtones he commenced reading the following
hymn; but changing his manner towards the
concluding stanzas, burst forth with apealing exultation and joy--
"The ribs and terrors in the whale,Arched over me a dismal gloom,
While all God's sun-lit waves rolled by,And lift me deepening down to doom.
"I saw the opening maw of hell,With endless pains and sorrows there;
Which none but they that feel can tell--Oh, I was plunging to despair.
"In black distress, I called my God,When I could scarce believe him mine,
He bowed his ear to my complaints--No more the whale did me confine.
"With speed he flew to my relief,As on a radiant dolphin borne;
Awful, yet bright, as lightning shoneThe face of my Deliverer God.
"My song for ever shall recordThat terrible, that joyful hour;
I give the glory to my God,His all the mercy and the power."
Nearly all joined in singing this hymn,which swelled high above the howling of the
storm.
A brief pause ensued; the preacher slowlyturned over the leaves of the Bible, and at
last, folding his hand down upon the properpage, said: "Beloved shipmates, clinch the
last verse of the first chapter of Jonah--
'And God had prepared a great fish toswallow up Jonah.'"
"Shipmates, this book, containing only fourchapters--four yarns--is one of the
smallest strands in the mighty cable of theScriptures.
Yet what depths of the soul does Jonah'sdeep sealine sound! what a pregnant lesson
to us is this prophet!What a noble thing is that canticle in the
fish's belly!
How billow-like and boisterously grand!We feel the floods surging over us; we
sound with him to the kelpy bottom of thewaters; sea-weed and all the slime of the
sea is about us!
But WHAT is this lesson that the book ofJonah teaches?
Shipmates, it is a two-stranded lesson; alesson to us all as sinful men, and a
lesson to me as a pilot of the living God.
As sinful men, it is a lesson to us all,because it is a story of the sin, hard-
heartedness, suddenly awakened fears, theswift punishment, repentance, prayers, and
finally the deliverance and joy of Jonah.
As with all sinners among men, the sin ofthis son of Amittai was in his wilful
disobedience of the command of God--nevermind now what that command was, or how
conveyed--which he found a hard command.
But all the things that God would have usdo are hard for us to do--remember that--
and hence, he oftener commands us thanendeavors to persuade.
And if we obey God, we must disobeyourselves; and it is in this disobeying
ourselves, wherein the hardness of obeyingGod consists.
"With this sin of disobedience in him,Jonah still further flouts at God, by
seeking to flee from Him.
He thinks that a ship made by men willcarry him into countries where God does not
reign, but only the Captains of this earth.He skulks about the wharves of Joppa, and
seeks a ship that's bound for Tarshish.
There lurks, perhaps, a hitherto unheededmeaning here.
By all accounts Tarshish could have been noother city than the modern Cadiz.
That's the opinion of learned men.
And where is Cadiz, shipmates?Cadiz is in Spain; as far by water, from
Joppa, as Jonah could possibly have sailedin those ancient days, when the Atlantic
was an almost unknown sea.
Because Joppa, the modern Jaffa, shipmates,is on the most easterly coast of the
Mediterranean, the Syrian; and Tarshish orCadiz more than two thousand miles to the
westward from that, just outside theStraits of Gibraltar.
See ye not then, shipmates, that Jonahsought to flee world-wide from God?
Miserable man!
Oh! most contemptible and worthy of allscorn; with slouched hat and guilty eye,
skulking from his God; prowling among theshipping like a vile burglar hastening to
cross the seas.
So disordered, self-condemning is his look,that had there been policemen in those
days, Jonah, on the mere suspicion ofsomething wrong, had been arrested ere he
touched a deck.
How plainly he's a fugitive! no baggage,not a hat-box, valise, or carpet-bag,--no
friends accompany him to the wharf withtheir adieux.
At last, after much dodging search, hefinds the Tarshish ship receiving the last
items of her cargo; and as he steps onboard to see its Captain in the cabin, all
the sailors for the moment desist from
hoisting in the goods, to mark thestranger's evil eye.
Jonah sees this; but in vain he tries tolook all ease and confidence; in vain
essays his wretched smile.
Strong intuitions of the man assure themariners he can be no innocent.
In their gamesome but still serious way,one whispers to the other--"Jack, he's
robbed a widow;" or, "Joe, do you mark him;he's a bigamist;" or, "Harry lad, I guess
he's the adulterer that broke jail in old
Gomorrah, or belike, one of the missingmurderers from Sodom."
Another runs to read the bill that's stuckagainst the spile upon the wharf to which
the ship is moored, offering five hundredgold coins for the apprehension of a
parricide, and containing a description ofhis person.
He reads, and looks from Jonah to the bill;while all his sympathetic shipmates now
crowd round Jonah, prepared to lay theirhands upon him.
Frighted Jonah trembles, and summoning allhis boldness to his face, only looks so
much the more a coward.He will not confess himself suspected; but
that itself is strong suspicion.
So he makes the best of it; and when thesailors find him not to be the man that is
advertised, they let him pass, and hedescends into the cabin.
"'Who's there?' cries the Captain at hisbusy desk, hurriedly making out his papers
for the Customs--'Who's there?'Oh! how that harmless question mangles
Jonah!
For the instant he almost turns to fleeagain.
But he rallies.'I seek a passage in this ship to Tarshish;
how soon sail ye, sir?'
Thus far the busy Captain had not looked upto Jonah, though the man now stands before
him; but no sooner does he hear that hollowvoice, than he darts a scrutinizing glance.
'We sail with the next coming tide,' atlast he slowly answered, still intently
eyeing him.'No sooner, sir?'--'Soon enough for any
honest man that goes a passenger.'
Ha! Jonah, that's another stab.But he swiftly calls away the Captain from
that scent.
'I'll sail with ye,'--he says,--'thepassage money how much is that?--I'll pay
now.'
For it is particularly written, shipmates,as if it were a thing not to be overlooked
in this history, 'that he paid the farethereof' ere the craft did sail.
And taken with the context, this is full ofmeaning.
"Now Jonah's Captain, shipmates, was onewhose discernment detects crime in any, but
whose cupidity exposes it only in thepenniless.
In this world, shipmates, sin that pays itsway can travel freely, and without a
passport; whereas Virtue, if a pauper, isstopped at all frontiers.
So Jonah's Captain prepares to test thelength of Jonah's purse, ere he judge him
openly.He charges him thrice the usual sum; and
it's assented to.
Then the Captain knows that Jonah is afugitive; but at the same time resolves to
help a flight that paves its rear withgold.
Yet when Jonah fairly takes out his purse,prudent suspicions still molest the
Captain.He rings every coin to find a counterfeit.
Not a forger, any way, he mutters; andJonah is put down for his passage.
'Point out my state-room, Sir,' says Jonahnow, 'I'm travel-weary; I need sleep.'
'Thou lookest like it,' says the Captain,'there's thy room.'
Jonah enters, and would lock the door, butthe lock contains no key.
Hearing him foolishly fumbling there, theCaptain laughs lowly to himself, and
mutters something about the doors ofconvicts' cells being never allowed to be
locked within.
All dressed and dusty as he is, Jonahthrows himself into his berth, and finds
the little state-room ceiling almostresting on his forehead.
The air is close, and Jonah gasps.
Then, in that contracted hole, sunk, too,beneath the ship's water-line, Jonah feels
the heralding presentiment of that stiflinghour, when the whale shall hold him in the
smallest of his bowels' wards.
"Screwed at its axis against the side, aswinging lamp slightly oscillates in
Jonah's room; and the ship, heeling overtowards the wharf with the weight of the
last bales received, the lamp, flame and
all, though in slight motion, stillmaintains a permanent obliquity with
reference to the room; though, in truth,infallibly straight itself, it but made
obvious the false, lying levels among whichit hung.
The lamp alarms and frightens Jonah; aslying in his berth his tormented eyes roll
round the place, and this thus farsuccessful fugitive finds no refuge for his
restless glance.
But that contradiction in the lamp more andmore appals him.
The floor, the ceiling, and the side, areall awry.
'Oh! so my conscience hangs in me!' hegroans, 'straight upwards, so it burns; but
the chambers of my soul are all incrookedness!'
"Like one who after a night of drunkenrevelry hies to his bed, still reeling, but
with conscience yet pricking him, as theplungings of the Roman race-horse but so
much the more strike his steel tags into
him; as one who in that miserable plightstill turns and turns in giddy anguish,
praying God for annihilation until the fitbe passed; and at last amid the whirl of
woe he feels, a deep stupor steals over
him, as over the man who bleeds to death,for conscience is the wound, and there's
naught to staunch it; so, after sorewrestlings in his berth, Jonah's prodigy of
ponderous misery drags him drowning down tosleep.
"And now the time of tide has come; theship casts off her cables; and from the
deserted wharf the uncheered ship forTarshish, all careening, glides to sea.
That ship, my friends, was the first ofrecorded smugglers! the contraband was
Jonah.But the sea rebels; he will not bear the
wicked burden.
A dreadful storm comes on, the ship is liketo break.
But now when the boatswain calls all handsto lighten her; when boxes, bales, and jars
are clattering overboard; when the wind isshrieking, and the men are yelling, and
every plank thunders with trampling feet
right over Jonah's head; in all this ragingtumult, Jonah sleeps his hideous sleep.
He sees no black sky and raging sea, feelsnot the reeling timbers, and little hears
he or heeds he the far rush of the mightywhale, which even now with open mouth is
cleaving the seas after him.
Aye, shipmates, Jonah was gone down intothe sides of the ship--a berth in the cabin
as I have taken it, and was fast asleep.
But the frightened master comes to him, andshrieks in his dead ear, 'What meanest
thou, O, sleeper! arise!'
Startled from his lethargy by that direfulcry, Jonah staggers to his feet, and
stumbling to the deck, grasps a shroud, tolook out upon the sea.
But at that moment he is sprung upon by apanther billow leaping over the bulwarks.
Wave after wave thus leaps into the ship,and finding no speedy vent runs roaring
fore and aft, till the mariners come nighto drowning while yet afloat.
And ever, as the white moon shows heraffrighted face from the steep gullies in
the blackness overhead, aghast Jonah seesthe rearing bowsprit pointing high upward,
but soon beat downward again towards thetormented deep.
"Terrors upon terrors run shouting throughhis soul.
In all his cringing attitudes, the God-fugitive is now too plainly known.
The sailors mark him; more and more certaingrow their suspicions of him, and at last,
fully to test the truth, by referring thewhole matter to high Heaven, they fall to
casting lots, to see for whose cause thisgreat tempest was upon them.
The lot is Jonah's; that discovered, thenhow furiously they mob him with their
questions.
'What is thine occupation?Whence comest thou?
Thy country?What people?
But mark now, my shipmates, the behavior ofpoor Jonah.
The eager mariners but ask him who he is,and where from; whereas, they not only
receive an answer to those questions, butlikewise another answer to a question not
put by them, but the unsolicited answer is
forced from Jonah by the hard hand of Godthat is upon him.
"'I am a Hebrew,' he cries--and then--'Ifear the Lord the God of Heaven who hath
made the sea and the dry land!'
Fear him, O Jonah?Aye, well mightest thou fear the Lord God
THEN!
Straightway, he now goes on to make a fullconfession; whereupon the mariners became
more and more appalled, but still arepitiful.
For when Jonah, not yet supplicating Godfor mercy, since he but too well knew the
darkness of his deserts,--when wretchedJonah cries out to them to take him and
cast him forth into the sea, for he knew
that for HIS sake this great tempest wasupon them; they mercifully turn from him,
and seek by other means to save the ship.
But all in vain; the indignant gale howlslouder; then, with one hand raised
invokingly to God, with the other they notunreluctantly lay hold of Jonah.
"And now behold Jonah taken up as an anchorand dropped into the sea; when instantly an
oily calmness floats out from the east, andthe sea is still, as Jonah carries down the
gale with him, leaving smooth water behind.
He goes down in the whirling heart of sucha masterless commotion that he scarce heeds
the moment when he drops seething into theyawning jaws awaiting him; and the whale
shoots-to all his ivory teeth, like so manywhite bolts, upon his prison.
Then Jonah prayed unto the Lord out of thefish's belly.
But observe his prayer, and learn a weightylesson.
For sinful as he is, Jonah does not weepand wail for direct deliverance.
He feels that his dreadful punishment isjust.
He leaves all his deliverance to God,contenting himself with this, that spite of
all his pains and pangs, he will still looktowards His holy temple.
And here, shipmates, is true and faithfulrepentance; not clamorous for pardon, but
grateful for punishment.
And how pleasing to God was this conduct inJonah, is shown in the eventual deliverance
of him from the sea and the whale.
Shipmates, I do not place Jonah before youto be copied for his sin but I do place him
before you as a model for repentance.Sin not; but if you do, take heed to repent
of it like Jonah."
While he was speaking these words, thehowling of the shrieking, slanting storm
without seemed to add new power to thepreacher, who, when describing Jonah's sea-
storm, seemed tossed by a storm himself.
His deep chest heaved as with a ground-swell; his tossed arms seemed the warring
elements at work; and the thunders thatrolled away from off his swarthy brow, and
the light leaping from his eye, made all
his simple hearers look on him with a quickfear that was strange to them.
There now came a lull in his look, as hesilently turned over the leaves of the Book
once more; and, at last, standingmotionless, with closed eyes, for the
moment, seemed communing with God andhimself.
But again he leaned over towards thepeople, and bowing his head lowly, with an
aspect of the deepest yet manliesthumility, he spake these words:
"Shipmates, God has laid but one hand uponyou; both his hands press upon me.
I have read ye by what murky light may bemine the lesson that Jonah teaches to all
sinners; and therefore to ye, and stillmore to me, for I am a greater sinner than
ye.
And now how gladly would I come down fromthis mast-head and sit on the hatches there
where you sit, and listen as you listen,while some one of you reads ME that other
and more awful lesson which Jonah teachesto ME, as a pilot of the living God.
How being an anointed pilot-prophet, orspeaker of true things, and bidden by the
Lord to sound those unwelcome truths in theears of a wicked Nineveh, Jonah, appalled
at the hostility he should raise, fled from
his mission, and sought to escape his dutyand his God by taking ship at Joppa.
But God is everywhere; Tarshish he neverreached.
As we have seen, God came upon him in thewhale, and swallowed him down to living
gulfs of doom, and with swift slantingstore him along 'into the midst of the
seas,' where the eddying depths sucked him
ten thousand fathoms down, and 'the weedswere wrapped about his head,' and all the
watery world of woe bowled over him.
Yet even then beyond the reach of anyplummet--'out of the belly of hell'--when
the whale grounded upon the ocean's utmostbones, even then, God heard the engulphed,
repenting prophet when he cried.
Then God spake unto the fish; and from theshuddering cold and blackness of the sea,
the whale came breeching up towards thewarm and pleasant sun, and all the delights
of air and earth; and 'vomited out Jonah
upon the dry land;' when the word of theLord came a second time; and Jonah, bruised
and beaten--his ears, like two sea-shells,still multitudinously murmuring of the
ocean--Jonah did the Almighty's bidding.
And what was that, shipmates?To preach the Truth to the face of
Falsehood!That was it!
"This, shipmates, this is that otherlesson; and woe to that pilot of the living
God who slights it.Woe to him whom this world charms from
Gospel duty!
Woe to him who seeks to pour oil upon thewaters when God has brewed them into a
gale!Woe to him who seeks to please rather than
to appal!
Woe to him whose good name is more to himthan goodness!
Woe to him who, in this world, courts notdishonour!
Woe to him who would not be true, eventhough to be false were salvation!
Yea, woe to him who, as the great PilotPaul has it, while preaching to others is
himself a castaway!"
He dropped and fell away from himself for amoment; then lifting his face to them
again, showed a deep joy in his eyes, as hecried out with a heavenly enthusiasm,--"But
oh! shipmates! on the starboard hand of
every woe, there is a sure delight; andhigher the top of that delight, than the
bottom of the woe is deep.Is not the main-truck higher than the
kelson is low?
Delight is to him--a far, far upward, andinward delight--who against the proud gods
and commodores of this earth, ever standsforth his own inexorable self.
Delight is to him whose strong arms yetsupport him, when the ship of this base
treacherous world has gone down beneathhim.
Delight is to him, who gives no quarter inthe truth, and kills, burns, and destroys
all sin though he pluck it out from underthe robes of Senators and Judges.
Delight,--top-gallant delight is to him,who acknowledges no law or lord, but the
Lord his God, and is only a patriot toheaven.
Delight is to him, whom all the waves ofthe billows of the seas of the boisterous
mob can never shake from this sure Keel ofthe Ages.
And eternal delight and deliciousness willbe his, who coming to lay him down, can say
with his final breath--O Father!--chieflyknown to me by Thy rod--mortal or immortal,
here I die.
I have striven to be Thine, more than to bethis world's, or mine own.
Yet this is nothing: I leave eternity toThee; for what is man that he should live
out the lifetime of his God?"
He said no more, but slowly waving abenediction, covered his face with his
hands, and so remained kneeling, till allthe people had departed, and he was left
alone in the place.
>