Have you ever come home to a note that madelife just a little bit easier?
A tip from someone you trust that helps youfind the things you care about.
When you have lots of options in front ofyou, it’s easy to find yourself wishing
for a bit of advice.That’s why we’re introducing the +1 -- a
way for you and your friends to help eachother find great things in Google search.
When you click +1, you’re telling your friends,your family, and the rest of the world: “this
is something you should check out.”Since people will find your recommendations
right when they’ll looking for them, youcan +1 things you might not send an email
or post an update about.And the next time you’re searching, you
might see +1s from your friends and contacts,both on Google search and search ads. So picking
the right coffee maker, news article or chocolatechip cookie recipe could get a little easier.
And soon you’ll be able to +1 more thanjust search results. You’ll also find the
+1 button on sites across the web, makingit easy to +1 pages after you’ve visited
them.The web’s a big place. Sometimes it helps
to have a tour guide. So if you think something’scool, +1!