AdWords helps you reach your customers
whenever,
wherever,
and however you want to reach them.
You can target your ads to broad groups of people.
Or, people with specific characteristics and interests.
No matter what your goal,
you can get more out of AdWords if you take time
to define exactly who you want your ads to reach.
To get started,
try asking the four "w's" of defining your audience.
"Who?"
"When?"
"Where?"
and "What?"
You'll use the answers to these questions
to set up and manage your campaign.
"Who?"
You know your customers better than anyone.
Who are they?
And, what sorts of things do they have in common with each other?
AdWords helps you reach people
based on where they are and what language they speak.
And, for some campaigns, AdWords connects you with people
based on age,
gender,
and interests.
"When?"
They say that timing is everything.
When is the best time to reach your customers?
On the weekend?
In the summer?
AdWords provides ad scheduling tools
that let you choose when your ads will likely appear.
Certain hours of the day.
specific days of the week,
Or, certain holidays or seasons.
"Where?"
It's a big world out there.
And you want to be able to to reach your customers
wherever they are.
AdWords can connect you to people located in specific countries.
Or, right around the corner.
And, we mean that literally.
Your ads can appear on the mobile devices of shoppers right near your store.
"What?"
Now, put yourself in your customers' shoes.
What words and phrases are they using,
and not using,
to search online for the products and services you offer?
These words and phrases, known as "search terms,"
are the keywords and negative keywords
that you should include in your AdWords campaigns.
Using the right keywords
is one of the most important ways to reach the audience
you're looking for.
Getting specific about your audience
is a great way to set yourself up for success
and get the most out of your AdWords investment.
For more ideas on how to make your business more successful with AdWords,
Visit the AdWords Help Center.