I'D LIKE YOU TO TRY SOMETHING FOR ME
I WANT YOU TO TRY AND IMAGINE A WORLD WITHOUT
MONEY..
A WORLD THAT DOESN'T USE MONEY AT ALL
NO BANKS, NO CASH, NO WAGES, NO BILLS.
NO MONEY OF ANY KIND OF WHATSOEVER
WHAT DO YOU SEE?
LET ME GUESS..
MAYBE YOU IMAGINE EVERYONE GOING BACK TO A MORE
PRIMITIVE LIFESTYLE
LIVING A MEAGRE EXISTENCE GROWING OUR OWN CROPS
AND LIVESTOCK..
KIND OF LIKE PEASANTS.
OR, MAYBE YOU SEE A COMPLETE BREAKDOWN OF SOCIETY
NO LAWS OR SOCIAL ORDER
WITH PEOPLE DESPERATE, OR TOO LAZY TO GROW THEIR
OWN FOOD
STEALING FROM OTHERS
OR MAYBE EVEN KILLING EACH OTHER TO SURVIVE
IT DOESN'T SOUND LIKE A VERY
ATTRACTIVE PROSPECT, DOES IT?
WELL SUPPOSING I TOLD YOU THAT THAT IS NOT WHAT
WOULD HAPPEN
THAT IN FACT A DELIBERATE DECISION TO STOP
USING MONEY
WOULD ACTUALLY MAKE OUR LIVES MANY TIMES BETTER
THAN THEY ARE NOW
LOOK AT YOUR LIFE RIGHT NOW FOR EXAMPLE
JUST HOW FREE ARE YOU?
DO YOU OWE MONEY TO ANYONE OR TO A BANK?
A CREDIT CARD DEBT OR A MORTGAGE MAYBE?
YOU CAN'T JUST IGNORE THESE THINGS CAN YOU?
YOU MAY END UP LOSING YOUR HOME
OR MAYBE EVEN GOING TO JAIL!
WHAT ABOUT YOUR JOB?
IF YOU HAVE A JOB AND YOU LOVE IT, GREAT BUT..
MOST PEOPLE ONLY WORK BECAUSE THEY HAVE TO
YOU HAVE TO WORK TO PAY YOUR BILLS
IF YOU DON'T WORK THE LIGHTS GO OUT,
THE WATER GETS TURNED OFF..
THE PHONE'S DISCONNECTED, YOU CAN'T BUY FOOD TO EAT!
SO YOU’RE NOT REALLY THAT FREE AT ALL, ARE YOU?
LIKE MOST PEOPLE YOU PROBABLY THINK THAT THIS
IS SIMPLY A FACT OF LIFE
WE HAVE TO WORK TO MAKE MONEY TO LIVE
JUST LIKE OUR PARENTS DID.
WELL LET ME TELL YOU THIS IS NOT A FACT OF LIFE
ANYMORE
LET ME EXPLAIN WHY..
FIRSTLY, BEAR IN MIND THAT WE DON'T ACTUALLY NEED MONEY,
WE JUST NEED TO THINGS THAT MONEY BUYS FOR US..
LIKE FOOD, CLOTHING, A HOME, ELECTRICITY, PHONE,
COMPUTER, ETC.
MONEY ITSELF IS JUST A MIDDLEMAN
WHICH ON IT'S OWN IS COMPLETELY USELESS
AND JUST CAUSES MISERY TO ANYONE WHO DOESN'T HAVE
ENOUGH OF IT.
NOW, WITH TODAY'S TECHNOLOGY
JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING WE PRODUCE FOR OURSELVES
IS DONE BY MACHINES AND COMPUTERS
IN FACT THIS IS THE VERY REASON WHY WE HAVE
HUGE UNEMPLOYMENT EVERYWHERE..
THE MACHINES ARE TAKING ALL OUR JOBS!
BUT IF YOU STOP AND THINK ABOUT THAT
THIS IS REALLY A GOOD THING!
TECHNOLOGY HAS COMPLETELY FREED US FROM HARD
LABOUR. WE SHOULD BE CELEBRATING THAT FACT
SO IF WE DON'T NEED PEOPLE TO PRODUCE THE STUFF
WE CONSUME
THEN IT SURELY FOLLOWS THAT PRODUCING THESE
THINGS IS A VERY EASY THING TO DO
AND IF PRODUCING STUFF IS EASY
THEN THERE'S ABSOLUTELY NO REASON AT ALL WHY
WE SHOULDN'T BE DOING IT FOR EVERYBODY IS THERE?
AND NOT JUST THE ONES WHO CAN PAY.
AT THE MOMENT OUR ECONOMY IS ALL ABOUT MOVING
MONEY AROUND, AND NOTHING TO DO WITH ACTUALLY
GIVING US WHAT WE NEED
DOESN'T MAKE SENSE DOES IT?
THE ONLY CONSTRAINTS TO PRODUCING THE GOODS WE
NEED SHOULD BE WHAT'S PHYSICALLY POSSIBLE AND
NOT WHAT'S AFFORDABLE!
BELIEVE IT OR NOT, OUR PLANET HAS PLENTY OF RESOURCES
TO PROVIDE FOR EVERYONE..
THE ONLY THING WE'RE SHORT OF, IT SEEMS,
IS MONEY!
SO WHY NOT JUST MAKE EVERYTHING FREE?
FORGET ABOUT MONEY ALTOGETHER!
WHY NOT?
IT'S OUR WORLD, WE CAN MAKE OUR OWN RULES
THE ONLY THING MONEY CREATES IS INEQUALITY
A SCORING SYSTEM FOR HUMANITY THAT DECIDES WHO
GETS WHAT
FOR THE FIRST TIME IN HISTORY OUR TECHNOLOGY
ALLOWS US TO DO AWAY WITH THIS NOTION OF
'HAVES' AND 'HAVE NOTS'
AND THAT'S ONLY THE BEGINNING..
MAKING OUR WORLD FREE WOULD UNLEASH OUR FULL
TECHNICAL POTENTIAL
ALLOW US TO TAP INTO CLEAN ENERGY SOURCES
BRING MEANINGFUL PROSPERITY AND KNOWLEDGE
ALL ACROSS THE WORLD
AND BRING AN END TO WAR AND INJUSTICE FOREVER
JUST IMAGINE
FOOD PRODUCED TO THE HIGHEST STANDARDS AND IN
PLENTIFUL SUPPLY
BIGGER, BETTER HOSPITALS AND SCHOOLS WITH NO
BUDGET PROBLEMS
CLEAN ENERGY AND COMMUNICATIONS AVAILABLE
TO EVERYONE
SPACE EXPLORATION
UNDERWATER CITIES
WHO KNOWS?
TAKE AWAY COST, AND THE ONLY LIMIT IS OUR
IMAGINATION AND THE RAW MATERIALS NEEDED
TO MAKE WHATEVER WE WANT
IN TODAY'S SOCIETY
IF YOU DON'T HAVE MONEY
BASICALLY, YOU DIE
THIS IS NOT JUST WRONG,
IT'S COMPLETELY IMMORAL
BECAUSE IT'S UNNECESSARY
THERE IS ANOTHER WAY,
A NEW WAY
A FREE WORLD WITHOUT MONEY
WHERE EVERYTHING IS FREE
WHERE YOU ARE FREE
WHERE WE CAN PROVIDE FOR EVERYONE, AND
FINALLY SEE AN END TO STARVATION
WHERE SOCIETY IS AS FAIR AS IT CAN
POSSIBLY BE
WHERE TECHNOLOGY, UNHINDERED BY COST
IS SO ADVANCED THAT WE WOULD HARDLY
RECOGNISE OURSELVES!
AND IT'S ALL POSSIBLE NOW
IF WE CHOOSE IT
THE FREE WORLD CHARTER
DEFINES TEN FUNDAMENTAL PRINCIPLES ON WHICH
TO BUILD JUST SUCH A SOCIETY
THESE PRICIPLES ARE NOT RULES OR LAWS
THEY'RE JUST SIMPLE STATEMENTS ON
COMMON-SENSE, THE COMMON GOOD
AND THE SURVIVAL OF US AND OUR PLANET.
A SOCIETY FAITHFUL TO THESE PRINCIPLES
WOULD ULTIMATELY HAVE NO NEED FOR LAWS
BY SIGNING THE FREE WORLD CHARTER
YOU ARE SIMPLY SAYING "YES PLEASE" TO A
FAIRER, FREER
AND BETTER WORLD FOR EVERYONE
PLEASE SIGN IT TODAY AT
FREEWORLDCHARTER.ORG
THANK YOU VERY MUCH