You lift me up high
You spread my wings
And fly me to the sky
I feel so alive
It's like my soul thrives in your light
But how I wish you'd be
Here with me all year around
Ramadan Ramadan Ramadanu ya habib (Ramadan Ramadan Ramadan o beloved)
Ramadan Ramadan laytaka dawman qareeb (Ramadan Ramadan how I wish you were always near)
Love is everywhere
So much peace fills up the air
Ramadan month of the Quran
I feel it inside of me, strengthening my Iman
But how I wish you'd be
Here with me all year around
Ramadan Ramadan Ramadanu ya habib (Ramadan Ramadan Ramadan o beloved)
Ramadan Ramadan laytaka dawman qareeb (Ramadan Ramadan how I wish you were always near)
I just love the way you make me feel
Every time you come around you breathe life into my soul
And I promise that
I’ll try throughout the year
To keep your spirit alive
In my heart it never dies
Oh Ramadan!
Ramadan Ramadan Ramadanu ya habib (Ramadan Ramadan Ramadan o beloved)
Ramadan Ramadan laytaka dawman qareeb (Ramadan Ramadan how I wish you were always near)
Laytaka dawman qareeb (How I wish you were always near)