What you're about to embark upon is unlike any other experience you´ve ever had
We're going to travel throughout history and question every single principle that you have
We do this so we can understand our world
The reason why it´s gonna be unlike any other experience you´ve ever had
is that I´m goig to
insist that you question and critically think about all the information I present to you
Don´t believe anything I say unless you can confirm it and that it resonate with something in your soul
If you can do that you are in the first steps of becoming totally free!
The reason why I produce this project is to create the intellectual foundation for a new era of humanity
We do not have to live in a society based on debt and death
We can produce a society that is founded upon freedom
where everybody´s rights are protected
and everybody has the ability to rise to their highest and best self
I´ve spent 6 years putting together all the information that I can,
to help people understand
why we are where we are today
who controles our world and where it's going to go.
I don't claim to be the originator of a lot of the ideas that I present to you
I don't even have all the answers
but I do intend to ask all the questions
because i know the power of the question
when people start questioning their reality people start becoming free
My unique ability, is to be able to bring all this information in a clear narative
where people can understand what is going on in this world
I believe that when people are aware of how the world works they can prepare for any chalenges that we need to face
This project is an encompassing educational experience that seeks to tell the greatest truth never told.
Through out all of history there's always been a small group of men
that have ruled over all of humanity
for there own personal power and profit
The most amazing aspect to this fact
is that it's physicaly impossible for such a small group of men to control so many people
Once we see how this men work
and how they're able to manipulate societies
we see that at the end of the day the probleme doesn't lies with them, it lies within us.
It is only possible if they can control what's inside of here,...
and that's what this project seeks to do, it seeks to open up your mind
so that you stop thinking like they want you to think
and that you start becoming your highest and best self.
This educational journey that you're going to be taking in this project, will be a dangerous one.
one that if I'm successful will result in your old self dying
this is necessary for your new totally free self to be born
This is truly a life changing experience
and one: if enough people will grasp on to the concepts that I'll be teaching
will result into a new era of humanity so that we don't have to go down the road of fear and tyrany
Once you're aware of how the world really works
you will no longer replay the fool
in your relationships, your investements,
or even your thoughts.
If you notice the most successful peoples in your life
they're usually not the one that are the smartest or hardest working
but thet are the people who were at the right place at the right time.
Understanding how the world works will alow you to put yourself in the right place at the right time.
This project seeks to give you the absolut clarity on how the world works and where we are going.
That will give you the massive confidence to take massive dramatic actions in your own personal life
So that you, are in the right place at the right time.
If I can leave you with one final thought before we continue on
it's something that I came up with
as I was going through my own awakaning and educational experience
and it is :
Subtitles by the Amara.org community