But anyway, this is about the evils of science, so I think it’s perfect.
♫ My oh my, walking by, who’s the apple of my eye? ♫
♫ Why, it's my very own Clonie. ♫
♫ Oh, if I should stroll the hood, who knew I could look so good ♫
♫ just talking on the phone to Clonie. ♫
♫ We are pals, it's cool, 'cause we're not lonely, ♫
♫ shallow gene pool is nothing to my only Clonie. ♫
♫ Me and you, hustling through, holding on through thick and thin, ♫
♫ just day by day, our DNA, so the Olson twins got nothing on us. ♫
♫ We'll survive, side by side. Mother Nature, don’t you call her phony, she’s my Clonie. ♫
♫ Was wealthy, but not healthy, had no one to dwell with me, ♫
♫ so look who I got born -- Clonie. ♫
♫ Far from broke, bored, rich folk, we don't need no natural yolk -- ♫
♫ our babies come full-formed, Clonie. ♫
♫ We'll be huggable, get a publicist ♫
♫ and show them, be the most lovable thing since fucking Eminem. ♫
♫ Oh my friend, multiply, we’re a franchise, like Walt Disney or Hannibal Lecter. ♫
♫ We can tell our cancer cells are more benign than old Phil Spector. ♫
♫ We’ll survive side by side, should have signed with Verve instead of Sony. ♫
♫ You’re my Clonie. ♫ "Oh Clonie, how I love you."
"Ha, I'm the only person I ever loved."
♫ Gee, that's swell. I guess you're just my fatal attraction-ie. You’re my Clonie. ♫
Thank you.
(Applause)