[Thrun] The correct answer is intelligent agent.
Let's talk about intelligent agents.
Here is my intelligent agent,
and it gets to interact with an environment.
The agent can perceive the state of the environment
through its sensors,
and it can affect its state through its actuators.
The big question of artificial intelligence is the function that maps sensors to actuators.
That is called the control policy for the agent.
So all of this class will deal with how does an agent make decisions
that it can carry out with its actuators based on past sensor data.
Those decisions take place many, many times,
and the loop of environment feedback to sensors, agent decision,
actuator interaction with the environment and so on is called perception action cycle.
So here is my very first quiz for you.
Artificial intelligence, AI, has successfully been used in finance,
robotics, games, medicine, and the Web.
Check any or all of those that apply.
And if none of them applies, check the box down here that says none of them.