[You Can't Evict an Idea Whose Time Has Come]  [Occupy Wall St]
[♪somber music playing♪]
[Occupy Wall St]
This movement isn't about the 99 percent defeating or toppling the 1 percent.
[Bank of America]  You know the next chapter of that story,
which is that the 99 percent create a new 1 percent.
[Charles Eisenstein, author, Sacred Economics] That's  not what it's about.
What we want to create is the more beautiful world our hearts tell us
is possible--a sacred world, a world that works for everybody
a world that is healing, a world of peace.
You can't just say:  We demand a world of peace.
Demands have to be specific.
Anything that people can articulate can only be articulated
within the language of the current political discourse.
and that entire political discourse is already too small.
[NEWS] [OCCUPY WALL STREET...] and that's why making explicit demands
kind of reduces the movement
and takes the heart out of it.
And so it's a real paradox, and so I think that
[LIFE OVER PROFIT] the movement actually understands that.
The system isn't working for the 1 percent either.
You know, if you were a CEO, you would be making the same choices they do.
The institutions have their own logic.
Life is pretty bleak at the top too,
and all of the baubles of the rich,
they're kind of this phony compensation.
for the loss of what's really important.
the loss of community, the loss of connection,
the loss of intimacy, the loss of meaning.
Everybody wants to live a life of meaning,
and today we live in a money economy,
where we don't really depend on the gifts of anybody,
but we buy everything.
Therefore we don't really need anybody
because whoever grew my food, or made my clothes,
or built my house, well, if they died
or if I alienate them, or if they don't like me, that's okay.
I can just pay somebody else to do it.
It's really hard to create community
if the underlying knowledge is we don't need each other.
So people kind of get together, and they fraternize,
or maybe they consume together, but joint consumption
doesn't create intimacy--only joint creativity
and gifts create intimacy and connection.
[♪faster, livelier music playing♪
You have such gifts that are important.
Just like every species has an important gift to give to an ecosystem,
and the extinction of any species hurts everybody.
The same is true of each person--that you have
a necessary and important gift to give,
and that for a long time
our minds have told us
that maybe we're imagining things,
that it's crazy to live according to what you want to give.
But I think now as more and more people wake up
to the truth--that we're here to give--
and wake up to that desire and wake up to the fact
that the other way isn't working anyway,
the more reinforcement we have from people around us
that this isn't crazy--this makes sense.
This is how to live.
and as we get that reinforcement,
then our minds and our logic no longer
have to fight against the logic of the heart,
which wants us to be of service.
This shift of consciousness that inspires such things
is universal in everybody,
99 percent and 1 percent, and it's awakening
in different people in different ways.
I think love is the felt experience
of a connection to another being.
An economist says that essentially more for you is less for me,
but the lover knows that more for you is more for me, too.
If you love somebody, then their happiness is your happiness,
their pain is your pain.
Your sense of self expands to include other beings.
That's love; love is the expansion of the self to include the other,
and that's a different kind of revolution.
[OCCUPY YOUR HEART] There's no one to fight; there's no evil to fight.
There's no other in this revolution.
Everybody has a unique calling,
and it's really time to listen to that.
That's what the future is going to be.
It's time to get ready for it and to help contribute to it and make it happen.
[Directed by Ian Mackenzie]
[Produced by Velcrow Ripper, Ian Mackenzie]
[Music by Discount Fireworks II G IV OOTS 4]
[OCCUPYLOVE.ORG]
[OCCUPY]