In 926, the capital of Balhaefell to Georan.
On the territory Georan founded
a new country called Dongranguk,which means 'Georan of East'.
The survivals of Balhae,
however, kept struggling fiercelyto restore their country.
In 927, Autumn
A raid by the Killer-BladeArmy of Dongranguk!
Form a defense line!
Don't give an inch, just fight back!
Gunhwapyeong!
I'm honored.
The commander of the Killer-Blade Armyhas come to pay a personal visit.
I came all the way to ask you something.
Wouldn't you rather cooperatewith Dongranguk?
I'm a human being.
You want me to be a dogfor Georan, like you?
Any last words?
I'm sad to announce
that even our future king, Prince Suhyeon,
has been assassinated by Gunhwapyeong.
Gunhwapyeong,
that traitor is killing off everyonefrom the royal family, cutting off the lineage.
Son of a Bitch!
I heard the news has spread all over,
hurting the morale of the people.
It's a big problem.
We need a king at a time like this.
With Prince Suhyeon dead,who can become our king?
Who else is left?
I've found a princewhose whereabouts were unknown.
Oh, is there a prince?Who is he?
Do you remember Prince Jeonghyeon?
What happened?
As you ordered, I sentMaeyoungok and Mabul to Jungwon.
Youngok...
She always works hard.
According to a secret agent,
Balhae has also dispatchedan excellent fighter...
Who's that?
We don't know yet.
Does anybody have any ideawho it could be?
This time you have to go far.
He's the son of LADY OH.
He was involved in some political strife14 years ago,
and sent to Jungwon.
He was exiled.
The Killer-Blade Army will be coming.
We must find him before the they do.
We must have a king to unite our people.
If we can unite our people and soldiers,instead of fighting all over the place,
we can never lose...
Don't forget that.
Balhae's fate depends on him.
How was today?
What about the girl?
- Sosam?- Yes.
What have you got?
What do you need to sell?
I'll meet the gentleman firstand tell him.
Gentleman?
Sit over there and wait.
There's no need to doubt.
Just tell me how much you can pay.
There are others who are doingthis kind of business.
Why did you come to me?
I heard there's no later trouble with you.
No trouble when dealing with Sosam.
That's right.
The important thing is whether there will betrouble or not. The price is the next concern.
So, how much are you asking?
Fifty jeon...
You rat!That's too cheap!
Is about right,but I'll give you up to 80 jeon.
Fine.
Hey, Sosam, well...
I'm not sure where you heard of mebut you found the right person.
It's very importantwho you deal with here.
You have to find a credible person...
I have a question to ask you.
What is your honorable name?
You were looking for Sosam.
I'm asking for your real name.
There are too many eyes here.Follow me.
What you have,only two of them were existed.
I thought I've been seeing strangers lately.
Your Highness,there must be a misunderstanding.
I'd never misunderstand assassins.
Do me a favor.
Hey, Sosam.
That's no favor...I thank you.
Don't worry and just go!
A misunderstanding?Aren't you going to follow him?
I don't think anythingI say will matter right now.
Please, you guys need to help me.
Before that, you must help us first.
We're desperate.
I don't think so
All I have learned is how to kill.
No need to talk to you.
Kill her.
I said "I don't think so".
Okay, okay! Understood.
I would like to know something.
There is so called"Rules" on the back street.
I know 10 ways to make you speak.
But, I'm not sure you can bear it.
Calm down.I'm willing to give out everything.
Please sit down.
I'm Yeon Soha,officer first class of Biseonwon.
Please forgive my discourtesy,Your Highness.
Of course,I have to forgive in this situation.
I don't know why you think so,but I'm not an assassin.
Do you think I'm stupid?
They'll leave an exiled prince alive?
- What if other princes...- All the other princes are...
are no more.
Your Highness!You must become the king of Balhae.
I will be escorting you to Balhae.
I've lived in a place like this,hiding from assassins for 14 years.
And now that painful time is all gone
and I am to be the king of Balhae, right?
Do you think I believe that?
OK.
Let's say that's all true.Do you think I'm crazy?
That's only a title. You're saying thatI should become the king
to be chased by Georan,not knowing when I will be killed?
Do you know what I believe in?
"Survival, above all else."
That's all I'm interested in.
Your Highness!
My kids came back almost all crippled,which means I lose face.
What are we supposed to do now, huh?
I didn't do it.
Did I say you did it, Prince?
You ain't from battle field, are you?
Tell me.
About what?
Tell me the detailsso I can decide on the price.
How much money will you bring mewhen I hand you over?
Always the same routine...They need to be beaten to start speaking.
You... Stop!
She... She's the one!She attacked us!
Welcome.
I've heard interesting storiesabout your skills.
I'm the boss of...
I told you to take your hands off of him.
Not gonna work.You should talk to me.
I'm the boss of...
Oh, Shit!
Your Highness, are you okay?
What's going on?They're on the same team!
Please don't worry.
I will protect you.
Bo... Boss...
Yeon Soha... It's you.
You came here.
We've passed a couple of times,
but this is the first timewe've said hello.
What do we do?There are more than two of them now.
Don't worry.
This is our region.And we've got more people.
Who are they now?
They're Dongranguk's Killer-Blade army.
Officer Yeon,
wouldn't it be better if we avoidedany unnecessary killings?
Give us Prince Jeonghyeon
and we'll guarantee your life.
I can never allow you to take him.
It's not going to work by talking.
Everyone stop!
What?
Looking at the current situation,I think you're the one we should join up with.
Get out!
Lt'll be better to talk.
I'm the boss of...
What are we doing?Kill them!
Your Highness, please run!
What?
We have to run away.Hurry!
What is the matter?
Your Highness!
They'll keep coming.You have to keep away from them!
Follow me!
Tell me.
Who are you?
What do you have to dowith the Killer-Blade Army?
Most of them are traitors to Balhae.
In the past, I've seen themin the military.
Is that why you introducedyourself like that?
Is there something wrong withhow I introduced myself?
Then, how are you related tomy brother Suhyeon?
I've once guardedthe Crown Prince for a while.
We must go now.
Where to?This is the safest place.
There is no safe place.
As long as we are here,they'll eventually find you.
They will kill everyone on Wolnak streetif they need to...
That is the Killer-Blade army's way.
Didn't you say that surviving isyour only interest?
Then there's no other way.
Then follow me,I know a shortcut out of here.
You want a drink?
Is this the fast way you've mentioned?
We must eat well to go fast.
How can we travel far without eating?
They are the Bidomun, a branch ofHeukdobang's gang. I recognize the symbol.
I heard they are out of their mindsbecause their boss was killed.
Let's go now.We don't have much time.
I will decide whether to go or not.
If I don't like it, I won't go.
Who the hell are you?
My boss here told me
to ask you something!
What?That girl?
What did she say?
She wonders if it's truethat your boss died
from overdoing it with women.
That bitch!
Please just ignore him and let it go.
Too late. We already heard him!
What are you doing?We are still in mourning for my father.
That guy picked a fight with us.We didn't have a choice.
I gave you an order to be cautious,no matter what happened!
Say again what you just said.
I found him! Here! Here!
It's very late.Let's go now.
Uh... OK... Go quickly.
I appreciate your help very much.
Don't say that.How can I just ignore this kind of thing?
I wish...
I wish I could cut him though
for your sake...
Everything will be okay, don't worry.
Let's go.
What happened?
After listening to our story,she said she would help us.
Story?
You told her everything?
Are you out of your mind?
You have no idea how fast rumorsspread in this town.
I said that you abandoned your wifeand children to run away with a widow,
stealing your ill mother's money.
Hey! You're a warrior.How can you lie to people like that?
Sword is not the only thingyou need in the battle field.
Put these on. It's going to bea tough walk and quite cold from now on.
That's okay.
I'm not going to careif you get cold later on.
Let's go.
How did you learn martial art?
I've only trained to use sword.
Where did you learn to use it?
I learned from a military camp.
I had learned from many soldierssince I was little.
You had one rough life.
I would've give up.
What is going on?
I need to get horses.
I don't think it is possible.
It is not like stealing clothes.
It is way too difficult to steal them.
We have to wait till dawn, and...
Don't worry, I can pay.
Damn, it's hot!It's killing me...
Wow, who's this! Brother Sosam!
- I brought you a customer.- Customer?
Do you like any of them?
I want to buy the one on the far rightand the fourth one.
You know your horses.But they are quite expensive...
Since you came with Brother Sosam,
I'll give you a good deal.
For the two, give me 300 jeon.
I live off of you, Brother.
But they're real good horses!
- But they're stolen.- Shhh! Come on...
She's fine. Who is she?
A devil from hell.Come to take me to die.
What? Never understand a single word...
Anyway let me take a sword.I'd better carry one
since someone's trying to kill me...Let's see.
This one should be good.
Why did you choose that one?
Take a better one.I'll pick one for you.
Doesn't matter.I'll never use it anyhow.
You surprised me...
You're here again.
No word from the Deputy Commander yet?
Please don't worry...
Maeyoungok has never lost her quarry.
Wouldn't it depend on who the quarry is?
- Have you found out?- Of course!
Do you know a female warriorcalled Yeon Soha?
I'll go myself.
Are you going to kill the princeagain this time?
The royal court wantsBalhae's royal family to cooperate.
To help calm the conflicts and uprisingsall around the country.
But because you've been killingevery member of the royal family,
the court can't trust you.
If you want to gain something big,you'd better control your vengeful spirit.
Understand?
Father!
Welcome!
How can I help you?
We don't need dinner.Give us a place to stay.
Yes!
How many rooms...
Can't you see?There are two people.
Then I'll prepare...
Give us one room.
One's enough.
Are you going to staylike that all night?
This is the way Biseonwon warriors
guard the door of the kinguntil he falls asleep.
Please do not worry.
If you're going to be silly,you'd better come in and be silly.
You're going to be the king.
There shouldn't beany kind of scandalous rumors.
Are we in Balhae?Who's going to see?
Whoever's watching or notis not important.
Under the heavens,The king should have nothing to hide.
You speak as if I'm going to be the king.
When did I say I would?I'm not going to.
He said they went to Hadong.
The Chief Commander is coming.
Hey, Officer Yeon Soha!
You said you grew up in the military.
Was your father a soldier?
No, Sir.
Then, why?
I didn't have anywhere else to go.
Georan soldiers killed my fatherwhen I was 9,
my mother when I was 10...
I didn't have any other relatives.
It'll be tough to get to Hadong today.
There's a place to stay near there.A very cozy place.
What's that?
That incense...
It's my habit to comfort the dead.
Those who I used to know and the enemieswho have been killed by my sword.
You comfort even the soulsof your enemies?
With no hatred or resentment?
At least you won't be eatenby an evil spirit.
Why?
I also learned how to usethe sword in Balhae.
I know the story
that evil spirits born from the resentment,spite, and hatred,
that lives on in your sword.
Grown-ups used to scare mewith the story
that an evil spirit growsby drinking blood
and finally makes the owner ofthe sword evil as well.
I learned when I grew up
that the story meant one shouldn'tlose serenity because of hatred.
I believe evil spirits grow in the sword.
Do you still believe what you were toldwhen you were little?
That is why you treat it so carefully.
It protects you from evil spirits.
Yes.
I believe I have to use the sword
to protect my important things.
Hey...
What would people thinkwhen they hold the sword?
Protecting? No way...
Killing comes the first.
That is instinct.
I have tried to tell a couple of times,
don't give me that look.
Don't give me that pity look.
I have had a fairly great lifeuntil I met you.
I need to meet someone.Wait here for a while.
We don't have much time.There's still a long way to go...
It's the owner of this shop.
Don't go anywhere, just wait here.
It'll only take me a moment.
Hey, who's this?
Here you go!
What are you doing here,without telling us you were coming?
I'd like to get back my moneythat you're keeping for me.
It looks like I'll have to goin hiding for a while.
What have you done?
It's a long story. I'll tell you later.
So where are you going this time?
Well...For now, quite far...
Sosam, to be honest, some peoplecame by here yesterday.
Who?
They... Said they werewith the Killer-Blade Army.
And they're looking for you!
Let's talk.
Did you think you couldget away from me?
Let me ask you one thing.
Would you like to cooperatewith Dongranguk?
Negotiate?I don't know what you mean by that...
You...
Why are you trying so hard
to take me?
Because you're going to beBalhae's king.
You've seen how I live.
Do you think the throne fits me?
You'll be an excellent king.
Thank you for thinking highly of me,but let me tell you one thing.
I was going to leave you hereand run away.
I failed because my friend betrayed me.
If you were really going to do that,there were a lot of chances.
Why do you think I'm telling you this?
I have no intention to go to Balhae.
If I hope to survive,there are many other ways.
You have to go no matter what.
Then tell me one good reasonwhy I must go to Balhae.
Why do I have to go there?
As far as I know, you weren't presentat your mother's deathbed.
We'll pass by Cheonaegokon the way.
There is a graveyard.
Your Highness!
Long time no see.
I know only one thing.
My father and family were dishonored
and brutally killed bythe royal family of Balhae.
The charges against themwere not false.
I don't care who says what.
I will kill whoever insultedmy father and family.
Your Highness, are you OK?
No, I'm not OK.
Do you know how terribleit is to be stabbed from behind?
A message came from headquarters.What would you like to do?
Say we haven't found them.
I'm not going backbefore I kill Yeon Soha.
Kill Yeon Soha?
As long as I'm under orders,I want to take care of it on my own.
And...
I don't want to cause trouble to you,most of all.
I will give you four days.
If I see Yeon Soha,
you'll have no more chances.
It was quite close.
I guess it may not be that serious...
It is from the street fight.
It is from the battle field.
What made you think...
I wouldn't even get close to it.
I was told you joined the majesty,your father,
for the battle against Georanwhen you were only fifteen.
Georan soldiers!
They seem droppingout of the headquarters.
Your highness!
Look at this chaos.
They wouldn't have time to pack.
They wouldn't even dare to fight, but run.
What is that for?
It is for you since you are not well.
It seems so convenience.
Hand it over.
I will do, your highness.
Why?
Have you ever done carpenter's work?
I had to fix stuffs to sell.
Some dorks broke thingswhen they stole goods.
What? This is what I have been doing.
You see!I'm not even close to be a King.
You made wrong decision.
General KeumHwee.
For the fifteen years old prince
who was brave and fought in the battle field,every soldiers called you by that name.
With glint helmet,
You were surely stand out in the battle field.
How well do you know about me?
There were many princeswho fought in the field
but no one could even get close towhat you had done.
You are the one people rely onin this harsh time.
I'm nobody.
All that is left is useless myself, Sosam.
Your real nature wouldn't have changed.
That is wrong.
I have confidence in you.
Don't be silly.What if you are wrong?
I bet my life on that.
Do we have to do that?
Going across the borderis the fastest way to Balhae.
We could get into big troubleunless we put on Georan costumes.
Don't reveal your emotions.
They are looking forBalhae's militia corp soldiers.
Those who fought here were notfrom regular army of Balhae.
They were from militia corp.
They used to be normal farmersor wood gatherers.
Give me the reins now.I'll take it from here.
That's okay.
I'm bored. I'm bored to death.
Take a nap.
Or sing a song.
What is wrong with you?
You seem so upset.
With all your help, I try to help you back,
but all I get is your angry look.
What is wrong with me, you asked?
Your highness, you were almost killed.
You should be a king.
Your life does not onlybelong to you, but to all people.
What you have donewould have kill more people.
You shouldn't worry too much.
Reason why I'm heading that way isto visit my mother's graveyard.
We are almost there.
There should be a personfrom Balhae waiting for us.
What's wrong?You don't look well.
I'm okay.
Let's rest for a moment.
We must go.
We can't slow down because of me.
Take it.
I may not be able to protect you,but I can avoid causing you more trouble.
Let's go, please.
You said the life of a king is not his own,
and said that he should run away,
even if the manwho would protect him is dying.
Let's say I'm the king of Balhae.
You're telling me I should become a king
who only thinks about himself,although his man is dying?
Is that a king?
If that is...I will never become the king.
Please let me go.You have to receive a bow in welcome.
I, Jocheonsu, under General lmsunji,greet Prince Jeonghyeon, Your Highness.
What happened to you?
- Uncle...- Yes.
Please take care of the prince.
Soha!
Why is she sick? Is it serious?
Tell me what's happened.
She's been poisoned by snake venom.
I think it's too late.
I heard that lmseonju movedto protect the prince.
With his army...Do you understand what this means?
Once they arrive here,there'll be no chance!
I'll finish before they arrive.
The royal court wantssomething more specific.
They sent the Golden Boy Army here!
The Golden Bow Armywill catch the prince.
The Killer-Blade Army can waitfor a new mission.
But...
It's the orders of the court!Are you going to go against them?
I called you because of Gunhwapyeong.
The Killer-Blade Armyshould have taken care of this job.
But the Golden Bow Armyhas been sent already...
If the Golden Bow Armytakes the honor of victory,
I cannot keep my promisewith Gunhwapyeong.
Send us please.We are sure to succeed!
I wish I could.But I already have my orders.
Well, there may be a way...
Can you give me your life for it?
Of course!
Do you know what I mean?
I... I am a warrior!
If there is any way for you to succeed,you must take it,
don't you think?
Don't you regret?About changing your country...
Why... don't you like it?
I don't care about country.
My only concern is to serve you.
Whatever your position is,
you're always the same person to me.
It won't take long...
Once the last prince is killedthe dream will come true...
I will establish my own country
on the territory of current Balhaewith a help of Georan.
Now she passed the crucial moment.
She will wake up soon.
Now you should gomeet your mother.
Yayul cheolla said we have to leave
before the Golden Bow Army arrives.
I will never forgetwhat you wished for, Maeyoungok...
Have you contactedthe Golden Bow Army?
Of course.
They might attack you Killer Bladesunless they know you're coming.
Prince Jeonghyeon will be dead...
No matter who finds him,the Killer Blades or the Golden Bows.
What do you mean?You're still thinking like that?
The court wants the prince alive...
You... think you'll be okay after this?
The Balhae people killed you.
Or, better yet, Prince Jeonghyeon.
So I killed Jeonghyeon to avenge you.
It's a simple story.
You... Ingrate...
He is dead.
Send this message of his deathto the Gloden Bow Army.
I think you should go.She may be awake.
I should.
Your name is Jocheonsu, right?
Yes, your highness.
You look familiar.
I have seen you a couple of timesin the battle field,
General Keumhwee.
How is the wound on your back?
Your Highness.There is a person from headquarters.
Chief of assault team, Jochensu.I came here to see you, your highness.
You are deeply wounded.
I will call medic to bring youto headquarters.
It wouldn't take long, your highness.
I remember you, now.Chief of assault team, Jochensu.
Please take your time to see her.
I will.
Soha!
You're awake. Good.
The prince is not here.
He went to Lady Oh's grave.
He was on guard for you all night.
Gunhwapyeong's here!
Is that how Gunhwapyeong indicateshe's on the hunt?
The prince is in danger!
Mother, I'm here.
I survived no matter whatas I promised to you.
Are you satisfied now?
Aren't you... Jocheonsu, the onewho used to be called the One-Strike-Killer?
It's been a long time, Gunhwapyeong.
I've heard enoughabout your brutal killings.
Take off.I'll catch you up later.
Hurry!
Now that you've met me,I think you're killing days are over.
We must hurry.
Have you recovered? Are you ok?
Yes, I'm fine. Let's go.
Better than expected, Gunhwapyeong.
But you're just an old tiger now...
This... This is...
To the victor goes the spoils...
Your Highness!
No more energy, already?
I know what's happening to you.
If you overuse your energywhen you're poisoned,
your blood gets all twisted.
If you practice your military techniques,
you'll die.
You're wrong.
There's difference betweennot being able to use the techniques
and not being allowed to use them.
You... What's going on?
Stop right there,Commander Gunhwapyeong.
Jocheonsu is dead. I killed him...
And now
I'm going to kill that prince...
There's only one way.
There's one attack,but it will cost you your life.
Do you know what you need forthat one blow?
You need the will to kill.
Think of how much you want to kill.That's all.
The sword... it's not for killing.
It is for protecting valuable things.
But nobody can block my way...
Just sit there...
and watch the prince die helplessly.
That... sword...
You know it well...
Your father gave the same swordto two young princes.
How... How did you...
Because I killed Daesuhyeon.
Your Highness.Teach me how to use the sword.
Why do you want to learn?
My father and mother,both were killed by the Georan people.
I... I want to learn.
The sword is not for killingor hurting people.
Rather, it's for protecting something valuable.
Let me ask you one thing.Why do you have it?
I saved it to kill you...
the last in the lineage.
That's wrong...
That sword is not the secret swordyou think it is.
But the sword you were lookin for is...
The true sword isthe valuable spirit of Soha's.
I must save that spirit.
No matter what.
There's this thing calledthe Body-Attack technique.
Both Daesuhyeon and Jocheonsu...I killed them with this skill.
With this skill...I will also kill you. Slowly.
With the secret skill ofthe Balhae royal family.
You know,this was the only military technique
that I learned completely.
I guess you haven't learnedhow to overcome the inner shock.
From the beginning,you couldn't beat me.
Why...
Why didn't you tell me?
You must pass Cheonaegok now.
I'm asking you why...
You...
You really thought I'd be the king?
Since the day I met you in Junwon,
I've never doubted. Not even once...
Because you must be...
the same person you were 14 years ago.
Without you...
I wouldn't be here.
You brought me a reason to live...
to me who lost everything.
You were my life for 14 years.
It's General lmsunjiand soldier of Balhae.
Please get ready to meet them.
Soha!
I... I have no chance.
What are you talking about?Everything is over!
We're almost there!
Please don't say anything.Please stay like this for a while.
I beg you...
Your Highness, I kept my promise.
But... You didn't...Save your life.
I saved somethingmore valuable than my life.
Sword is to protectimportant things to you.
Am I right?
Soha...
Soha!
We were robbed our castles, our land
and our country.
They even stole our capitaland changed the name of the palace.
A lot of people have died.
They're telling us
to recover the valuable thingsthe things they lost.
So, in this battle,
we are not going to falter or fail in!We'll continue to fight.
If our swords break,we'll fight with our hands.
If we have no strength and are caught,our eyes will pierce the enemies.
If our eyes get plucked out...
We'll speak about their sinsto the heavens!
We'll let them know
they can never take us from this land!
Now this castle will againbe called Holhan Palace
and we'll restore our country!
Charge!
In 928, Dongrangukwithdrew to Leaotong area.
Post-Balhae and Jeongahngukwere founded on the territory.
Both of them proudly called themselvesthe descendants of Balhae.
The medics have arrived to escort you.
- Genera Jo.- Please speak freely.
This kid lost both parents.
Please take care of her.
Yes, sir.
You remember everything I told you?
Yes.
Can you promise you won't forget?
Yes, I promise.