So we talked about
inhaling and exhaling.
And I'd mentioned that the key
first step for both of them
is this change in volume,
going up in volume
or going down in volume.
But I didn't really talk about
how that happens exactly,
so I thought I would
jump into that now.
And let me begin by telling
you that in the middle
of your chest, you have this
enormous kind of bone that
goes down.
And I'm drawing it
out of proportion just
to make it very clear
where this bone is.
But you can go ahead and
feel on your own body
this bone, which we call
either the breastbone,
or the more technical
name is the sternum.
So I'll write that down here.
The sternum is this middle bone,
and all the ribs on both sides
attach there.
So you've got a total of 12
ribs and seven pairs of them.
Actually, I should
say 12 pairs of ribs.
I don't want you to
think there are 12 total.
We actually have 24 total
and seven pairs of the ribs.
So 14 ribs actually attach
directly to this sternum bone.
So in white, these are the ribs.
And between the ribs,
you actually have muscle.
So I'm going to draw in some of
these muscles between the ribs.
And these muscles are all going
to have their own nerve that
allows them to contract.
So these muscles are
controlled by your brain,
and their name-- let
me just jot down here
on the side-- is
intercostal muscle.
And inter just means between, so
this is the name of the muscle.
And costal refers to the ribs.
So when you see
that word costal,
you'll know we're
talking about the ribs.
So what's between the
ribs is these muscles,
intercostal muscles.
And they are going to
start moving outwards when
your brain says, hey, I
want to take a deep breath.
So these muscles are
going to contract.
The ribs, I should say,
are going to move outwards.
So these go out.
And you also have--
let me just make
a little bit of space on
this canvas-- another muscle
that kind of rides
down here and has
kind of an upside
down U shape to it.
So I'm drawing it
kind of like a dome.
You can think of it as a dome.
And this dome is the
floor-- if you remember,
we talked about the
floor of the thorax.
So this is, of course,
our diaphragm muscle.
So we've got our
diaphragm muscle.
And this one when it contracts,
instead of going out,
it's going to go down.
So it's going to
kind of flatten out.
And I can actually draw this.
If you can now just stick
with me for a moment,
I'm going to erase
this dome-like shape.
And I'm going to draw what it
looks like as it contracts.
So when it contracts, it's
actually going to be more flat.
And this flat diaphragm,
as you can see,
is now further down
than it used to be.
And as it goes down, all
of the structures that
are inside this space--
so the two lungs.
And of course, I didn't
draw the heart here.
But the heart would be kind
of in this cardiac notch.
If you want, maybe I could
even draw that heart here.
They're all going to kind
of physically move down.
So this is our
heart and our lungs.
They're physically going
to be kind of drawn
downwards and out.
They are going to also move out
as the intercostal muscles move
out.
So you have expansion
of these lungs.
That's basically the idea.
And if you were to kind of
zoom in on this to kind of see
exactly what this
expansion looks
like, when I say you have
more volume in the lungs,
really what I should be saying,
if I wanted to be more exact,
is that all the alveoli--
if these are the alveoli,
let's say this is
another branch.
And this is another
alveoli right here.
All these alveoli, they
are actually expanding.
And you have about
500 million alveoli.
If you can just kind of fathom
how big a number that is.
It's an enormous
number of alveoli.
And if I was actually
drawing them,
I would be here drawing forever.
It would take
forever to write out
this many different alveoli.
But basically what happens
is that when the ribs go out
and the diaphragm moves down,
these alveoli are actually
being pulled out.
They're actually
being pulled outwards,
so they are actually going
to be getting larger in size.
They literally look like
they've grown in size,
and this is what they look like.
And actually, if you were
to take an even closer look,
you'd see that these
alveoli have around them
a bunch of protein.
The cells around them
have a bunch of protein,
and this protein
is called elastin.
And you can guess
what elastin might do.
It has kind of a similar
sound to the word elastic.
And elastin is basically
kind of like a rubber band,
so you can kind of think of
elastin as a rubber band.
And when the muscles
move down and out
and the alveoli
are pulled open--
let me actually now scroll up,
because you can kind of go back
to the idea of inhaling--
what is happening, then?
Well, you have a couple
things happening.
One, you have muscles-- I'll
just write muscles contracting.
And when I say
muscles, you know I'm
talking about all those
intercostal muscles
in your diaphragm.
And as a result of the
muscles contracting,
you have now the alveoli
are stretched open.
So those rubber bands,
those elastin proteins,
are literally physically
being stretched opened.
And keep that in mind, because
what's going to happen then
is when the muscles
relax, which is
what happens when you
exhale, what do you
think is going to
happen to that elastin?
Well, if it's like
a rubber band,
if that's what I'm saying
it's going to be like,
then the alveoli
are going to recoil.
And that's actually
the driving force
for why the volume
goes back down.
So if you have a
bunch of rubber bands
that you're stretching
out-- let me actually
bring up the picture.
You'll see it really clearly.
If you're physically kind of
using your muscles to help
pull this stuff
open, then the moment
that you stop pulling
open, the moment
that you stop contracting
those muscles now
that you have a nice big
volume, what's going to happen?
Well, all these
elastin molecules
are going to snap back.
Let me do it with
a different color.
Let's do this color.
They're going to
snap back like this.
All that protein
is going to want
to snap back into
the original size.
And when they do, this
thing gets smaller.
So my alveoli goes back
to its original size,
which was much
smaller than this.
Let me actually just quickly
show that and show you
that even though contraction
is what opened up things,
it's the recoil
that brings things
back down to their normal size.
And let me erase this to make
it kind of a neater drawing.
So you can see it now.
Inhaling, the way that we
actually increase the volume,
is by pulling things
open through contraction.
And this actually
requires energy.
Remember, you can't
contract a muscle
without spending
chemical energy.
So this takes chemical
energy, and we usually
think of this molecule ATP as
the specific type of chemical
energy we're going to use.
And to exhale, when
you reduce the volume,
it's going to be driven
by this elastic recoil.
So that's a type of
elastic potential energy.
So this process of
inhaling and exhaling
is really a little
different from each other.
On the one hand,
you're using ATP.
You're actually burning
through these molecules.
And then when you
exhale, you're actually
not using chemical
energy anymore.
You're just using that
elastic potential energy,
kind of the same sort
of energy that you
can imagine you would have
if you snap a rubber band.
So let's stop there, and we'll
pick up in the next video.