Consider the numbers one third, seven, and negative fifteen.
To which sets of numbers, listed below does each of these numbers belong?
So let's think about the sets first and then that'll make it pretty straightforward to think about what sets these guys are members of.
So natural numbers - you can kind of view these as the counting numbers.
This is one, two, three, four, five, six.
Or another way to think about it - it's the whole numbers except for zero.
So zero is not in the natural numbers.
It starts at one. One, two, three, four, so on and so forth.
Whole numbers, is the natural numbers, plus zero - plus zero.
Integers are the whole numbers plus the negative versions of the natural numbers.
Then rational numbers - these are any number that can be represented by a fraction.
Irrational numbers cannot be represented by a fraction.
And then real numbers are essentially all of these.
Let's think about the numbers that they gave us.
So let's first think about one third.
One third is not a counting number. It's not a whole number - it's a fraction.
It's not an integer (it's a fraction.)
It is a rational number - it can clearly be represented as a fraction.
So I'll write it over here.
One third is a rational number.
It's not an irrational number.
There's nothing that's part of both the rational and irrational.
You have to pick between one of those two.
But it's clearly a real number.
So one third is rational and it is real.
So let's do seven here.
So seven is a natural number.
When you count things, you can count up to seven.
it's definately a whole number. In fact anything that's a natural number is also going to be a whole number.
And anything that's a natural number or a whole number is also going to be an integer.
Anything that is a natural number, a whole number or integer is also going to be a rational number.
Cuz you can represent this as seven over one.
Seven is equal to seven over one.
And you can do this with any integer.
You can just say it's the same thing as that over one.
So you can represent it as a fraction.
So it's clearly not irrational.
But it's going to be real. It's going to be real.
And then finally you might be saying "Hey, why do we even care about real numbers?"
In the future we'll be introduced to things called imaginary and complex numbers.
And those aren't real.
But most of the numbers that you've dealt with so far, they're going to be real numbers.
So let's just finish up with negative fifteen over here.
Negative fifteen is not a counting number, it's not a natural number - it's not one two three and so on and so forth.
It's not a whole number, because that would just be zero plus one two three four five.
It is an integer though.
It is an integer - so it is negative fifteen is right over here.
You can view natural numbers as all positive integers.
You can view whole numbers as all non negative integers.
And of course integers will include negative and nonnegative integers.
And that's where negative fifteen's going to sit.
Negative fifteen can be represented as a rational number.
It can be negative fifteen over one.
So we're going to put negative fifteen over here.
If it's rational it can't be irrational, and it's gonna be a real number.
And we are done.