Produced byLee Choon-yeon
Executive producerPark Mu-seung
Associate producerLee Mi-young
ProducerIm Hye-won
Original screenplayByun Won-mi & Song Min-ho
Screenplay revised byGwak Jae-yong
Director of photographyKim Byung-il
Lighting directorLee Kang-san
Location soundAhn Sang-ho
Set designArt Service
Production designerLee Jung-woo
Edited byGyung Min-ho
Music byJung Jae-hyung
StarringLee Byung-hun
Lee Mee-yeon
Lee Eul
Park Sun-young
Directed byPark Young-hoon
You scared me.
I can't concentrate because of you.
It's not the first timeyou've heard this.
My eardrums are gonna pop!
Doesn't this sound great?
After your military service,I thought you'd grow up.
Anyway, you can't car race.It's too dangerous.
Hey, Dae-jin.
Look for other work whilehelping me out like old times.
Your work is just as dangerous.
You always cut your hand.
Over 10,000 people diea year from car accidents.
But I haven't seen anyone
die from a car race yet.
Ho-jin. Step aside.
You worry too much.
I can't die that easily.
Be careful.
Mr. Choi, checkthe singers' MR tape.
Okay.
Mr. Jun, checkthe moving lights.
Take a look.
OK!
Mr. Choi, checkthe monitor speaker.
- Please hurry. Over here.- Yes.
Go inside the domeinstead of Hyun-woo.
Yes.
It has to be checked properly.
It has to open during the concert.
Why not? It'll be fun.
Sure. Getting trapped insteadwould be fun, huh?
- It won't open!- Open it up!
I didn't do it.
Don't turn on the master so fast.
Thanks.
Hello?
Yes. Really?
From the 16th to the 18th?
Yes. But the exhibitionwill last for only three days.
Yes.
I'd like it to be for a week though.
Then please ask around again.
Thank you. Bye.
How'd you time it perfectly?It's pouring.
- Hungry, huh?- Yes.
This song.
Don't you remember it?
It's my favorite song.
It's nice hearing it in the rain.
Here. It's a present.
What's with you today?Thank you.
That's all?
I love you.
What's this?What's gotten into you today?
You made all this?
Of course.
But it's not my birthday,and yours is much later than mine.
Hey, Eun-soo.
It's our anniversary, dummy.
My goodness, you're right.
I totally forgot.I'm sorry, Ho-jin.
There's one more thing.
It's the most valuable thing to you,
but the chain wasalways a problem.
Eun-soo, I love you.
Honey. It's like as if my dadsent you to me.
Why?
Whatever my dad makes,
it becomes preciousno matter how trifling it is.
Even this necklace,
he made it out of peach flowerseeds when I was a kid.
I know. That's why youdeserve this much.
There's only onelike this in the world, huh?
But I'm sorryI didn't prepare anything.
Then how about I steamyou up tonight?
Really? Tonight?
Sure.
Bastard.What perfect timing.
He's too big to live with us, huh?Shall we get him married?
Shall we?
Yeah.
But right after I said it,
it really didn't open.I'm serious.
No way.
I must have sometelekinetic power.
Do it.
Do what?
Okay, I'll give it a try.
Look straight into my eyes.
Yawn. Should I do iton Dae-jin, too?
Hiccups.
Sorry, I guess I can't.
He did it.
I really had to.
- It switched.- Stop joking around.
No, it was real.
Don't joke with...
Come on.
No, mine was real, too.
It was real?
Yeah.
I'll go drink some water.
Come here.
No, I have togo drink some water.
Stop joking around.
I'm serious.
Dae-jin, don't you want a girlfriend?
The best times are at your age.
I like it now.
Like what?
Fiddling with your carin the garage?
I'm curious as to what's inthat mind of yours.
I'm going to bedso you two drink up.
- Good night.- You, too.
I'll be in soon.
Dae-jin.
Make sure youblock your ears tonight.
- Good night.- You, too.
I've never seen you neat freakwho can't close a lid right.
Thanks a lot for today.
It's nothing.
I'm so happy.
You still have the hiccups?
No, I'm okay.
You still have them. There's nouse tonight. Let's just go to bed.
It stopped.
It stopped?
It did.
Really?
You're doing it again.
Just go to sleep.
Ho-jin.
Yeah.
You're supposed toput it all the way on.
That's because it's used up.I'll buy it later.
I think a lot of reportersare coming to my exhibition.
Dae-jin. Act like a reporterand ask me questions.
So I can practice.
Come on, that's dumb.
Just this once.
Mr. Hwang Ho-jin,please explain your work.
Yes. From the furniturewe commonly see,
I felt like I twisted them a little.
Similar to Marcel Duchamp's toilet,
I recreated whatwe commonly see.
Furniture...
Ho-jin. You practiced a lot, huh?
Does it show?
Of course.
Be a little artsy and inarticulate.
As if it just came to you,
and say 'and' a lot.
Also, smiling and liftingyour eyes is better.
You're right.
Do it again.
Mr. Hwang Ho-jin,please describe your work.
Yes. From the furniture...
we commonly see...
How can I put it?
I twisted them a little.That is...
Ho-jin.
Just do it like before.
Bastard.
You did well.
Oh, hi.
What are you doing?
They say pollacks can look farwith their big eyes,
and can eat a lotwith their big mouths.
Then how could theyget caught then?
You're right.
If I get hungry while driving,I'm gonna eat it.
Do as you please.
Whether you cook or fry it,
I'll put it here for your sake,
so be careful.
Thanks, Ho-jin.
Ho-jin. It's your favorite dish.
Hey.
Is Dae-jin still in the garage?
Wait. Wait.
What are you doing?
I don't have the hiccups today.
So what? What if Dae-jin comes?
He's leaving soon.
Wait. Is it bothering you?
Do something with the table.
Okay, just a sec.
Aren't you going to fast?
I can handle it.
He's taking it too hardfrom the beginning.
I told him to pace himselfand go slow.
Would a drug addict listen
if you said to inject slowly?
What's he doing?
I don't know.
Might be engine trouble.
You exhausted the engine.
The race isn't far away,so don't blow the engine.
Don't use too much RPM.
I didn't overdo it.It'll be fine.
Your record's improving,so I'll let it pass.
But racing isn't all about luck.Take caution.
I got it. Hey, the car's in great shape.
Damn it. I should've beenborn a car.
Good job everyone.
A coin that brought you pleasure?
Eun-soo.
Huh?
You got another love letter today?
You're so lucky.
For what?
You've been marriedfor three years,
but you still exchange love letters?
You're so lucky, Eun-soo.
I wish I could meeta guy like that.
It won't be too easy.
Can't there bea guy like Ho-jin?
What?
Ho-jin. But the letter'snot finished.
That's okay.
- Sleep well?- Oh, yes.
You must've came inlate last night.
Yeah, I had a drink with Yae-joo.
I'm out of lotion,so I came for Ho-jin's.
- It's on the dresser.- Okay.
That's our business, Dae-jin.
It was just here,but I wasn't looking at it.
If you're done,then please leave.
We live in the same house,but you two are unfair.
So hurry and get married.
Okay.
Ho-jin.
Look at this.
Hello.
You're here early, Yae-joo.
Of course. It's an important dayfor Dae-jin.
You're the only onewho thinks of him.
Ho-jin, this came off.
I'll fix it later.
The more I see it,the prettier it is.
There's only onelike this in the world.
I'm so jealous.
- Stay for a while.- Okay.
You and Dae-jinseem to hit it off.
I wish. It was betterwhen he took pictures.
I feel like I'm leftin the cold now.
He always worries mewhen he car races.
You should change his mind.
Think he will if I tell him?
Hey, am I invisible now?
- What's up?- Hey.
Ho-jin, I'm leaving now.
- You're going now?- Yeah.
Going to the race, right?
Of course.
Tell him good luck for me.
I will.
I'll see you later.
Be careful driving.
See you later.
- Have a nice day.- Okay.
Oh no.
Drivers please come to
the record room for tests.
Five minutes leftuntil the race begins.
Did Ho-jin say he'll come?
Yeah, he did.
He doesn't like me racing,so he might not.
Then why are youif your brother opposes it?
Because I like it.
Drivers please reportto the waiting area.
Hey, good luck!
Welcome.
To Yongin Speedway please.
I'm very late.I have to be there by one.
Wow, you're really late.
I'll go fast.
It's the thirdKorea Motor Championship.
1st place in the GT Class,Indigo's Kim Yi-soo.
He took pole positionin the last match.
3rd place was the wild horse,Bak Joon-woo of Oilbank.
Fourth was Hwang Dae-jin.
Feeling good, huh?
- And don't pass upthe in course.- Okay.
Remember, you're buying tonight.
I know.
Three minutes left until the race.
The gates are closing.
Please clear awayfrom the grid.
The sign board is up.
Start your engines.
I screwed up on corner three.What's my time?
Present lap time is 1:08:07.
You're doing alright.
Aren't you going too fast?
I thought you were late.
Right.
Don't worry.
I've been accident free for 10 years.Even as a speed taxi.
It's the 7th head pin,so slow it down.
He wants to kill himself!He's scaring me!
The steering wheel is strange.I'm going in.
Hurry up!
What happened?
The steering wheelshakes too much.
Check the tires fast.
Check the tires!
Dae-jin, please be careful.
How much am I behind?
0.3 seconds behind in lap time.
Run the courseinstead of placing.
No, I have to place.
You still have more to go,so it's okay. Be careful.
The traffic lightsaren't cooperating today.
Dae-jin, there's troubleon the course. Slow down!
Dae-jin!
What? What did you say?
I can't hear you well.
His pulse rate andbrain waves are improving,
but he still can't wake up.It's too bad.
Dr. Lee, what happenedto this patient?
Didn't I tell you?
Both brothers got intoa car accident.
His older brother got hitby a truck while in a taxi.
So he's pretty much dead.
I guess so.
But the younger one
was in a car race accident.
What a strange world.
But is there any hopefor this patient?
I don't know.
Are you okay?
Jung-woo, match the steps.You're falling back.
You're supposed to turn there.
Young-eun!
Are you checkingthe distance? They're off.
Mr. Kim, please check the lights.There are shadows onthe models' faces.
Hello? Oh, hello.
What?
Please rest for now.
It's really fortunate thatyou at least have come back.
Are you okay?
Get up.Go rest in your room.
Hey, Dae-jin!
Thanks for being alive.
You were lying therelike a corpse,
and I was helpless,thinking you'd leave forever.
I'm just really happythat you're alive.
You were a heavy smoker before.
While you were in bed,know how stupid I acted?
I went all the wayto the junkyard.
I wanted to see your carget totally demolished.
When I went to see it,I laughed a lot.
You were in bed like that,
and I was jealous of that car.
I was acting overboard.
But now
I'm just really thankfulthat you've come back.
Yae-joo.
Hi, Eun-soo.Is Dae-jin really alright?
Dae-jin.
What are you doing?
Have a seat.
Did you buy that flower?
No. I thought you bought it.
Was Dae-jin always a good cook?
The way he cutsvegetables is amazing.
Sit. Yae-joo, too.
Hurry and eat.
Dae-jin.
Right now, this is all thatI can do for you. Now eat.
Dae-jin...
Mr. Hwang Dae-jin.
- After you woke up...- My name is Hwang Ho-jin.
Any other symptomsbesides headaches?
Sometimes my ears ring.I'm cold. And I keep getting sleepy.
But doctor, I'm Hwang Ho-jin.
What happened to me?
From a psychologist's perspective,his depression and hysteria
have sprung up in a peculiarway after his trauma.
On the surface,
he believes he's Hwang Ho-jin.
But the problem isthat his consciousness firmly
believes that he's possessed.
Possessed?
If I explain it simply, the body istaken over by someone else's spirit.
The best way to know is to findproof of his believe fromhis unconscious.
Doctor. How can this be possible?
Oh my goodness.Oh my goodness.
Your hand.
Oh no.
Eun-soo, he cut his hand.
He kept saying he's Ho-jin.
Wait.
My hands aren't listening to me.
I don't know how this happened.
Dae-jin, hurry and go inside first.
Yeah, let's hurry, Dae-jin.
I'm not Dae-jin.
I don't know. I don't knowwhy I'm like this.
Hey. Pull yourself together.You're Hwang Dae-jin.
You're the Hwang Dae-jin.I've always liked!
Eun-soo, I'm sorry.I'm really sorry.
Yae-joo. Dae-jin is still sick.
He's doing this becausehe's still mentally unstable.
When time passes, he'll be better.
That bastard. He's trying tosuck me dry forever.
I'll be backafter I give this to him.
The gift yourfather gave you.
I've finally fixed it.
- Can you hear my voice?- Yes.
Tell me your name.
Hwang Ho-jin.
Good.
You're falling into acalmer and deeper sleep.
Imagine a cloud.
A soft wind is blowing.The cloud is moving slowly.
Very slowly.
Now look slowlybelow the cloud.
What do you see?
A road.
What's on top of this road?
A taxi. Taxi.
Are you riding in this taxi?
I don't know.
You're moving forward.Slowly.
What do you seein front of you?
What do you see?
Calm down.Put your mind at ease.
Common symptomsfor possessed patients
are a drop in their temperatureand feeling very cold.
They keep sleeping,and even their ears ring.
But doctor how couldmy husband's soul...
Even modern psychology can't provewhether possession exists or not.
By simply acknowledging itand nursing him is better.
Take your medicine.
How I'm acting now...I'm not sick, Eun-soo.
I understand. But you have totake this medicine.
Eun-soo.
Eun-soo, open the door.
I'm not going to do anything.
Eun-soo.
I'm sorry.I didn't want to do this.
But being alone in that roomis too hard for me.
Don't go.
I'm scared, Eun-soo.
If I sleep in that room alone,I feel like I'll never wake up.
I'm very frightened.
Being with Dae-jinis too hard on me.
I feel like I'm unconsciouslylooking for Ho-jin in him.
No. Honestly, I saw him.
I'm so confused.
I feel like I know whatyou're going through.
Eun-soo. I finished my thesis,so I have a lot of time now.
If it's okay that I spend timewith him, he'll get better.
When you were in the marines,
you said it was hell,but you felt peaceful.
If we work our butt offat my family's ranch,
that mildew in your headwill wash away.
Yae-joo. Where can I go?
I'm not going anywhere.This is my place.
Eun-soo agreed with me.
Eun-soo did?
Yes, your sister-in-law.
If I just stay here like this,
everything will turn back to normal.
Hey, how long will you keep this up?
Are you planningto drive us crazy?
Eun-soo is having it hardenough taking care of Ho-jin.
Seeing him in a coma forover a year is hell enough.
What did you just say?
Look. Look very carefully.
That's Hwang Dae-jin's face.Know do you get it? Do you?
If it's that hard on you,I'll become Dae-jin.
I'll live like Dae-jin.
Scared, huh? Cutting grass,chasing and milking cows.
You'll probably pass out.
But don't worry. I'll help you.
Ho-jin. It's Eun-soo.I see that my Ho-jin is still sleeping.
I thought you hated being lazy.So how could yousleep this long?
I've changed a lot lately.
I get angry with people a lot,and I don't laugh easily.
If you saw me,you'd be surprised.
I can't remember your voice.
The harder I try, the moreI can't remember.
I wish you'd call me just once.
Eun-soo. Hey, Eun-soo.
Without you, I can't do anything.
Go!
Hey. You're working upa real sweat.
Trying hard to make my family rich?
Dae-jin.
Leave me alone if you want tomake me into Dae-jin.
Since you're not complainingand whining, you're no fun at all.
Fine. I guess I'll just bea one-woman band forever.
I'll play drums with yousometimes. Bang, bang.
Hey. Like you,
if I could become someone else,
then I wish I had never met you.
Then I could've madeabout 100 guys like me.
Hey.
Look. When you do this,you're totally Dae-jin.
Now you laugh for me?
I tried so hard to see it just once.
Hey. I don't care who you are.
You're simplysomeone who I love.
Also, I'm going to hold onto that love. Until I die.
I'm sorry. I had no choicebut to come back.
For Eskimos,
when someone they love dies,
they gather and talk aboutthat person for five days.
While they talk, they erase theirmemories of that person.
Afterwards, they nevertalk about that person again.
If they do, then that person's soulcan't rest in peace.
Let's talk about Ho-jin.
About everything you and I know.
Eun-soo.
And then never talkabout him again.
After you left to serve,
I begged Ho-jinto go over his place.
Stop it, Eun-soo.
It was about the end of June.It rained the whole day.
When I got there,his place was flooded in.
While we poured water outall day, Ho-jin said,
Feels like the world has flooded,and we're the only two left.
To raise money for your tuition,
did you know that he workedin a factory for two months?
I was worriedso I went to him,
and saw him limpingwhile carrying bricks.
I wanted to take him out of there,but I couldn't.
I thought he'd be more upsetif he knew I came,
so I couldn't.
No one knows.No one can know.
How we met.
How we loved.No one knows.
It was exactly on June 28th.
And it started rainingfrom the afternoon.
While pouring out the water,you said,
I wish the world swept away,and we were the only two left.
I couldn't bare watching you,and told you to stop,
but you silentlyscooped the water.
A man can never leave a woman,who overcame an obstaclewith him.
I worked at the factoryfor one and a half months.
It was a Saturday.You suddenly...
You came right before lunch.
After getting yelled at,I turned around,
and saw a girl with a yellowshirt walking away.
I also saw you that day.
I wanted to call you,I wanted to grab you,
But I couldn't.
Seeing me like that, I thoughtmake you upset.
I knew how you'd feel,so I couldn't call you.
Stop it.
Eun-soo. Whenever you laughedor became upset,
I was always with you.
So that's why
we're the same inside.You know better.
Stop it. Stop.
Look. Look at me, Eun-soo.
It's me. Can't you see?
I should've died then,but I couldn't.
I should've died, and be gone forever,but I couldn't.
Because of you. No one canlove you as much as me.
That's why I returned.
Remember this, right?
How could you not?
All the memories thatare hidden in our home
are proof that we'veloved each other until now.
Ho-jin.
Eun-soo.
You're all that I have.
Let's buy bananas.
I don't want to.
Why?
I don't like bananas.
But it's for our baby.
You're out of lotion, right?Should we buy it?
I brought your lunch.
Is it going well?
Yep.
I'm going to have an exhibition.I feel a lot better now.
That's great.Don't overwork yourself.
Okay.
What's wrong?
Because you're pretty.
Why do you keep laughing?
It's good to see youa lot happier now.
Does it show? Yae-joo.
I'm okay.Anyway, it feels strange.
I tried so hard to bring Dae-jin back,
but suddenly, I thought whatdifference would it make.
Since Dae-jin thought of meonly as a friend.
I'm sorry, Yae-joo.I didn't want to...
But Yae-joo, he's really Ho-jin.
I always felt my fatherwas with me after he died.
Even though I can't see him,
it feels the same with Ho-jin.He's really Ho-jin.
I know. That Dae-jin isn'tsomeone I can love.
He's someone else now.
And it's not like we canshare the same person.
It's a complicated fate.
But I'm glad to see Dae-jinhappy before I leave.
You two have to live happily.Mine and Dae-jin's worth.
I'll go say bye to Dae-jin...I mean Ho-jin before I leave.
Had it hardbecause of me, huh?
Because of who?Dae-jin or Ho-jin?
So you're studying abroad?
Yeah.
When will you come back?
If I do? Will you becomeDae-jin then?
Can I think of you asDae-jin and say something?
You're a rotten bastard.
Have a good life.
Hey. Whether you're Dae-jinor Ho-jin, give me a hug.
You really must not be Dae-jin.
Dae-jin never gave mea warm hug like this before.
One sec.
Hello? Oh, hi.Yes, it's Hwang Ho-jin.
You remembered.
Yes... So I'll be readyfor the exhibition
in about a week I think.
I'd like about two daysin advance to set it up.
Yes.
I see. Wouldn't just one bannerout in front be good enough?
And for the openingand closing ceremonies,
I'd like a sufficient.
It's because of traffic,
and I'd like to focus a loton the opening party.
Yes. Thank you.Bye.
To be honest, he's been braindead for too long.
And some of his body partsare rotten.
I'm sorry to tell you this,
but for the patient's sake,
I think it's goodto send him away.
The latest test resultsshow a lost of corneal reflexes.
Reflexes in the spinal cordhave been lost.
Even after the latest test,the patient's brain waves
were flat for 30 minutes.
With the test results as proof,we confirm Hwang Ho-jinas brain dead.
Hwang Ho-jin is now deceased.
Yes, I'll see you in a bit.
Okay.
- Please look around.- Thank you.
Ho-jin, I'll go homeand come back tonight.
Why? Not feeling well?Your face looks bad.
I just feel a bit dizzy.
Go get some rest then.
Eun-soo.
Why'd you come out?
I wanted to see you leave.Can you drive?
Of course.
Come here. I don't want youto leave.
I'll go rest a littleand come back.
When you go home...
call me.
Okay.
Boy, he scared me.
Go back in.
Go.
Who is it?
I have a package for you.
A package for you.Please sign here.
Thank you.
I thought you might needthe original so I'm returning it.
Even when I'm lying deadin my coffin,
I still won't be able tounderstand your sick love.
Before then, I hope I forget you.
Wouldn't just one bannerout in front be good enough?
Yes.
And for the openingand closing ceremonies,
I'd like a sufficientamount of time.
It's because of traffic,
and I'd like to focus a loton the opening party.
Yes. Thank you.Bye.
Like what Marcel Duchampintended to do with the toilet,
I wanted to make thingscommon to us closer to real life.
So there are a lot of images,like flowers and butterflies.
Eun-soo's Dandelions
I saw a girl today.
She was like the sunshineof September.
The moment I caught
all the sadnesswithin me disappeared.
I don't know how to explainthis strong feeling.
What are you so nervous about?
No, I'm not.
For someone who'sclueless about women,
I'm very curiousas to who she is.
I met my brother's woman.
- Sorry I'm late.- It's okay.
Dae-jin, right?
Dae-jin say hello toHan Eun-soo.
- The world...- Hi.
abandoned me.
Even the skies.
Today is the happiest dayof my brother's life.
After today,his life will be even happier.
Since Eun-soo will be with him.I'm also a happy person.
I'll be able to see Eun-soo forever.
From behind.
Ho-jin told me everythingabout his times with Eun-soo.
Ho-jin doesn't know women.
So I told him howto write love letters.
And through his letters,Eun-soo became happier.
Ho-jin said he's luckyto have a brother like me.
I'm a luckier guy.
Seeing that I haven't gone insane yet,living under the same roof with them.
To give a pureand fairy-tail like feeling,
and to make it pleasurable,was my intention.
Furniture is something that
people are very familiar with.
But they easily forgetits actual existence.
Dae-jin, don't you wanta girlfriend?
The best times are at your age.
I like it now.
Like what?
Fiddling with thatcar of yours in the garage?
Of course. Just with thatI'm happy enough.
Sometimes I want to justthrow it all away, but I can't.
I can't think of anything else,and I don't want to.
I think I'll belike this until I die.
Since it's next to me,
I like it. I can always see it,and feel it. I like this a lot.
You're here.
Did everything go well?
So are you okay now?
This piece. To make this,you stayed up for three days, huh?
Are you really okay?
Yes.
This is the door to heaven.
If I were to explain it,
I made it thinking that deathisn't a scary thing after all.
Think it gives offa pretty and warm feeling?
Yeah.
And this?
This is Alice in Wonderland.
I made it to be fun and cute,
while thinking of our baby.There's a mirror inside, too.
That'll look betterat our doorway.
Sounds good.Since it's blue, it'll feel fresh.
And we can put the CDs on it.
You haven't seen this, huh?
Yes.
Oh yeah, you saw thiswhile I was working on it.
I saw.
My brother...My kind brother...
You lived while sacrificingyour life for me.
But did you know this?That I loved Eun-soo first?
I loved her enoughto abandon myself.
But Eun-soo never knew.
All she thought of was you.
Yes, my brother.I'm not in this world anymore.
I'm the one who really died.
I'm going to become youand love Eun-soo now.
Eun-soo will think of youwhen she's with me,
while loving only you.
Ho-jin.
You can never forgive me, right?
Don't forgive me.Never.
Don't ever forgive me.
Ho-jin, I'm sorry.