Gengo is a human powered translation platform
that is breaking down language barriers.
For example, if you want to send an email overseas, you can get a translation in 2 hours or less!
All of our translators are real people
so you don't get terrible machine translations.
They are all pre-tested native speakers
who deliver natural, native sounding translations.
Short messages or facebook posts are completed within 10 minutes
and only cost a few cents.
You can order large amounts of translations through our API
Site changes and updates can be automatically ordered for you.
Even if you have thousands of product descriptions
Our worldwide network of over 5,000 native translators
Can quickly handle any amount of work.
The Internet has brought the world together but
there are still language barriers.
We combine crowdsourced translations and our API
to take that language barrier and bring it down.
At Gengo we have talented employees from all around the world.
Our small office might not fit everyone completely, but
we have amazing UX and visual designers who
can quickly show the world anything you create.
Our investors also support what we do and
Gengo is a great environment for doing high-impact work with talented staff
I expect great things from Gengo!
Gengo works with node.js, Postgres, and Python
and we're looking for talented web engineers who want to create new and exciting features.
If you're interested
join our international team
and let's break down the language barrier together!
I gave up learning Japanese myself
But I can survive in Japan thanks to Gengo