Identify all acute, obtuse, and right angles
in the image below.
So let's just remind ourselves
what an acute, obtuse, or right angle is.
An acute angle is an angle that
is less than 90 degrees.
And I'll right it right under the word acute.
A right angle is an angle that is
equal to 90 degrees, or who's measure
is equal to 90 degrees.
And obtuse angle
is an angle that is greater than 90 degrees,
greater than 90 degrees, and it is less than 180 degrees.
Or you could do it this way:
Greater than 90 degrees, or 90 degrees is
less than an obtuse angle.
And an obtuse angle is less than 180 degrees.
They don't ask us about this, but
is you have an angle that is
180 degrees, it forms a straight line.
And that really is called a straight angle.
So let's look at this diagram, and
let's start with the acute angles.
And I'll do the acute angles in purple.
Ones that we know are less than 90 degrees.
Well, you look over here
the only real information they've given
is they've marked this box right over here
that this angle right over here is a
right angle.
So actually, let's start with the right angle.
Because that actually might be a little
more interesting.
So they tell us that this right over here
is a right angle.
So we already know one of the right angles
is angle QAR.
Where A would be the vertex.
You could also call it angle RAQ.
So, angle QAR, QAR, hey actually tell us that
the measure is 90 degrees, now there's another
90 degree angle here, that is QAT
This angle right over here, angle QAT
and the reason why i know that angle QAt
is also right, if you take QAR which is this one
and combine it with QAT, you actually form a straight angle
all the way around like this
and so there some needs to be a 180 degrees
so, QAR is 90 degrees, QAT also has to be 90 degrees
anothe way to think about it, is so, is because
they're next to each other and has a ray and common
they are adjacent angle, and if u were put them
and if you look at their outer edges they actually form a straight angle
you will call this two angle,supplementary
or they will add up to 180 degrees
another definition of supplementary, they add up to 180 degrees
therefore, if one is 90, the other one has to be 90 degress
that all the way, now let's look at the acute angles
Cause that actually gives us a lot of information
Because of this entire angle, if QAT is 90 degrees, then any of the angle
that make up QAT have to be less than 90 degrees
for example, QAP, that angle right over
there, the measure of that angle has to be less than 90 degrees
because its part of this larger 90 degrees angle,
you have add that two right angle over here, that actually
90 degrees, so both of them has to be less than 90 degrees
so one acute angle is angle QAP,
and another cute angle is angle PAT
angle PAT, and once again, we know
that because we add this two angle together you get 90 degrees
So each of them have to be less than 90 degrees
assuming that this angle are zero degrees
now there any other acute angle right over here
or another angle that looks acute is angle RAS, angle RAS
an the reason that we can feel pretty good
that it is less than 90 degrees is because
if you keep this line, if AQ is just a ray right now
but if u extend all the way, let say u have some
mythological point over there called X, angle RAX
would be 90 degrees, so RAX is less than that
so RAX has to be less that 90 degrees
and i think we got all the acute angles here
we got the two right angles here
now we have to think about the obtuse angle
so it was more than 90 degrees and less than 180 degrees
so one of the obtuse angle, if you went from
Q, QAS, or SAQ is definitely an obtuse angle
cause it contains 90 degree angle rather than its even wider than that
so, SAQ, angle SAQ is definitely obtuse
i'd be tempted to say SAP, but SAP is a straight angle
if you went all the way around like this a 180 degress
that would be a straight angle, that's not officially
obtuse angle, i notice, this called a straight angle
because it forms from a straight lines but two
rays, two edges of the angle
forms a straight line, so not going to include SAP there
now, another obtuse angle, this in a different color
this RAP, angle RAP, once again it contains RAQ in it
which is 90 degrees which is even wider that that
and let's see, RAT is a straight angle, so for all purposes
we will not consider that obtuse.
And, have i found everything? am im not missing something?
that one, would be straight angles. Oh wait, i just saw
one more, of course, you also have this angle over here
a big blank spot, and i wasn't paying attention to it
you also have this angle TAS
and the reason why we know that it's more than 90 degrees is
once again we have our mythological point X over here
that we just continue, QA in this direction
we would know that this is a 90 degree and TAS is opening up more
than 90 degree angle,
so TAS is also obtuse,
and i think i've got all of them now
Let me see.
Yup, we're done.