Subtitles are available in several languages
Sixty-nine year-old Palestinian Leila Khaled, oncea medical student, became a resistance fighter
for the PFLP movement (the Popular Front for theLiberation of Palestine) and with others hijacked an
aeroplane in 1969. She was convicted and laterreleased in an exchange deal.
Forced to flee her home in Haifa in the 1948Catastrophe, she famously demanded the pilot
of hijacked flight TWA840 to fly over Haifaso she could see her hometown, inaccessible
to her after the creation of Israel.
Leila continues to be a symbol of Palestinianarmed resistance, while to Israel she is a
convicted and unrepentant terrorist.
She now lives with her husband and 2 sonsin Jordan; I met her during her recent visit
to Gaza in a PFLP office.
Looking at what happened recently in Gazawith Israel's Operation Pillar of Cloud, the
nature of the resistance force against thestate of Israel during this time, I think
surprised a lot of people, even maybe Gazans.And it seemed that there was an ability
to repel Israel to some extent. So my questionis in today's context, is resistance strategically
or symbolically useful?
It's always strategic. Because when there'soccupation, there is always resistance. And
this is a fundamental equation. History taughtus that freedom and liberation cannot be achieved
without facing reactionary violence (exceptby revolutionary resistance). And this is
guaranteed by the international law. The eighthitem of the United Nations Charter says people
under oppression and occupation have the rightto resist, including armed struggle. So we
are defending ourselves and as you said, Israelwas the first one to be shocked by the resistance
itself.
Our people, our factions learnt from [the]last war in 2008, that they have to prepare
themselves for another attack because thewar did not end. This is a battle now and
we are proud of the resistance and our people.
The main thing [is] that resistance unitedthe people in spite of the division. While
Negotiations divided people. And this is oneof the main achievements. This means that
the leaderships of Hamas and Fatah shouldabide by the attitude of our people, whether
inside Gaza, in the West Bank, in all [of]Palestine, in [the] Diaspora. All our masses
were [in] the streets in different countrieswhere they are, even in foreign countries,
saying one thing: we are with the resistance.
[For] Israel this is not the first time tohave [an] excursion and attack against our
people, whether in the West Bank or in Gazaor in Sabra and Shatila and Lebanon and everywhere.
Do you expect our people to go, throw roseson the planes which killed our children? No.
Resistance is something human.
What about the French revolution? This isfrom Europe. Now you're asking about the people
in Europe. But let them think of what theNazis did in Europe. Destroyed Europe. Fifty
million casualties. That was in Europe. Andthe people resisted [Nazism] and it was defeated.
Are we waiting for...?
Nazism, yes?
Yes. They defeated Nazism. Are we waitingfor the Zionists to launch a third World War?
I think it's important to think of that. Andthink that fascists and Nazis and the Zionists
cannot be defeated except by resistance, withall its means, including armed struggle.
What does the resistance (the Palestinianarmed resistance) have to do with Islam?
Is there any relation with Islam?
It called for resistance of injustice,whoever inflict[s] atrocities upon our people.
Looking at the successful UN bid, I personallysee this as a consolidation of the two-state
resolution to the injustice. So you famouslyasked the pilot to fly over Haifa to see your
homeland. So my question is to you, what ofthe one-state solution? Do you support it?
If so, why? And if so, how? How? How doesone get there?
Well, we in [the] PFLP, in our programme.There is a transitional period to achieve
the strategic goal of our struggle. And theprogramme that all factions [that] were united
in [the] PLO — [the] right [of] return,right of self-determination, [the] building
our own state with Jerusalem [as] its capital.These are the goals of our struggle as a transitional
period to establish democratic Palestine.
And I think that this is realistic also. Butwe can never, and we don't, accept the solution
of the Americans, who are the supporters ofour occupants. That two-state solution means
that we give up seventy-eight percent of ourland. And how? The core issues of the whole
thing (of the Palestinian cause) lies in two:the land (to be sovereign over [it]) and the
return of the refugees. Any solution thatdoesn't deal with [these] two issues, I think
that it [wouldn't] last long.
[The] Oslo Accords proved that it's a failurefor both sides who signed and who accepted
this signature. But at the same time we believein our people, we believe in the will of our
people to practice their rights, the rightsthat were recognised also by the international
community in the United Nations.
So thinking of [a] two-state solution meansthat we have twelve percent of the land. This
is not Palestine. Palestine is the historicalPalestine. I'm from Haifa. That one from Akka.
That one from Jaffa. Those people have theright to go back to their homelands. And it's
guaranteed also by international law.
Thank you very much, indeed.
Most welcome.
Thank you.
You're from Britain?
Yup. It's nice to meet you.
When you go there, ask them: if anybodyattacks their homes would they smile in front
of their occupants? I don't think so.
This video's production was made possibleby Gaza Report's funders
Visit GazaReport.com for more insightinto the situation afflicting Gaza
English subtitles byHarry Fear