This film contains graphic images.
Viewer discretion is advised.
On Thursday, the 8th of November
Six days before it launched Operation Pillar of Cloud
Israel killed 13-year-old Ahmed Younes Abu Dagga
Also known as Hamid,
He was killed right here
while he was playing football with his friends.
He died on the way to hospital
This man, Saleh, witnessed Hamid’s death.
Hamid was shot in his stomach
and he ran towards the steps of his home.
We took him to the hospital in a car
But he died on the way.
At the time, my crew and I were
filming a few hundred meters away
Near the Israeli-imposed no-go military zone
Investigating an incursion into Gaza.
This is the buffer zone.
We are greeted with the sounds of
helicopters and Israeli drones.
This is an Israeli tank, part of that incursion,
Just hundreds of meters away from Hamid’s home.
We heard live fire at the time
Hamid was killed and ran to cover.
We had no idea Israel had killed an innocent.
I visited Hamid’s school to speak to two boys
who were playing with him when he was killed.
On Thursday we were playing football and suddenly
I heard Hamid screaming and
shouting, “My stomach, my stomach!”
And then we saw him run to his
home while holding his stomach.
He started to call out for his mum.
His brother was there who started
asking us, What’s wrong with Hamid?”
So I answered him that they shot him in his stomach.
He was shocked and said, “You mean Hamid?!”
I answered, “Yes!” then the car came to take him.
As recent history has shown, no where
in Gaza is safe for Palestinians
But Hamid’s family home in Abasan, Khan Yunis is just a few
hundred meters from the military buffer zone with Israel.
Its horizons under constant domination
by Israel’s surveillance balloons.
It’s one of the least secure places to live in Gaza
But for the large Abu Dagga family,
it’s simply always been their home.
It was my shift that night at the hospital.
Suddenly, we heard the noise of shelling and shooting because
the hospital is close to the east, near the boarder with Israel.
After five minutes, a casualty arrived to the hospital.
He was a child, and we immediately started treating him.
When we took him, we could see that he appeared to be dead.
We massaged his heart and gave him drugs like
adrenalin and a drip to try to restart his
heart to beat again or to make him breathe
again, to bring him back to life,
But unfortunately the child was
injured directly in his heart.
Ahmed was more than a brother to me.
He was my friend.
I spent most of my time with him.
We used to play football together in the streets
and always used to play Playstation together.
We were together most of the time.
What happened affected me a lot.
I feel my heart is empty.
Even yesterday, I had my friends visiting
me at home and when they wanted to leave,
I accidently said, “Hamid, Ahmed, show them downstairs!”
I forgot that he was dead.
May his soul rest in peace.
I said to myself, “We put our trust
in God, the best of planners.”
Near Hamid’s home, there’s also a sniper outpost.
Although a Hamas official initially reported
that a helicopter shooting killed Hamid,
It’s not clear whether it was shrapnel
from a sniper or helicopter bullet,
or even shrapnel from a tank shelling that was responsible.
This is just another incident of a suspicious Palestinian
child casualty as a result of Israeli force.
We were surprised by the injury because there was no bullet.
When there is a gunshot, there is
an entry wound and an exit wound,
but the child had only two very small holes on
the right side and the left side of his torso,
on both sides of his body.
This proves that it was not a gunshot,
but shrapnel that killed Hamid,
due to a shelling and the shrapnel
entered his chest directly.
It hit his heart, and when we examined
him, we found two very small holes,
two millimeters in size, on both sides.
Here in the hospital, we deal with the children's
injuries with our very limited treatment capabilities.
Our limited ability is one of our biggest problems
because here in the hospital we are suffering from
a shortage of the most basic medical supplies.
Mohammad was another boy playing
football with Hamid when he was killed,
I first spoke to his parents
Hamid was here with us, and then suddenly, in seconds,
we were surprised, he was gone, he was dead.
My child was with him, I felt bad because my child was
in the same place, may Ahmed’s soul rest in peace.
I ask the international community to stand
up for the rights of Gaza’s children.
No one in this world cares about the
children or people here in Gaza.
We ask God to finish this occupation,
God willing, as soon as possible.
May Ahmed rest in peace in Heaven.
Hamid came to my home and invited
me to play football with him.
I accepted.
Before we left my home, he asked me to take photos of him
So I took photos of him and he
asked me to put them on Facebook.
After the afternoon prayer, I went to his home,
and we played football from 3 until 4 pm.
This is Hamid
Suddenly, we heard shooting and shelling
and Hamid fell down as he passed the ball.
I started screaming, saying, “Get down, there is shooting!”
Hamid went to the ground while our other friends ran away.
He started crying and I started calling for his brothers
Then suddenly, he stood up, saying,
“Oh, my stomach, my stomach!”
He started running towards his home and I screamed
to his brother, “Come, Hamid has been shot!”
Then he started running around his home, screaming.
His brother came and told me to find
a car to take him to the hospital.
My child, Mohammed, has his exams these days.
Whenever I ask him to study hard to succeed,
he opens his books and then starts crying.
“I can’t, I can’t study.”
All the time, he holds his mobile phone
and looks at the photo he took of Hamid.
I told him to focus on his studies,
to pray, and I said to him,
“Look how God chose Hamid to be a martyr,
and go to Heaven. He was lucky!”.
He always answers, “I can’t, I can’t
because what happened affected me a lot.”
He’s all the time crying and looking at Hamid’s photo.
Now the boys play with Hamid’s football, but without Hamid
Human Rights Watch told me they didn’t have the
resources in Gaza to investigate the killing of Hamid.
Hamid’s killing was, of course, barely
reported by Western media agencies.
The BBC ran one limited article in which Hamid’s
killing was reported as just an unverified,
alleged incident of collateral damage.
Days after it killed Hamid, Israel launched
its November operation Pillar of Cloud,
claiming it was responding to rocket
fire from Gazan militant groups
Rocket fire that killed no one.
After Hamid’s death, in the weekend
just preceding the operation,
Israel killed two more Palestinian children when
it struck near a funeral parade in North Gaza.
The truth is that the timeline of the recent war
started with Israel’s killing of Hamid, buried here.
This was Hamid’s classroom.
A memorial wreath stands on his chair.
Just before he was killed, he was
sitting tests in Geography, and Maths
We all went to school together and
went home as a group every day.
Every Thursday, we used to play football together.
Sometimes he would invite me, sometimes I would
invite him, and we used to go out a lot together.
My brother was a religious fan of Real Madrid.
He used to download the videos of all
their games and goals to watch them play.
Playing football was his biggest hobby.
He always dreamed of becoming a football star.
He always pretended he was Cristiano Ronaldo and he was
killed while he was wearing a Real Madrid t-shirt.
Glorious is God: he lived loving football
and he died while he was playing it.
What can a child care about
except his school and having fun?
These are the only things children think of.
He only cared about wearing his Real
Madrid t-shirt, his Real Madrid boots,
grabbing his football, and then going to play.
He did not even really care about his studies.
Hamid even said on Thursday morning,
“I have a big responsibility, I have two exams on Saturday!”
And Israelis thought that he was
thinking about shooting rockets?!
Hamid’s mother was motionless with grief.
Some relatives wanted to show me
Hamid’s bedroom and possessions:
his bed,
backpack, and mobile.
His schoolbooks,
football boots,
the t-shirt Hamid was wearing when he was martyred.
The weapons they use are unbelievable.
We have received many injuries of
this kind, not only with children
Ahmed is one of them.
They’re all the same.
There are very small holes in the chest,
stomach, really, anywhere in the body.
Sometimes two holes.
But when we resuscitate them, and
take them to perform surgery,
we see shocking damage, including
lacerations in the intestines.
Wherever the injury is, we see incredible damage.
So we saw injuries similar to Ahmed’s
back during Operation Cast Lead.
Since Hamid was killed, in Gaza alone,
a further 61 Palestinian children have
been killed by Israeli state violence.
I went to Hamid’s funeral parade.
The pupils from his preparatory school arrived.
Glory to our faithful martyrs.
The local police force also paid their respects.
I say to the world, you accepted agreements
and protocols to protect Human Rights
during wartime and during peacetime,
like the Geneva Convention
and the jurisdiction of the International
Criminal Court in the Hague.
This international community is sitting
silently when it comes to Israeli violations
against the Palestinian children and people.
They are being killed day and night by the Israelis
who think that no power in the world can stop them.
To the soldier that shot my son, he has
to know that he killed an innocent child.
Of course, he has his own children.
How would he feel if he saw his son being causelessly killed
while he was playing football with his friends?
What’s the crime he committed?
Why are our children being unduly
killed in front of their homes?
We ask God to end this occupation.
I call on President, Barak Obama,
who just won a second term,
the new president of the USA that
speaks in the name of freedom:
Do the American people accept for a child to be killed
while he was playing football in front of his home?
If this happened there, in America, the
whole world would stand against it.
If this child has been killed inside Israel,
would the state of Israel have stayed silent?
Why does the international community continue its silence?
This is a massacre of children inside Gaza.
The reckless killing or murder of this
13-year-old Real Madrid-supporting child
constitutes a prima facie war crime
committed by the state of Israel.
One day the International Criminal
Court will call for witnesses:
My crew and I will be there.
My message to the world and to everyone listening,
pay attention to our plight.
We are poor and oppressed people.
We have lived 65 years suffering from
occupation, killing and colonizing.
God willing, people of the world will start
to care and put a stop to all of this.
What can I say to the Israeli
soldier who killed my brother?
They are not human because they killed
a little child playing football.
What kind of terrorism did he commit?
They say they attack terrorists and rocket firers.
My brother Hamid was playing
football, not launching a rocket.
They think that when they attack our children
that we will be weakened. It is the opposite.
They raise hatred in our hearts.
Now, don’t you think that Hamid’s friends
will hate the Israelis more and more?
We are like them, we are all humans!
What did he do for them to attack him?!
Those children will grow up and
the hate will grow up with them.
God willing, the Israelis will leave our
land and the occupation will end soon.
I swear to God that they will not stay here.
The end is coming soon.
As a doctor, as a children’s surgeon, I want to say
that we are a people of peace and that we love peace.
And my message to the world is please stand by the
people of Palestine so that we can live in peace,
so our children and their children
can live together in peace.
Why do the people of the world live in freedom
while the children of Palestine do not know the
meaning of freedom or sleep peacefully at night?
So this is my message:
stand by the children and the people of Palestine.
We should stop the killing.
Visit GazaReport.com for more insight
into the situation afflicting Gaza.
This film’s production was made
possible by Gaza Report’s funders.