[What's New in Firefox] It's now easier and faster to get where you want to go with the latest Firefox.
With the redesigned Home page you can now easily access and navigate to your most commonly used menu options.
Like downloads, bookmarks, history, add-ons, sync and settings.
[New Tab Page] We've also added improvements to your New Tab page.
With the New Tab page, you can now easily navigate to your most recent and frequently visited sites in one click.
To start using the New Tab page, create a new tab by clicking the '+' at the top of your browser.
The New Tab page will now display thumbnails of your most recently and frequently visited websites from your Awesome Bar history.
You can customize your New Tab page by dragging the thumbnails around to change the order.
Click on the pushpin to lock the site into place, or the 'X' button to remove a site.
You can also click the 'grid' icon in the top right of the page to go back to the blank new Tab page.
Get the latest Firefox now and start using these new features today!