[adding new users]
This is Chrome.
This is your Chrome,
and your friend's, Chrome,
and your roommate's, Chrome,
each with a different set of bookmarks, apps, extensions, and other settings.
If you share a computer with other people,
you may not want your Chrome stuff getting mixed up with everyone else's.
Now, you can add new users to Chrome,
so you can keep everyone's, stuff separate
on the same computer.
A badge in the corner makes it easy to tell everyone's, Chrome windows apart,
and clicking the badge makes it easy to flip between users.
Each user can also sign in to Chrome to bring their Chrome stuff to all their other devices.
To add a new user to Chrome, go to Options (or Preferences on a Mac),
click Personal Stuff, and select, "Add new user."