You are a miracle
You are a blessing from above
You brought joy to my soul
And pleasure to my eyes
In my heart I can feel it
An unexplainable feeling
Being a father
The best thing that I could ever ask for
Just thinking of you, makes me smile
Holding you, looking in your eyes
I'm so grateful for having you
And everyday I pray
I pray that you'll find your way
You know I love you
I love you
My little girl, my little girl
I ask God to bless you, and protect you always
You're like a shining star
So beautiful you are
My baby girl
You light up my world
I pray that I'll get the chance
To be around and watch you grow
And witness your first steps
And the first time when you will call me dad
Just thinking of you, makes me smile
Holding you, looking in your eyes
I'm so grateful for having you
And everyday I pray
I pray that you'll find your way
You know I love you
I love you
My little girl, my little girl
I ask God to bless you, and protect you always
I could spend hours watching you
You're so innocent, so lovely and so pure
Oh, God I can not express my gratitude
Ohh, but i'll raise her good, cause all I want is to please you
And now I pray, You'll guide her ways forever
You know I love you
I love you
My little girl, my little girl
I ask God to bless you, and protect you always