(song playing)
(ticking noise)
hmmm
what is that mysterious ticking noise?
Not over here, not over there... hmmmm.
kind of catchy.
snape snape severus snape
dumbledore
snape snape
severus snape
dumbledore
snape snape snape severus snape
ron ron ron weasley
ron ron
snape snape severus snape
dumbledore
hermione
severus
dumbledore
ron
harry potter harry potter
harry potter harry potter thats me
hermione
harry snape harry snape harry snape harry snape
dumbledore!
hermione!
dumbledore
harry potter
i'm harry potter
i'm harry potter harry harry potter
Singing our song, all day long at Hogwarts!
I found the source of the mysterious ticking!
It's a pipe bomb!
(laughs evily)
Voldemort, Voldemort ohhh Voldie Voldie Voldie Voldemort.
(song plays)