Hello! I am very glad to see you!
Today I am going to draw a water drop.
And do not leave because at the end of the
tutorial I am going to show you 2 paintings
to give examples of how you can use a water
drop in a work of art.
To start I sketch the shape of the drop and
go over it.
In a transparent object, the light behaves
in a particular way:
Lets say that the beams of light come from
the top-left,
then the darkest part would be precisely on
this part, as the light would go through the
drop and illuminate the bottom-right.
And here, if anything, will be a little reflexion.
Down here then, would be the most light.
I start shading the darkest part of the drop.
I«m using a slightly hard lead: an H
It would cast a shadow on this side, but in
the middle of it, would be a light.
Then with a brush I smudge the graphite for
a more even finish.
I reinforce the shadow in the vicinity of
the drop,
and then smudge it.
With a kneaded eraser I pull some reflexions.
And then with a white pencil, pastel like,
I reinforce the lights.
It is dry. A sort of chalk.
I darken a little further.
This is not a drawing paper and is leaving
me black spots. Even after smudging you can
still see them.
Therefore I sharpen my eraser like an ant
eater [chuckles], and I pull the dots.
Then, if I left some white spots, I fill them
in carefully with the lead.
It should be smooth and uniform, to look like
a water drop.
I want to give it even more light!
The beauty of drawing on a toned paper,
is that the lights really stand out.
Specially if they go with good shadows.
I will extend it further up,
although this part is going to be flatter
and without reflexions.
I hope you liked it. That is finished!
And as promised, I will show you 2 paintings:
This is an oil on canvas called Freshness.
It is a pretty simple one.
While this... does not have a water drop...
it has about 320 drops!
I would really like to know what do you think
about it. You can write me in the comments
section of the video.
And if you liked the tutorial, please give
it a LIKE and subscribe to my channel.
You know where to follow me, and where are
the links.
See you next Tuesday!