Patani students campaign for peace on the International Day of Peace.
On the international Day of Peace
this is a small campaign by members of
Thailand's Federation of Southern Students.
They come together to campaign for peace.
We will display our cards of words.
To let people suggest
what peace means for each of them.
I've seen what the students do today,
of their activities for peace.
They suggest peaceful solution
to the conflict and violence
in the three southern provinces
I myself have joined a campaign group
for peace in the south.
This is therefor something
I'd like to see students participate.
Because part of the problem
comes from some young people and students.
If they join this campaign,
it will offer us the best way-out.
Peace for me means no problem.
But of course, there's no society
without problem.
What we have to do is to try
to reduce the problem as best we can.
When it happens, peace begins.
It begins when we respect each others.
Peace begins
when we understand each others.
I think this is good,
that we let people express themselves.
They can tell us how they think of peace.
When we don't have a chance like this,
we could forget peace
or that such word exists.
Today is the International Day of Peace.
I am one of those people
who want global peace.
Especially in the three southern provinces.
May God protect us and give us,
people in the south, peace,
which we've been deprived of
for many years.
The government should understand that
we are under the law which is not
by international standard.
I'd like the government to consider this
as well as peace.
Patani wants peace.
Subtitles by the Amara.org community