Brought to you by the PKer team @ www.Viki
Episode 11
She talks in her sleep now . I'm never going to get sleep. What the heck am I going to do ?
That's right
I spent the whole night with Seung Jo.
You mean that when I wake up, Seung Jo will be in the same bed as me.
Seung Jo.
It's time to wake up.
Did you sleep well?
Good morning.
It was a disaster sleeping with you last night.
Why?
Because of your terrible sleeping habits.
What are you talking about? I'm a totally still sleeper.
Stop kidding me.
Wear this one.
I don't want to.
Are you just going to stare at me like that?
Ah, sorry...
You act like it's your own home.
Really?
Is that so?
en español
it feels different when I'm staying in Seung Jo's apartment.
It feels like we're living together.
What kind of fantasy are you having now?
Don't overdo it.
He's never been late for work.
What's the matter?
" Oh Han Ni and Baek Seung Jo spent the night together"
Did they really spend the night together?
You know that girl from the tennis club.
Oh her?
Hey! Baek Seung Jo! Since when did you...?Lucky you
Tell us, tell us the details. So how was it?
I said to give us some details.
Mother!
What's your problem?
Why are you calling me "Mother"? You're embar . . .
Mother!
How can you tell so quickly?
The way you disguise yourself so thatone can tell in one look...The way you disguise yourself so thatone can tell in one look...
please do something about it!
And what do you think you're doing coming all the way to my school and causing all this?
Ha Ni, how are you feeling, after being sick and all?
I'm alright now.
Really? That's a relief.
Alright...So how was it?
Huh?
How was it...?
Your voice is very loud.
It was nothing special.
Ah...really?
Seung Jo is that type of man? That's unbelievable.
Oh yes! Ha Ni, did you give him the chocolates?
Right! The chocolates!
The chocolates..
I lost the chocolates!
What do you mean you "lost" them?
It is a sign of love.
Where did it go?
What to do? Baek Seung Jo's chocolates!
Do you see me volumizing the ends?! Isn't it off the hook! I'm really good at it!
I'll make sure your hair isn't damaged and-- Welcome!
Bong Joon Gu...
What? Slept together?
Baek Seung Jo and Oh Ha Ni?
My feet just dragged me here...
When I spoke to Ha Ni not long ago she didn't tell me anything like that.
There is no way Ha Ni won't tell me the big news.
Weren't you mistaken and went around in the rain for nothing?
From a kiss to sleeping together...that's great!
Now everything is over. It's over.
Ah... Joon Gu... Joon... Bong Joon G...
Nothing happened you said?
Yeah...
A man and a woman spent a whole night together,
How is it that nothing happened?
Nothing happened.
Can I tell her?Jung Ju Ri
You're early today.
The school's a bit talkative today.
You know nothing happened.
True..
There is no way.
Seung Jo...
Do you want to get dinner together after class?
I think I'm going to die because of this upcoming test.
Min Ah, you don't study for exams?
There's no way I can study for all 12 subjects.
If there's no way for Dok Go Min Ah, then it's absolutely impossible for Oh Ha Ni.
Fine, I've made a decision. I'm only going to study for English.
Only English?
Why?
It's the only subject I'm taking with Seung Jo, so if I fail that as well, then it's all over.
No matter what I get on the other subjects, I'm definitely going to pass English.
Oh Ha Ni, you are now in study mode.
Ah! I don't have much time. I'm leaving.
It's raining...
Aigoo. Why is it raining like this?
Oh! Really.
Oh, aren't you the one who works at the restaurant?
Oh right! What are you doing here? Are you waiting for someone?
Looks like you're not in a good mood.
It's not that I'm in a bad mood.
I am trying to give up my love
My heart feels like it's breaking apart.
What do you mean give up on love?
You shouldn't give up on love.
No, certainly not.
I've only been following for the past few years.
I never even went on a date with her.
This is a very serious matter.
Have you tried confessing your feelings?
Confessing?
Oh, so you don't know how to confess.
Look
This is how you do it.
You grab the girl like this.
You pull her like this,
push her up against a wall, and when she looks up,
then you say,
" If you can forget me then go ahead," and suddenly kiss her.
If you do it like this
the girl won't even be able to think
When they're flustered,
they'll suddenly have feelings for you!
That's how you confess.
That's right! A confession.
I won't die from it, so
let's try it.
Hyung-nim, thank you!
Oh right!
Timing is very important thing, timing!
Brought to you by the PKer team @ www.Viki
Ha Ni, you're here!
Your face doesn't look good.
Even when it's exam week,
you two look fine.
Usually,
you're supposed to take tests with your every day capabilities.
If you try to study it all at once, then how could they test what you've learned?
Then the test would just be some kind of photographic memory test or something.
Isn't that right Seung Jo?
How did you do on the other tests?
So so.
I will really do my best on the test, so that we can
attend the same class next semester together...
This English test is famous for being hard. What are you going to do?
Weren't you hitting it pretty close in the last test too?
Ha Ni,
it would be better if you attend this same class for another year.
You know that girl you saw before,
Ji Yeon, who Seung Jo and I were tutoring.
She's going to be attending our school.
How about you attend the same class next year?
Ha Ni,
why are you glaring at me like that?
Your eyes will burst.
This is the first time
I'm taking a test together with Seung Jo.
Seung Jo looks greatest when he is solving questions.
Why are you not finishing?
I'm done.
There is still 40 minutes left! Already?
Seung Jo, wait for a second.Let's go out together.
It was surprisingly easy, right?
Oh, you didn't even write anything! What are you going to do?
I came because
I have something to tell you.
Oh, really?
What is it?
Even if you don't tell me anything,
I know everything.
You probably don't know how much my heart ached that night.
But no matter how much I thought about it, it didn't seem right.
To be honest,
I can't bring myself
to give up on you Ha Ni.
But still,
once a guy pulls out his sword, he's got to see it till the very end.
I'm just going to be understanding about everything that's happened.
Ha Ni, I
thought about giving you up,
but it won't go the way I want.
You don't have to be sorry.
How is it your fault?
It's that fool Baek Seung Jo that's trying to seduce you!
Quite soon
I'm going to beat the crap out of that Baek Seung Jo.
So,
forget everything
and let's start over,
Ha Ni.
Ha Ni?
Ha Ni, are you sleeping?!
Hey!
Hey, Bong Joon Gu.
Hurry.
What?
Hey, Bong Joon Gu. What are you trying to start over?
That night, nothing happened between them.
He didn't touch a hair on her.
Really?
Yeah, really.
Man, that Baek Seung Jo is a real gentleman!
Wow, you're even complimenting Baek Seung Jo.
Ha Ni!
Let's go!
Oh Ha Ni.
Let's start dating.
Hey, Gi Tae,
when did you arrive?
You've come back?
Hey, go and practice.
What are you saying so early in the morning? Ha Ni's got someone.
It's not a joke.
I am Kyung Su's friend, and starting next semester
I'll be attending the same school
I'm Kim Gi Tae.Nice to meet you.
Since you guys are here already, say hello.
He is your Tennis club Sunbae,
His name is Kim Gi Tae. Greet him.
- Hello.- Hello
If you're done, go and practiceGo, go.
You're a funny guy.
Since when do you know Ha Ni,
that you want to go out with her as soon as you met her?
Haven't you heard?
Oh Ha Ni and Baek Seung Jo.
I know.
Ha Ni likes Baek Seung Jo, right?
Ever since high school, I've watched over those two.
Huh?
Then, why?
Especially since the two of you aren't dating,
that means that I too,
have a chance.
Yes? Suddenly...
Was it too fast?
OK, good.
This week-end,
let's go on a date.
You need to get to know me as well.
That's how it's going to be.
Then, see you later.
I'm leaving.
Before leaving, let's have a game.
Next time.
She totally froze up.
Hey Ha Ni.Isn't he really good looking?
When we first joined this school,Gi Tae and I were very popular with the female Sunbaes,
Him for his looks, and me for my charisma.
But that Gi Tae, to you . . .
You punks! You won't go practice?!
It feels weird.
I was very surprised.
This is the first time in my life I have been confessed to this way.
This is amazing.
Is it real? Did it really happen? Did he ask you out?
Isn't this the first time in your life? You've always been the one doing the chasing!
I heard he was a sunbae? Who might he be? I'm curious!
How is he? Is he tall? What about his looks?! Is he good looking?
Well, a little.
You're embarrassed! He must be good looking.
Hey, Baek Seung Jo knows too?
Right right.Does Baek Seung Jo know too?
I'm saying, Ha Ni got confessed to by a really cool guy.
Really?
So?
So if you don't do something, Ha Ni and that guy might get together...
You're not worried?
You sure do get excited over nothing.
That's what you wanted to say?
I'm not worried.
Oh? really?
He wants to date you?!
Yes.
But it's not a big deal.
Omo!
Who would like you?
How can he be just like his brother!?
The thing I've been fearing has finally come.
Someone as cute as Ha Ni...
I knew I would lose her like this soon enough.
This is all because Seung Jo is dragging his feet.
Stop it dear. Don't get so worked up.
Stuff like this is all the free will of the person.
What kind of guy is he?
It's a sunbae and he's one year older than me. We're in the same grade.
Sunbae?!? My god the most dangerous person is a male Sunbae!
I don't really remember his face.
Ha Ni, haven't you been tricked by a player?
You're all naive and go around smiling at any old guy right?!
No, dad. I'm not like that.
I have to do whatever I can.
I can't leave it like this.
It's gotten much bigger than I expected.
Today has been eventful.
Still, he confessed to me knowing I like Seung Jo
He's a bold person.
How does he look?
I didn't get to take a good look.
How did his face look?
Brought to you by the PKer team @ www.Viki
Hey you.
I'll see you later.
Oh Ha Ni.
Why did you come...?
You can't forget my face.
So I came to show you my face.
Hey, Baek Seung Jo is working part time at a restaurant?
Huh?Yes.
Last time I went, you were there too.
I heard that you went there everyday.
I went a few times
You know, I'm pretty damn smart too.
Of course I wasn't as visible due to the all around perfect Baek Seung Jo.
Then are you approaching me because of Seung Jo...
Of course I was provoked a bit by Baek Seung who's good at everything whether it's studying or tennis.
As I was worrying about Baek Seung Jo,
it's true that I saw you following him around everywhere.
Suddenly without me even realizing it, little by little,
I started looking at you.
Ah, yes.
You would still step forward despite being rejected by Baek Seung Jo over and over again.
You could say I was touched by that, Oh Ha Ni.
Anyway I was pulled towards you.
Hey, just go out with me.
Don't waste your precious youth on Baek Seung Jo, when you don't even know if he will turn around towards you.
Have an amusing campus life with me. What do you think?
Even so, I...
I was wondering who it was. It's Gi Tae Sunbae!
Oh, Yoon Hae Ra.
Do you know each other?
I met him often during the tennis matches.
But do you know each other?
I am going out with Oh Ha Ni.
Ah, that's not true.
So, you're going to give up Seung Jo now?
Of course!
Don't just say whatever you want!
Before Kyung Su Sunbae, and now Gi tae Sunbae. You're so popular Oh Ha Ni!
You suit each other well.
See you later at the club room.
Ok.
See you later.
Sunbae, continue what you were doing.
Make sure to keep it moving straight forward!
I'll be going first.
See you later.
Oh, I can't believe it!
His face is about a... 85%
He seems to have a bright personality and he's enthusiastic.
If he's a law major...
A future politician or lawyer?
Mother.
Oh!
This...
Did you possibly go to school to see that sunbae?
He's Seung Jo's rival, so we need to analyze him real well and plan something.
The way I see it, this guy is much cuter than Seung Jo.
What to do?
If this guy takes your heart,
What would I do?!
Mother.
Not to worry.
I will always think of Seung Jo only.
Ha Ni.
I'll go reject him right now!
I'm deeply touched!
Oh wait! No, don't go.
Ha Ni you shouldn't reject him.
Yes?
Let's try to make Seung Jo jealous.
Eh! That's impossible.
No, no.
He may be acting so cocky all the time,
but just wait and see. Seung Jo will definitely feel himself being pulled towards you!
Because you're always next to him,
he is relaxed and doing other things!
But if you suddenly show him another side of you, he will notice his feelings for you.
Will it be alright to use such a dangerous plan like this?
Will it be okay?
Will Seung Jo really be jealous?
You don't have to be thinking like that.
Do well.
Gi Tae sunbae is smart, and is very popular with the ladies.
But seeing that he has an interest in you,
he does have really unique taste then.
That's a relief. Then again, one man's trash is another man's treasure.
What are you talking about?
Though I'm like this, aside from you, I'm quite popular with the guys.
Maybe he's got a bad eye or a real weirdo.
That person is just as smart as you are
and as good looking as you.
Most of all, compared to you, he is really nice to girls.
I'm in a good mood,
because Ha Ni thinks of me like that.
Well Baek Seung Jo, seeing how it is, why don't you pass Ha Ni on to me?
So it was you Sunbae. There's no need to pass her on. It's not like she belongs to me. Do as you please.
What did he say? I can't believe him.
Gi Tae Sunbae
Oh yes princess?
Where are we going on this Sunday's date?
I'm okay with anything.
Whether it's the mountain or the sea, I'll go anywhere.
Sunbae, Congratulations. I'm serious!
Seung Jo!
If it goes on like this, I'm really going to cheat on him!
I won't regret it!
What would you like to order?
One ice tea.
Do you want to kill time with that again?
Today, I didn't came here to see you.
I'm here for an other appointment.
Ha Ni, I'm sorry.
On the way here, there was a traffic jam.
Did you wait long?
No, I just arrived here, too.
Oh, hi Baek Seung Jo. One coffee for me, with ice.
Yes. Ice tea and iced coffee.
Wait for a moment please.
Today, it's finally the much anticipated Date day.
The weather today was really nice!
What would you like to do?
Well, I don't really know.
Perhaps, is this your first date?
Huh? No way. I've gone on dates before.
With Baek Seung Jo?
Yes.
Then again, it's our time to have all the fun in the world.
From now on, I'll take you out a lot.
Yes.
Where should we go?
There's this new rollercoaster, which is really fast.Should we go to the amusement park?
It sounds fun! What should we do afterwards?
Watch a movie at the drive-in theater and eat something delicious.
Oh I totally like it, the drive-in theater.
I've never been there before.
Excuse me.
Then how about we go to a nice park and ride bikes?
Oh I like that!
Oh let's do that first, then let's go to the amusement park, and the drive-in theater.
Enjoy.
Have you gone to the Namsan Tower?
There's a place there, where you can write your names on a lock and if you do your love will stay true!
Watch your head.
Here, sit.
Oh, let's take another one.
Brought to you by the PKer team @ www.Viki
If he's this nice to me...
I don't know what to do.
Right, this is what a date is.
A typical girl would have experienced lots of them by the time she's 19.
Ha Ni!
Did you have a nice time?
Yes.
Here.
It's been a long time since I had this much fun.
Why is that?
Is it because when you're with Baek Seung Jo,you're nervous?
Well.
How many years have it been that you liked Baek Seung Jo?
What?
More or less 4 years.
Since High school.
I guess this will be a prolonged war for me, then.
What?
No...
If you loved him for 4 years...
Just because I've suddenly appeared before you,
doesn't mean your heart is suddenly going to change.
Even if you only think of me from time to time,
I'm satisfied with that.
He's 180 degrees different from Seung Jo.
I expected it, but Seung Jo eventually didn't show up.
Ha Ni, let's go!
I can't let it continue like this. This just allowed me to reconfirm that Seung Jo really has no feelings for me.
And if I continue along with this, I'm only using Gi Tae sunbae.
So, my heart aches.
I must end it.
What are you doing?
Ah, Sunbae.
What are you thinking about in a place like this?
Were you looking at something?
No.
You were looking at Seung Jo from here?
Sunbae, I . . .
Oh Ha Ni!
Forget Seung Jo already.
Sunbae, I have something to sa-
Come here.
Ha Ni.
S-sunbae.
- No...- What is this?
Sunbae!
I think I've seen you before.
What are you trying to do to Ha Ni?
Joon Gu don't!
I was wondering what fool kept hanging around my Ha Ni.
You little fearless...
If you compare the time hanging around, then you've done it much longer.
What are you saying? What do you know?
Yes, Bong Joon Gu.
Why don't you give up already?
What?!
Stop it already!
What's going on?
What do you think you're doing in the library?
You two aren't fighting over Oh Ha Ni, right?
Hey Baek Seung Jo, this has nothing to do with you. So, back off.
Despite you guys fighting or shedding blood...
It doesn't really matter, but still.
The only person Ha Ni likes is me.
So isn't it a waste to fight over it?
Seung Jo.
My mother said for us all to eat dinner together.
Let's go.
Slow down.
Baek Seung Jo, you have quite a lot of confidence.
What?
The only person Ha Ni likes is me?
My heart could have changed.
You haven't thought about that?
Never.
But, you were a little jealous, right?
If you're going to put on a show...
Why don't you use your brains a bit more.
I can see right through everything you and mother are doing. Dummies.
He already knew everything...
He really can't be tricked.
See how nice it is for us to all gather like this?
You like it too, right Seung Jo? Living alone I know exactly what you eat.
No matter where you go, eating at home is the best.
That's right. No matter which restaurant I go to, nothing compares to a home cooked meal.
I thought you said Dduk Bok Gi was the best thing in the world?!
Stupid.
But hey Su Chang, you aren't eating much today.
A new game is coming out so he's been pulling a lot of all nighters, so he's really tired.
Ahjusshi, I'll get some more soup for you.
No, his doctor told him not to eat too much.
No matter how enjoyable your work is, make sure you take of your health first.
Good health is the best thing!
Of course. Gi Dong shi, you take care of your health too.
Of course! Healthy is as healthy can be!
They ate up 3 bowls of Bool Nak porridge!
There's no way.
Seriously!
I'll just be leaving then.
I thought you would sleep here tonight and then go...
Seung Jo, I have something to tell you. See me for a bit.
Yes.
You are now an adult, too.
What do you think about your future plans?
It's been some time since you left the house. I feel like it's about time you start clearing up your thoughts.
No, not yet.
Seung Jo.
I wish you would manage my gaming company.
First, as my right hand man. Next, as a successor of the company.
What do you think?
It's not that you're asking me what I think, but that I should do as you say, isn't it?
So you're just deciding my future as you wish.
No, that's not it.
If you're done talking, I'll get up first.
Okay, go.
I'm going.
Okay.
Go safely.
Just as the holidays were approaching...
Seung Jo suddenly disappeared.
He didn't show up at the tennis courts and even stopped part-timing at the family restaurant.
Where could Seung Jo have gone?
Okay, I'm taking it.
One, two, three... Say cheese!
The trails around here are really nice. We'll be preparing the bbq while you're gone.
Thank you.
Good-bye.
Hyung!
I've come.
Sticky gum Ha Ni has found Seung Jo's new part time job!
Eun Jo, you came by yourself?
What about mom and dad?
Dad couldn't come because of workand mom said she couldn't leave dad alone.
Mother was really very disappointed.
It's obvious.
The water is really good! The water is really famous, seriously!
Aigoo, Ha Ni! Ha Ni has come!
Well then, if you need anything else, just call me.Rest for now.
Yes.
Why did you come so late?Ah, this must be Eun Jo.
Just as I thought, it was you Sunbae.
Why don't you just open up your own broadcasting company.
What are you talking about?
You didn't tell other people too, did you?
Seung Jo!
Have you been well? Oh Eun Jo is here too!
Oh Seung Jo, have you been doing well?
Our villa is right over there. I want to invite you over for dinner. Want to come?
You're coming, right?
Eun Jo, hello.
Kyung Soo sunbae! Just to me?! What kind of secret information is this?!
I have something to tell you, come this way.
Ha Ni, Ha Ni.
I'm thinking about closing the deal with Hae Ra this time.
Do you think, you can do that?
So, I really need your help.
You and I have to join forces to stay afloat.
First off, I need you to keep staying near Seung Jo and stop him from approaching Hae Ra.
Sunbae it's Hae Ra that is approaching Seung Jo!
Has Seung Jo ever approached Hae Ra?
Just becoming a couple is important.
I'm going to ask to play a couple game. And then you can just become a couple.
- You and Seung Jo. Me and Hae Ra.- Ay...
Is it that easy? I've tried it this whole time and it's still yet to happen.
Don't worry.
I've planned and prepared everything.
Give me your hand.
Let's try our best in order to achieve our loves!
I feel uneasy for some reason.
What are you doing? I said, let's do fighting!
Fighting.
Hello all my youthful visitors. You've all come here in order to create memories of your youth.
Will checking out the scenery here and there create memories?! No it won't.
So the couple games start now!
Fool.
The way to play this game... Take a look at the map and see the numbers 1-7?
Those are all places. The couple that gets a stamp from all those spots first, wins the game.
This is the stamp!
It's not just a treasure hunt...
But a stamp hunt!
Then we have to decide on your partner.
Your partner will be decided fairly...
We'll use this ladder game method.
Why isn't Seung Jo here?
And really it couldn't be helped...
But I will be joining this game in order to keep all of you safe. It really couldn't be helped.
What the?Eun Jo, haven't you seen Seung Jo?
I don't know.
Where the heck did he go?
Here you go, this is it.
Hae Ra, what number?
Ah! Number 3!
Then I'll be 8. Everyone pick.
Brought to you by the PKer team @ www.Viki
I'm dying here.
It's like some villas or something.
Let's see.
Is this here?
I can't tell.
I'm sure it'll show up eventually.
Ha Ni, just wait! I'll definitely protect you!
From now on, I'll never send you off alone!
Let's go.
Why must I do this with Oh Ha Ni?!
Oh! It's there, it's there!
Come quickly!
Wow it seems we're the first ones! Right, right, right?!
Shut up.
Ya, let's do this on good terms.
Why are you being like this too? Either way I can't even be with Seung Jo after coming this far.
Even elementary kids don't play games like this!
Do your legs hurt?
I'll piggy back you.
Try getting on my back.
Oh really!
Did you set this up?
You picked 3 first. How could I cheat that?
It's a bug.
I want to quit!
It's not fun.
Who said we're doing this for fun?
The great Yoon Hae Ra can't lose to Oh Ha Ni, right? Seung Jo wouldn't like that either.
We just need 6 more.
Let's hurry up and find it then.
Where can it be?
You're the one that hid the stamps, Sunbae. So how could you not know, Sunbae?!
Since the trees all look the same, it's a little confusing.
What is it?
Since we just got the 4th stamp we just need to go...
Did you hear that?
Just now, that sound...
Wasn't that the sound of a wolf?
Idiot. Wolves went extinct in our country.
Then...a bear!?
I think I heard Ha Ni's voice.
Thank god! It's probably not following us, right?
It is not a relief!
Where are we?
It's alright Eun Jo. Noona will try to figure out our path. Don't worry.
Are you alright?
Yes, I am alright Eun Joo.
Stupid!
But...my hat disappeared.
It's my most cherished.
Stay there.I'll come down there.
Yes.
Eun Joo, be careful!
Where are we supposed to go?
How did this change? Last night there wasn't any water.
Strange.
Hey, Hae Ra, let's go together.
Oh, hey, Hae Ra!
Let's go together! Together!
I found it!
The stamp, the stamp!
Where?
Oh, that?!
The stamp!
Let's go, hurry!
Gosh!
This is why there's no reason to like you.
It's alright, I'm going.
Hey Hae Ra...
Seeing a guy like this, doesn't your motherly instincts...
Isn't that Ha Ni's hat?
Did something happen to you, Ha NI?
Just wait there awhile. I'll come and rescue you.
Oh that!
Alright this.
Aigoo!
Got it. Got it.
Alright, alright!
Oh, Seung Jo!
Oh, really!
Seung Jo.
Seung Joo, give me water..
What happened to Sunbae?
I don't know! His body build is completely useless!
Seung Jo, the mountains here are pretty rough.
There are animals making noises in the mountains.
Anyways, it was really hard.
Where are Eun Joo and Ha Ni?
They were the first ones to leave.
They're still not back?
Give me water, water...
It got cold.
I am hungry too.
But other than that, the problem is not finding our way back.
There's still no signal.
Cell phones must not even work here.
Here.
Baek Eun Joo!
You are amazing.
That's it!
Preparation. If you are prepared you'll be happy.
Analogy...
What is it?
Just put this over yourself.
Our Eun Jo sure is reliable.
It feels like being with mini Seung Jo.
First we need to find the canyon.
If we follow the path we came from,
then we're going to be able to find a way out.
If we wait, won't Seung Jo come?
You are really stupid!
How will he know that we are here?
Are you cold?
You can hold it.
You're so reliable.
The sun is going to go down, and my feet are killing me. Damn it!
Anyway, I need to go.
Aigoo!
Ha Ni, I am really sorry.
I can't go up in this condition.
Like this..
Like this, definitely
This can't be!
Aigoo!
No!
No! That can't happen!
Ha Ni!
I love you!
That sound, there it is again!
What do we do!
It's probably a village dog or something!
Isn't that Ha Ni's voice?
Ha Ni!
It must be coming this way.
What should we do?
Get behind me.
Hyung!
Eun Jo!
Seung Jo!
Won't anyone help me?
I would be grateful if someone came to help me.
Oh.
Hey.
Grab this.
Isn't that voice Baek Seung Joo?
Hurry and grab this.
Hey.
Why are you butting in?!
Who the hell are you to save me!
Screw off!
Really? Then, I'm leaving first.
Hey, hey! Where are you going now?
Fine, we have to save Ha Ni.
Calm down, she's safe. She went to the camp first.
Rea...Really?
It is a relief, you really did well.
It is really a relief!
Hey! Then...
would you help me?
Man I'm dying.
Shut your mouth. I can't show anyone this side of me.
Especially not to Ha Ni. Got it?
Anyways, nobody knows that you're here.
Don't worry.
Man, I'm a complete mess.
How can I show this side of me to Baek Seung Jo.
Baek Seung Jo!
I'm going to return the favor.
That's not very appreciative.
Oh...Seung Jo!
Did you come out for a walk?
Yes.
You should've come alone.
Huh?
Saying that you like me and stuff..
don't you know how I feel?
How you feel...
There's no way someone like me...
It was a dream.
I was surprised.
No wonder
It was playing out so smoothly.
If I knew it was a dream...
I should have dreamed a bit longer before waking up.
But...
the feeling of his lips
Brought to you by the PKer team @ www.Viki
For the first time I want to do something.
I'm going to apply for medical school.
I have a dream too.
Tell me that dream.
That you want to do something with me?
I'll make it come true.
Did you grab your wallet?
A new wife, I'm sure you want to call him honey.
Let me choose what I want to do with my life.
Baek Seung Jo
I've decided to become a doctor.
I will not inherit father's company.
Father!
Father, what's wrong!
Honey!
Are you okay?
This is the first time you want to do something right?
If I do this, Dad will be happy. I have no interest in it but at least he'll be happy.