SPEAKER 1: We're here
in the British Museum,
and we're looking at the head
of Augustus from about 27 or 25
BC.
SPEAKER 2: So who's Augustus?
SPEAKER 1: Well,
Augustus of course,
became the first emperor.
He, of course, was part
of the triumvirate.
So lots of people know the story
of Mark Antony and Cleopatra
through Shakespeare etc.
And, of course, he defeated
Antony at the Battle of Actium,
and that was when he was
able to assume the position.
He didn't become
Augustus until later
on when he finally defeated
all the other rivals.
SPEAKER 2: So he goes
from being Octavian,
who's one of three in charge of
Rome, to defeating his rivals,
including Antony, and--
SPEAKER 1: He's given
the name Augustus.
It's an honor that the
Senate give to him.
And with that is a shift.
He's saying, well, this is
a change from the past now.
He can't do the same kind of
promoting himself in the ways
he had before-- in
battle struggling
against the other people
that wanted to rule.
So here he's saying,
well, I'm ruling now,
and I'm changing the propaganda.
SPEAKER 2: Going back to looking
at this statue in front of us,
it's not necessarily the
kind of empire builder
that we would imagine.
This is quite stripped down.
I'm mean, he's a young man.
He's got a kind of
contemplative look.
He never seems to be meeting
your eye no matter where
you stand.
SPEAKER 1: I've walked
around him a few times now.
He won't look me in the eye.
SPEAKER 2: But he has
these very piercing eyes,
which are actually
made out of glass.
So they really stand out from
the dark bronze that we see.
SPEAKER 1: That's
something that you
see on other antique
sculptures as well.
SPEAKER 2: This is really well
preserved with a lot of detail
for something that's so old.
SPEAKER 1: And The
fact that it's bronze
is extremely unusual.
Because, of course,
not many bronze figures
would have lasted from
antiquity, because people
would usually melt
the metal down
and use it for another purpose.
SPEAKER 2: And there's
this fabulous story
about why this particular
head is so well preserved,
which is that it was
actually part of statue that
was put up in Egypt.
And at one point
the Kush Empire,
these enemies of the Romans
who were in charge of Egypt
at the time, invaded.
They knocked down the statue.
They took it away, and
it was like, ah-hah.
Thumb your nose at
the Roman Empire
by burying the head
of the emperor.
SPEAKER 1: And cutting
the head off a statue
is symbolic for
cutting the power--
the source of power of
the emperor himself.
And what they did with
it was very unusual.
They buried it underneath the
temple where they worshiped.
So they were actually
all standing on his head
and treading on him whenever
they went to worship.
So that's a good way of
trampling him under their feet,
always reminding him,
you're beneath us.
SPEAKER 2: The thing
that strikes me
about this is he's
portraying himself
in a very specific
way, obviously.
And there's this connection
to Alexander the Great
through the youth and the
tousled hair and, of course,
Alexander the Great
being the ultimate role
model for the young
military genius.
And this is clearly a
tradition that Augustus
is tapping into here.
But he's also giving himself
quite a bit of dignity
with this portrayal, He's got
the slightly furrowed brow,
but just enough to imply
a focus, not a worry.
SPEAKER 1: And
that's interesting,
because at this time when
he's creating this new image
he was trying to create
a shift in society.
He didn't want it to be warring,
infighting senators trying to
up themselves and promote
their own prowess.
He was bringing it
back to moral outlook,
down to the individual.
And he took the
name of Principate,
so he's the first
amongst equals.
And he tried to lead by example,
talking about family values.
And the imagery he took on,
he was promoting that as well.
And it's interesting to
talk about his youth,
because he used this
image until he died.
So he died at l think '76
or something like that.
And he never got another
[INAUDIBLE] or anything.
SPEAKER 2: So the idea of the
state portrait in Britain--
there's images of
Queen Elizabeth
and they're everywhere.
SPEAKER 1: We age her.
On our coins we have aged her
like every 20, 40 years or so,
we put a couple of wrinkles on
her and make her a bit fatter.
SPEAKER 2: Not so
much with Augustus?
SPEAKER 1: No, and
then every emperor
afterwards took that approach.
So they could maybe depict
themselves as an old person,
but they would never age
themselves any further
than their original image.
SPEAKER 2: It's also
worth remembering
that what had come
before this was
the Roman Republic-- the Senate.
And the idea was that
Roman citizens had a say
and voted on things.
And this is Augustus who's
breaking from that mold
and making it an empire.
So he's the first among
equals trying to connect back
to that republic idea, but
also putting himself slightly
over it.
And this is slightly
bigger than life size,
so he would have been a little
bit bigger than anybody.
SPEAKER 1: Anybody
else, definitely.
But he was everywhere.
This image would
have been everywhere.
And it was in towns
as far off, flung
afield as Egypt,
the furthest corner
of the empire at that time.
And it's that the
statue actually
stood in for the
emperor himself.
So he would be able to
preside over court hearings
and pass judgments in his
presence in the statue.
SPEAKER 2: So the idea
of imbuing a statue
with a bit of the
personality of the person
that it is portraying--
SPEAKER 1: The power that
dwells inside the statue.
SPEAKER 2: And, of course, we
don't know what he looks like.
But this is a quite
realistic seeming portrayal.
A man could look like that.
He's quite attractive.
SPEAKER 1: He's
very sympathetic.
SPEAKER 2: He looks
like someone who
would give you a fair trial.
SPEAKER 1: And the
fact that the head
has been removed
from the statute
by the Kush-- they are
attacking that power.
They're attacking the statute.
And remember, that
statute is Augustus
in all intents and purposes.
And they managed to behead him.
So unfortunate for him, they had
his head cut off in the statue,
but lucky for us,
because it's been
preserved in the sands of Egypt.