Space - there's only so much.
And when you run out... That's it.
Or is it?
What if you could do
more with the space you have?
What if there was
a smarter way to use space?
There is.
Let's imagine a room everyone uses.
24 hours a day. It's a living room.
It's a playroom.
We'd better make it easy to clean up.
And if we use this space up here,
it can also be a bedroom. Smart.
Stackable stools, drawers
on wheels, a bed up in the air.
Small ideas can transform a small
space into a generous space-
-that works for everyone.
It's about maximising space - being
a little creative with how you use it.
So, what if we get a little
creative with a space like this.
Does a living room really need a sofa?
What if we tried something different?
There, we just created
a whole wall for storage.
And a cosy little nest for two.
Now everyone can do what they want.
At the same time.
Together.
And being together
is a good thing, right?
So, let's try something
completely different.
Here are six friends.
And this is where they live. Together.
Why not? With bunk beds,
curtains for privacy-
-and a big communal table
to gather around.
It can work.
To make the most of the space you've
got all you need is an open mind.
And a few smart, small ideas.
It's about finding
and using hidden spaces-
-and choosing furniture
that does more than one thing.
And it works. No matter how
much or how little space you have.
It's not about giving up your dreams.
It's about shrinking them,
just a little bit.
It's about making space do more.
Even more than you could imagine.
And it's not about waiting.
It's about doing it today.
A dream home doesn't need to be big...
Just smart.
And it's kind of funny
when you think about it.
The space you've
been looking for-
-it's been right there. All along.