Every day throw away millions of electronic devices, because they get old and are worn out.
But usually it is only one of the components that causes the problem.
The rest of the device works fine, but is needesly thrown away.
Simply because electronic devices are not designed to last.
This makes electronic waste one of the fastest growing waste streams in the world.
And our phone is one of the bigest causes.
So this is a new kind of phone.
It's made of blocks.
Detachable blocks.
They are all connected to the base.
And the base connects everything together.
Electrical signals are transferred through the pins.
And two small screws lock everything in place.
So if for instance your phone is getting a litte slow, you can just upgrade the block that affects the speed.
Or if something breaks you can easily replace it with a new one.
Or update it with the latest version.
An other great thing about this is, you can customise your phone
Let say this is your phone and you do everything in the cloud. Why not replace your storage blok for a bigger battery blok?
If you're like this guy and love to take pictures, why not upgrade your camera.
Or if you don't care about about anything of this stuff, you can keep it simple. Get a bigger speaker.
You can choose the Bloks that you want.
Support the brands you like.
Or even development your own Bloks!
Phonebloks is build on an open platform.
Where companies work together to create the best phone in the world.
To setup this platform we need to get the right people and companies involved.
It will only get started if there is enough interest in a phone that is worth keeping.
So this is the plan.
To show them that there is interest in this phone, we need your voice.
You can donate your social reach on our website.
We will gather as much people as possible.
On the 29th of October we will send out a blast.
All at the same time.
Spreading all your voices to show the world there is a need for a phone worth keeping.
The more people involved, the bigger the impact.
Please visit www.phonebloks.com to raise your voice and spread the word.
Phonebloks - a phone worth keeping