Save heritage, menahankan warisan
Its Wilayah Day and it is a day that we chose to conduct this city tour
this city tour is going to go through Jalan Sultan for us to advocate
a very important message that is to advocate the importance of
preservation of heritage and culture and history of a city
we all know that Kuala Lumpur is like any city in other part of the world,
Kuala Lumpur has its own character, history and cultural background
we wanted the Malaysians especially and the world to understand
how Kuala Lumpur was established and came to today as a developed city
it is very important as part of the history of Malaysians to know that
the establishment and development of Kuala Lumpur is through the effort
put together by all the races, all races that stay in this country
It is a concerted effort of all races that upbring Kuala Lumpur until today,
Today MRT wishes to construct an underground tunnel, going to cost RM40 billion
through Jalan Sultan, to us this is very unwise.
It is unwise because the construction even though they use
the latest best methods available in the world it is not able to guarantee
the stability of the old buildings along Jalan Sultan and along Jalan Petaling.
We therefore have a strong desire to keep the development of Kuala Lumpur going on
at the same time maintain, keep the character of Kuala Lumpur city as it is.
We wish MRT to consider realignment.
Today we have to conduct this city tour because through the last four months
we have requested MRT to sit down with us to have a dialogue
to understand the people’s voice
but four months effort have brought us to nowhere.