Batu Caves, preparation are underway for the grandest Hindu Festival of the year
Thaipusam is about faith, penance and endurance
More than a million devotees are expected
to congregate here over the next few days
Five days before Thaipusam we follow a group of
50 devotees from the Sri Muniswarar Temple in Puchong
as they make their climb up the 272 steps to reach the top of the hill
where the temple is located.
HIgh Priest Vasantha, aged 50 is leading a group of devotees to fulfill their vows
and to seek forgiveness for their sins from Lord Murugan
She has been doing this for the past 20 years only this year it is a bit different
To avoid the heavy traffic, due to a long stretch of public holidays
she is starting early
and for many devotees it is never too early to perform this pilgrimage