Find the measurement of angle CAD, so angle CAD.. this angle right over here..
measure of that angle, let's just call it x, so that I don't have to keep writing the measure of angle CAD
and the other thing that might jump out at you is that the measures of the other angles' measures  are given here..
50 degrees, 45 degrees and 37 degrees.  The other thing that might jump out at you
if you take the outer edge of all these angles which are adjacent to each other
if you take the outer edge, it forms a straight angle.  So this entire angle is going to be 180 degrees.
Or another way to think about it is the measure of each of these angles, when you add them all together needs to be 180 degrees
.. and that's what we need to solve this problem.  Because we have x plus 50 (50 in orange),
+ 45+ 37 is going to be equal to 180 degrees. And now these, let's see 50+45=95. 95+37 is 132. So all
of that is 132. We can subtract 132 from both sides.
On our left hand side we are just left with x. On our right hand side, 180-132 is 48 And we're done!
X is equal to the measure of this angle over here which is equal to 48 degrees.