&lt;i&gt;Episode 9- Part 1 &lt;br&gt; [Episode 17]&lt;/i&gt;
Tae Ik,
What are you trying to do?
Until when will you keep being like this?
Until when are you going to treat me like a phantom.
You're drunk.
Go in and sleep.
I...
When I say that I want to start over with you,
I'm sincere.
Sincere?
You,
don't seem to remember.
You also said you were sincere when &lt;br&gt; you broke up with me.
Back then, Tae Ik...
I like you, I am sincere. &lt;br&gt;I want to break up with you, I am sincere.
Whether the other person gets hurt or not, all that matters is whether you like it. That kind of sincerity!
For someone like you,
do you actually have any sincerity?
What about you?
Being like this towards me now,
are you being sincere?
You still haven't gotten over me.
Pretending not to notice me, ignoring me.
It’s because you still haven’t gotten over me yet.
Then, what about that photo hidden behind the frame?
You said you're over me. Then, why &lt;br /&gt;do you have the photo you took with me?
When people were saying that you are gay,
if you had just shown that photo, you...
wouldn't have had problems.
You didn't show it&lt;br /&gt; because you wanted to protect me!
If you had shown that photo,
I may have gotten hurt.
Is it raining outside? I hung clothes…
Don’t misunderstand.
I just don’t want to be entangled with you ever again.
Instead of being entangled with you,
it is better to be misunderstood as being gay with Won Kang Hwi!
I know that it is all a lie between you and Jang Man Ok.
I'm Jin Sae Ryong! World star Jin Sae Ryong .
If I want something, I get it.
If I want to discard it, then I discard it!
Whatever that may be!
&lt;i&gt; You still haven’t gotten over me. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; You act like you can’t see me. You ignore me.&lt;br /&gt;You are purposely doing that &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; because you still haven’t gotten over me yet. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; You said that you are over me!&lt;br /&gt;Then, why do you still have &lt;br /&gt;the photo you took with me? &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; If you had shown that photo, you wouldn’t have had problems! &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; You didn’t do so because you wanted to protect me. &lt;/i&gt;
Are you an idiot, Jang Man Ok? &lt;br&gt;Why did you run away from there?
I am freezing to death.
Are you a fool?
Are you exercising under the moonlight?
Why are you gardening in the middle of the night?
Let's go inside. It's cold.
What about Jin Se Ryeong?
What do I care?
Aren’t you going in?
I am going in.
I won't stay still.
I believe that you received several love calls from famous foreign directors.
Is there a special reason why you declined all those proposals and came to Korea?
A special reason?
I guess you could say it, personally, &lt;br /&gt;is a special reason for me.
Would it be okay to ask, in behalf of our viewers,&lt;br /&gt;what is that special reason?
There is something that I must get back.
If it is something you need to get back…
For now, I can only tell you this much.
Ah, yes.
Then can you tell us briefly about your future plans?
I plan on choosing slowly.
I will meet you again with good work, whether it be a drama or a movie.
Okay! Miss Jin Se Ryeong, &lt;br&gt; you've worked hard.
You've worked hard!
Good job. &lt;br&gt;Director, good job!
Good job.
Good job. Reporter Nam is waiting.&lt;br /&gt;Let’s begin the interview immediately.
Buy me some stockings. I have a run in these.
I will buy you some after the interview is over while we are on the move.
I don’t want to do the interview in this state. &lt;br&gt;Buy some now.
Okay, fine.
I will ask for Reporter Nam’s understanding.
Wait here for a minute.
Se Ryeong, good job. &lt;br&gt;We will go ahead.
Go carefully.
It's all right. Go ahead.
Reporter Nam!
I am ready.
There is no reason to turn it on.
You needn’t turn on the laptop.
I didn’t call you to do an interview.
What is this?
You'll know when you look.
Oh?
Why did you call me?
What’s urgent?
First, have a seat.
The album turned out well. Good job.
Congratulations! Your song was nice.
Did you call me here to tell me that?
I called you so that the three of us&lt;br /&gt;can have lunch together. It’s been ages.
We haven’t had an official meal together after Se Ryeong returned.
I know a place that makes good Chinese food. &lt;br /&gt;I will make a reservation.
The two of you can eat.
I will be going.
Tae Ik!
This punk!
Where are you going? The car is over there.
What are you doing?
You! What are you doing?
Get out.
Let’s go and eat together.
I haven’t once had a meal facing you&lt;br /&gt;after I returned to Korea.
Do you have to go this far?
Why are you acting like this to me?
I am really sick and tired of you.
Don't try to stop me!
Lee Tae IK!
Lee Tae IK!!
Reporter Nam! It's me.
Reveal it as soon as possible.
Lee Tae Ik! Lee Tae Ik!
Lee Tae Ik! Let’s go together!
We are going home, aren’t we?
Ahjussi.
Ah! Not there.
Not Full House. Let's go somewhere else.
Anywhere!
Ahjussi, just go straight for now.
Is there anywhere you would like to go?
Is there something that you want to do?
Do you want to go to the amusement park?
Or do you want to see a movie?
Or...
So that we can get fresh air, &lt;br&gt;somewhere in the open?
Shall we really do it?
What?
What we faked and photographed?
Can you go all the way to the peak?
Are you belittling me now?
Hurry and follow me.
Oh! Let’s go together.
Hey! I’m tired, let’s go down now.
What is this? &lt;br&gt;There is just a little bit left.
No! No! No! &lt;br&gt;I can’t go anymore.
What man can’t even climb this?
No, we must go up to the peak. &lt;br&gt;Let’s finish climbing up.
No, it’s too much!
We are almost there.
No! No!
Come on! Come on!
We reached it!
Come here.
1, 2, 3!
Now that we have come up, isn’t it really nice?
Yahoo!
Lee Tae Ik, give a shout out.
Forget it.
If you shout out, you will get it off your chest.
Rude bastard!
What?
Don’t do that!
Completely petty!
Hey!
Shout out louder!
Hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Hey!
Now, since we don’t have time, shall we go back down?
We have to go to our next destination.
Already?
We don’t have much time.
Do you want that one?
No!
Give us two separate ones.
Why? Let’s ride that one. &lt;br&gt;It is more fun when the both of us ride together.
You’re heavy.
If you exceed the time limit, you have to pay more.
Thank you.
Jang Man! Let’s go together!
Isn’t that Lee Tae Ik?
Who is that woman?
His fiancée?
Take a photo! Take one! Jackpot!
Let’s go and buy some caps first.
Never mind. &lt;br&gt;Don’t worry about it.
Still…
Did you forget?
We are engaged.
We needn’t go around covering our faces as if we sinned.
Up to the convenience store over there.&lt;br /&gt;Last person to get there buys the ice cream.
Oh!
Then we need to start together!
That’s a foul, Lee Tae Ik!
Anything is good.
For instance, Lee Tae Ik’s fiancée was really bad at studies when she was at school.
The guy she dated when she was a student was a loser.
Anything that can become a potential article.
Well…
Anyway, I have no intention of selling out my friend’s personal information.
Look here, Reporter Han!
How can you write an article lacking the spirit of a journalist? Huh?
This is not selling personal information.
Huh?
We are providing the public with information that they want to know.
Whatever!
Whether it is the spirit of journalism or whatever.
After I provide such information,&lt;br /&gt;if I get caught by Man Ok later . . .
Oh my god!
Then, does that mean that it was all a scam so far?
How dare she with my oppa!
What is it?
&lt;i&gt;Lee Tae Ik’s Honorable and Pure Love &lt;br /&gt;Turns Out to Be a Contract Engagement. &lt;/i&gt;
What?
Contract engagement?
Evidence was found that popular singer,&lt;br /&gt;Lee Tae Ik’s engagement is fake.
The fans are in a state of shock.
Ah! What a loss!
This tremendous scoop! I should have fished it!
What’s up with Miss Jang? &lt;br&gt;She isn’t very pretty, she is even crazy.
Is it a rumor that Take One ended up like this&lt;br /&gt;because Miss Jang two-timed with Won Kang Hwi?
It’s not a rumor. In the article, it says &lt;br /&gt;that it was revealed by a closest person.
What is Miss Jang’s identity?
Ah! Jang Man Ok deceives me to the end? &lt;br /&gt;You betrayer!
Miss Jang’s personal information revealed!
Name, Jang Man Ok. &lt;br&gt;Age, 24 years old.
Class of 2006, Sang Sang Girls High School.
Master of the Hapkido Studio, Man Ok Kwan.
Once called the Goddess of War in Dohwadong.
Lee Tae Ik.
What?
Sitting here like this, it really feels&lt;br /&gt;like a secret date, doesn’t it?
Put out your hand behind your back.
If we do this, it feels more like a secret date, doesn’t it?
This isn’t a posture to be maintained for long!
Ah! Ye… yes.
It is uncomfortable.&lt;br /&gt;Shall we sit facing each other?
Why? I also like this position.
We are drinking expensive coffee.&lt;br&gt;Isn’t it better to have it facing each other?
Are you hot, Jang Man?
Is your face burning up?
The co… coffee is hot, that’s why!
W... why?
What?
Perhaps... you think I will give you a foam kiss?
You watched too much TV.
Who… who?
Where are you going?
Restroom.
Ah! Hurry back.
Yes.
&lt;i&gt; Jackpot! Lee Tae Ik and that fake fiancée&lt;br /&gt;are in Café W in Sinsa-dong. &lt;/i&gt;
Does a contract engagement make sense?
That Jang woman must have definitely seduced oppa!
That’s right! If she is caught by me...
Her personal information was revealed.&lt;br /&gt;Should we gather the girls and go catch her?
Yes, yes.
Hey! Miss Jang is in Café W in Sinsa-dong.
What? If it is W, it is just over there.
Where?
Isn’t that Lee Tae Ik’s fiancée?
Where? Where? Where?
She is dead!
Oppa, please give me your autograph.
Yes.
You're dead!
- How dare you joke around with Tae Ik oppa? &lt;br&gt;- You are dead today!
Uh, why?
&lt;i&gt;Hyung-nim, where are you now?&lt;/i&gt;
Don’t worry, I will return shortly.
&lt;i&gt;That’s not it, hyung-nim.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;A big problem again!&lt;/i&gt;
Big problem?
&lt;i&gt;Didn’t you see the article?&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;No, Stylist Jang! Is Stylist Jang with you?&lt;/i&gt;
Tell me properly!
What is the problem?
&lt;i&gt;That is…&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;An article that says your engagement&lt;br&gt; to Stylist Jang is fake…&lt;/i&gt;
What the hell are you doing?!
Are you okay? Are you hurt?
I’m okay.
Are you an idiot?!&lt;br /&gt;Why are you standing there getting hit?!
You are a master of Hapkido.
Whether you throw them down or give them a kick! &lt;br /&gt;You must escape!
Why are you enduring it like an idiot?
Is this the face of someone who is okay?
Let’s go to the hospital first!
Hey! Are you okay?
Are you okay? What to do? Hey! Open your eyes!
Hey! Open your eyes!
What to do?
- Hey! Come to your senses! &lt;br&gt;- What to do?
- Hey! Hey! Hey! &lt;br&gt;- Come to your senses!
What happened, Go Dong?
Nothing is wrong, right?
Is she okay?
Yes.
They said she lost consciousness temporarily because she got worked up.
There is nothing wrong.
She just needs to rest a bit, so don’t worry too much.
It’s a relief!
Go ahead, hyung-nim.
They said she will wake up soon.
I will guard her till she wakes up and send her home.
Take care of her, Go Dong.
Yes, President.
Ah! She is okay.
Yes. Hyung-nim is going home now.
Go upstairs and get some rest.
I am going upstairs.
Where is Tae Ik?
Ah...He just now went up...
Are you in your right mind?!
The whole world is talking about the contract engagement! &lt;br&gt;As if that isn’t enough,&lt;br&gt; you go and hit a fan?!
What crazy action is this when the album release is just around the corner?!
I've kept saying that you are doing a good job. &lt;br&gt;How dare you stab me in the back?
Listen carefully!
All this is because of Stylist Jang.
She deliberately approached you.
And began all of this.
What are you talking about right now?
Doesn’t your head function at all?
The only way for you to live now is that way.
'A tragic star who was harassed by a stalker.'
'And eventually forced to get engaged.'
Are you crazy?
Who is the person who proposed the contract engagement to Stylist Jang?
The situation then and now are different. I...
Thinking about the money and time I spent taking care of your mess,
I will make Stylist Jang the scapegoat
and block this situation.
I...
What if I won’t dance to your tune anymore?
What are you going to do then?
You?
Because of a stylist?
You don't think that you can stop me, do you?
Don’t think of anything stupid.
If you throw that woman to the people and stay quiet,
this will soon be resolved.
Tomorrow at 2 p.m.,
the press conference for the release of your album,
we will hold it as planned.
This problem...
Let’s cover it up well and... &lt;br&gt;let's start again.
&lt;i&gt; She deliberately approached you. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; And began all of this. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; What if I won’t dance to your tune anymore? &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; What are you going to do then? &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Just because of a stylist? &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Don't think of anything stupid. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; If you throw that woman to the people and stay quiet, &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; this will soon be resolved. &lt;/i&gt;
Yes, Grandpa.
&lt;i&gt;Jang Man Ok.&lt;/i&gt;
Grandpa,
why aren’t you sleeping at this hour, what’s up?
Why is your voice like that?
Are you not eating?
No. I ate it all.
There are no problems at the hapkido studio?
Yes, there are no problems, Grandpa.
Until grandfather return, &lt;br&gt;be on complete alert&lt;br&gt; and guard the studio well.
Yes.
&lt;i&gt;Where there is a way!&lt;/i&gt;
There is a will!
&lt;i&gt;Dismissed!&lt;/i&gt;
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Grandpa.
Man Ok!
Today is the day my cast is removed.
What is this?
Since you were stuck in the basement, &lt;br /&gt;you don’t know anything?
We just had a storm.
Why are you, alone, so bright?
Storm?
I guess you didn’t surf the internet at night?
Hey.
What is this?
Tell me properly!
They say that Jang Man Ok and Lee Tae Ik’s engagement is fake.
News broke out yesterday.
Because of that, Jang Man Ok’s hair got grabbed by the life-and-death fans.
Lee Tae Ik pushed that fan.&lt;br&gt; Now, there is an article about his violence.
The President has lost his mind trying to take care of it.
It is a battlefield.
Where is Tae Ik?
I haven't seen him all morning.
Is he stuck in his room?
Only when a storm passes by,
can the sky clear.
What happened?
The fake engagement got revealed.
Man Ok suffered from the life-and-death fans.
What are you going to do now?
You involved an innocent person and&lt;br&gt; even made her get engaged to you.
Are you eventually planning to dump it all on Man Ok?
Perhaps?
Is that what you decided to do?
Are you crazy?!
Don’t bother about it. &lt;br&gt;I will take care of it.
What are you going to do?
How are you going to take care of it?!
Don't interfere!
This is my problem.
I will take care of it.
No, you can't.
You are merely LJ's puppet.
What can you do?
Eventually, it will be Man Ok who is hurt.
Like how I got hurt.
Listen carefully, Lee Tae Ik.
Whatever it is,
if something bad happens to Man Ok,
I will not let you off.
I'm happy. &lt;br&gt; I'm happy. [In Korean].
I'm happy.
I'm happy. &lt;br&gt; Completely happy.
I'm so happy. &lt;br&gt; I'm so happy. [In English]
I'm so...
What are you so happy about?
Why? Why did you stop singing? Continue!
I know how to sing that well in Chinese.
I'm happy. [In Chinese.]
I'm happy.
I’m happy, I’m always happy.
Shall we go?
Pardon? Where?
I hate you! Did you already forget?
Today...
is the day I remove my cast.
Oh, that's right!
Let's quickly go.
Let’s go remove the cast and eat something good.
Ah!
Let's go.
I will support you from this side.
Thanks.
- Lean on me. &lt;br&gt;- Yes.
I'm sorry for forgetting.
How is it?
Is it okay?
It is so refreshing.
I think I can live now.
The doctor said that you must still be careful.
Okay, I got it.
Hey, Man Ok
To celebrate my leg becoming well again,&lt;br&gt;let’s buy something good to eat.
I have some emergency funds. &lt;br&gt;What shall we eat?
Let’s just go home.
Why?
If someone recognizes you...
Instead, I will make you something delicious.
What do you want to have, Kang Hwi-nim?
It shouldn’t scar. This pretty face.
It won’t with something like this.
My skin is so good, it will be better in no time.
Just a moment.
Yes, Go Dong.
&lt;i&gt;Sylist Jang, where are you now?&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Is Tae Ik together with you?&lt;/i&gt;
No.
I am outside. Why?
&lt;i&gt;The press conference starts at 2 p.m.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;But there is no call from Tae Ik hyung-nim.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;The reporters are creating havoc.&lt;br&gt; And, he isn’t at home either.&lt;i/&gt;
What?
What do you mean by that?
&lt;i&gt; How is it? Our house. Do you like it? &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Is this really our house? &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I’m sorry. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; The whole responsibility is on me. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; So, I will leave U Entertainment on my own. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; What the hell are you doing now? &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I will no longer do it. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Home. That's the only place Lee Tae Ik can go to. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Lee Jun! &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I wonder who exposed the fact about the contract engagement to the reporters? &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Come back to me. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;I will reinstate you properly. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; What are you up to again? &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I must find Tae Ik. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I think you would know where he went, Senior Manager. &lt;/i&gt;