SelamunAleykum ve Rahmetullah ve Berekatuhu
Shukur YaRabbi Estagfurullah
Elhamdulillah
Asking support from our Shaykh,
Sahib ul Saif
Shaykh Abdulkerim el Kibrisi el Rabbani
Who is holding on tightly to the way
of our Grand Shaykh
to the way our Resullulah SAW
bringing the light to the whole world
Bringing th elight to the lands where
there is no light, because the sun
sets in the west
it doesn't rise in the west
Specifically he has been sent to the west
To this land to the America
And the light he brought was the light of the
Holy Prophet SAW
the Icazet that was given to him,
when he first came to this country
to spread the teachings of real Islam,
to spread the teachings of the tariqat,
to spread the love of the holy Prophet SAW,
to these part of the world
where nobody has ever heard of islam
and if they did
is nothing but lies and slander and
wrong things
and we are very fortunate
Alhamdulillah
Ttat we know him
and we are under him
and that he has pulled us out
from the mess and the jungles of his
dunya and this cehennem.
Yes, because this dunya has turned into a
cehennem
and brought us here
to the top of the mountain
to live our faith
to live Islam
to live the lifestyle of the Prophet SAW,
according to his teachings according to the way of our Grandsheikh,
according to this Tariqat, according to the way of Rasulallah (SAV).
We did not come here to the top of the
mountain,
we did not come
to take Beyat with him
to show our
ego,
show our
opinions,
to show our minds,
we came and we gave beyat to him
to say  Sameena ve ataana
we're here and we obey of course our ego
that is the worst thing
that our ego
to our ego
to hear and to obey because the ego`s
nature
is to hear and disobey.
But Allah SAT saying to the
ego
"step forward,"
the ego stepped back, opposite.
When He said to the ego "move to the
right," ego moved to the left.
When He said to the ego
"move to the left", the ego moved to the
right.
When Allah is saying
to our egos  to you and  to mine
our ego, saying "who am I, who are you?
and our ego says, 'you are you and i am me!
you are you, you are existing!
I am existing!
you are
Lord, I am  a Lord!'
So, our egos are declaring that
and  the ego
hates to recognize another Lord,
that is the characteristic
of sheitan.
Because Sheitan is saying  'Yes, Allah is our Lord but
only according to what
i wanted to be
the way that i want our Lord to be.'
And when our lord Allah SWT  is saying to Adam, "do not
eat from the forbidden fruit"
placing restrictions there
and Adem AS,
with our mother Havva Ana
they made the mistake
and Adem AS
is asking for forgiveness
and Adem AS  asked for forgiveness
when you was sent down to the world
standing on one foot on the island of
Sri  Lanka for three hundred years,
crying and begging to Allah SWT
asking for forgiveness
and Allah has forgiven, but still.
Because that is the nature
of the spirit
that Allah SWT has created
put into man
and the nation of the spirit is it does not
want
to anger
that one
who has created him.
He does not want to anger it's master, does
not want to anger his Lord
but the characteristic of the ego is the
complete opposite
is declaring
and always challenging
and when Allah SWT
is saying to
Shaitan
make  secde to Adem AS
and Shaitan says
that doesn't make sense to my idea
of what our lord
should do or should not do. How many of us
are doing that now, how many muslims
are doing that now?
how many
the people who says they follow a
master
they  follow a Prophet , they follow a master,they follow a Sheik
says that now?
It doesn't
makes sense to my head,
it doesn't make sense to my
understanding, it doesn't make sense to
my intelligence, what!?
No, I make secde only to you .I am not going to make secde to this one
that you have just created who did not even made one secde to you. Why I should
be making secde to him?
he should be making secde to me.
Of course Shaitan
he  has a different agenda
definitely
Shaitan  has a different agenda.
His agenda is to look
when he looked at the Makam-il Mahmud
that Allah SWT has created
and he's saying
I want that
it should be for me
but he knows that
he doesn't fit into that makam and he
knows that this new creature
that Allah SWT has created
this light of Prophet SAV,
fits into that Makam.
So, from that time until now Shaitan is going to go opposite
to what Allah SWT
has prepared for the children of men.
Walakad karamna bani Adam
"And we have honored
The bani Adem
the children of Adem."
Prophets they came,
Prophet SAV,
the seal of the prophets, the holy Prophet SAV came
and his inheritors,
the EvliyaAllah, and the Sheikhs
especially in this most distinguished
order, came
to make us,
to understand,
to come in to own reality
and to occupy
that place of honor.
That place of honor that Allah has said
"We have honored the Children of Adem."
That is the purpose
of the Sheikhs, that is the purpose of
the friends of Allah,
that is the purpose of the Murshids.
To change us,
to change
our nefs from Nefs-i ammaret to Nefs-i mutmain.
To change that nefs,
that is
together allies with the Shaitan,
to make our ego to be our vehicle,
that the spirit is going to ride on that ego
to bring us to higher stations. We can not
do that with books, we cannot do that
alone.
We can not even do it in a group.
We have to do it
with a Mursheed,
with a sheikh,
with a Varis el  Enbiya
the inheritor of the Prophet SAV.
The Prophet  SAV, he
came fourteen hundred years ago and,
that one
is hazir and nazir
that one who is
fresh and alive,
that one
who is inside of us, that one  who is everywhere
has also left inheriters and his
inheritors,
our Sheikhs
they are also following in the same
footsteps.
They have veiled from this world from this world
but  they are hazir and nazir,
definitely they are.
Because if Holy Prophet SAV is dead,
like so many they're claiming that he's
dead,
then, we're not responsible because we don't
follow
a dead prophet, we don`t.
We don't follow a dead prophet. That time,
we will not be responsible in the day of
judgment, Allah SWT
is questioning us
why we are not following the Shariat of the Rasulallah SAV.
But he's not dead,
those  who say that he is dead, their hearts are dead .
Definitely, they don't have connection to
that one,
that Allah SWT
has created everything in creation, you
and me,
the sun and the moon and the
galaxies, in everything in creation ,
that you know and you did not know that Allah is
continually creating
for the sake of that one.
So, he also has inheritors
and his inheritors are teaching us
how to come back to own reality, how to
come back to our own senses, how to hold
on tightly
to the lifestyle and the teachings and the sunnat of the
Rasulallah SAV,
that is going to fit according to these
times, according to this age and
according to the group that we're living
in.
So Elhamdulillah ,we are here, we`ve pulled ourselves away from this Dunya,
to be on top of the mountain,
only
to follow the teachings of the Prophet SAV
and his advice
to his nation in  the Ahir zaman, in the Ahir of the ahir zaman,
saying,
"O my nation, in the Ahir zaman there`s going to be so much fitna everywhere.
Pull yourselves back,
take a couple of sheep.
Pull yourselves to the mountains ,to the
secluded areas, away from the populated
areas.
Whatever little knowledge that you have,
don't go running around, searching and
investigating and arguing .
Take that small
knowledge that you have
and practice it sincerely,
live simply
and wait
because the time of the Sahibul Zaman
is right around the corner.
The time of the Sahibul Zaman,
it's going to come and we have reached to the ahir of the ahir zaman.
We've reached to the end of the end of the
end of times.
And the Ahir of the ahir zaman
it is not the time of paradise.
In the ahir of the ahir zaman,
it`s a time of great
tyranny and great confusion everywhere.
From the world,
to the countries,
through the muslim communities,
to the groups,
to the families, to the individuals
fitna is everywhere.
The fitna
of Deccal is everywhere. Yes,
because Deccal is going to
appear. He has already prepared.
We're asking the question,
why
in the month of Ramazan,
Shaitan is supposedly locked up but
people are still behaving
like shaitans.
People are behaving like they're
following shaitans.
People are behaving, completely holding on to shaitan .Why is that?
That is because
before shaitan has left,
he has prepared his deputies.
He has prepared
our egos. Trained our egos well, he says
"I may be gone, heh
but now,
you are trained
very well by me
and be able to continue the work, even if
I'm not there."
Deccal,
the big one that is coming
so many has come, small Deccals.
Forty fifty deccals, huh... in these
days
countless deccals.
That he has,
these deccals have prepared  the world, prepared
countries.
Countries ,nations moving.
Communities moving,
groups, families, individuals moving and
accepting
the way of Deccal,
the way of fitna,
the way of this Dunya,
the way of tyranny,
so that when Deccal comes,
the task, it is so easy for him.
That majority of the people, yes
if they don't wake up to themselves,
muslims who don't wake up to themselves,
they're going to look at Deccal and they are going to say yes,
this make sense.
We are going to follow you
because
you are going to give
what we're looking for.
And what are muslims are  looking for
these days, ask, think,
sit down, ask yourself!
What are you looking for?
Are you looking for
the Prophet?
If you are looking for the Prophet SAW,
you're going to find, look, consult
and be with his inheritor,
be with his
varis
be with a
WaliAllah,
be with a Sheikh
and you're going to say, this one is
representing the Prophet I'm looking for.
That one, so now I'm having him,
i'm going to hold on tightly to him.
Of course he is going to do
and he's going to say and he's going to
advice things that is not going to be
good for my ego. My ego is never
going to accept.
My ego is allies with Shaitan
but my spirit is going to be free that time.
My spirit
is looking for the Prophet SAW and I am
looking for the shariat,
the shariatullah,
the shariat of the Prophet SAW,
the way of the Prophet SAW.
Are muslims looking for that?
Are muslims looking for
holding on tightly to the shariat
that Holy Prophet brought
the shariat that is
the justice
that has been missing from this world
especially
in the past hundred and less than a
hundred fifty years.
The shariat there was held on tightly
by our ancestors
held on tightly
especially
by the Ottomans who brought justice
east, west. north and south.
Do they have enemies? Of course they do,
and they will continue to slander them
too
and all muslims are slandering them,
definitely.
Muslims are slandering the Halifa.
Masha'Allah, masha'Allah!
Very good for you.
Prepare yourself that time.
Because the Holy Prophet SAW  is saying,
do not against your Halifa.
Do not rebel against him.
to be awwam (???)
to do umum (???)
Do not rebel against him,
even if he takes the skin of your back.
The whole nation of islam
are we running towards that?
Looking for shariat,
looking for the shariatul Rasul,
looking for the Halifa to come back,
to live according to the way of the Prophet
brought.
or, our nations
looking for what?
The lands
where the sun has set
has to offer.
You don't have to be a genius to answer
that
or sing.
Are they looking for
a Halifa, a representative of that
Prophet SAW and to live
by his words to live by his law.
It's already showing if we are
then we will all have
Sheikhs, and we will have masters and we will all hold on tightly to them,
and obey them
and not have any problems with them.
Or do we always have problems with our
masters saying,
'I like this part but I don't like that part.'
'This is Ok, but that is not Ok.'
I like this one before,
now you change it and you like.. No.
So we have to check ourselves,
because preparing for the time of
Mahdi AS
it is not the easy,
these are not easy times,
these at times of complete darkness.
Sheikh Mawlana Hazretleri said so many times,
our Sheikh Efendi Hazretleri said so many times
it is time of dark, darkness
this is the time sorrow is covering everywhere
where the dark clouds are covering everywhere,
people are looking
muslims are looking, the hadith is saying dark clouds, where is the dark clouds?
Looking with these eyes, but they're
not understanding
their hearts, our hearts, the muslims' hearts have already been clouded.
It's already dark,
because we are not looking to ahirat.
We are not looking to the Holy Prophet SAW what he has to say.
We are not looking to the murshids,
we are not looking to the sheikhs and we are not
looking to Awliya Allah.
But we are looking to what our ego wants,
we are looking to what this dunya
has to offer to make this dunya
to become a paradise, don't we understand?
Don't you understand this is the ahir zaman? Don't you understand this is the ahir or ahir zaman?
We are following the Prophet of the ahir zaman.
As believers,
we should not be preparing ourselves to
live in this will world comfortably.
As believers,
we should be preparing to make our ahirat
better than our dunya.
To live in this dunya
as travelers.
Nations
have lost their direction.
Nations' leaders have lost their direction,
they have lost their compass.
Nations' Alims and Ulamas - they've
completely lost their compass.
They are under the payroll,
and they are looking.
Not what Allah and His Prophet has to say,
but who is paying them,
who has the power
to shut them out or to open their
mouth what those ones, what those ones have to say.
Fitna,
Holy Prophet SAW said
will come out
from the scholars of my nation
in the ahir zaman,
will come from them
and will circle around
and they will come back to them,
and a big curse is coming to them.
So, not for us to run
these times
to be come
scholars,
to know so much,
take whatever little knowledge that we
have
and practice it sincerely,
and prepare
for the grave.
Prepare for the hereafter,
make preparation for that, not for this dunya.
Are muslims preparing that?
Definitely not.
Preparing, wishing
that this spring is going to turn into
summer.
What spring?
They are saying Arab spring.
Eh, it's been a year and a half years already
spring is never finishing? Masha'Allah.
It's spring. No. It fell down.
It didn't spring, it flopped.
Same things happening, why?
Gather, be together
and ask
for the sahibu zaman to come.
because only he will come with a divine
power
to break the system
of dajaliyat,
to break the system of the shaitan,
to break the system where the ego is
running completely free,
to break the system where everyone
is declaring themselves lords.
Where nations' leaders, nations' alims
and those ones who are in authority are not warning and keeping their nations in check
and to say
do not
pass your limits.
We are servants,
do not cross into that other side
to follow
what shaitan has been
planning for these thousands of years to
welcome the time of dajjal. Yes.
We are in the time of dajjal.
We are not during the time, we are in the time of Mahdi AS,
definitely not.
What, you need proof for that?
Don't you see this whole world?
Right now we are comfortable, we just
finished iftar
we finished making zikir, we are going to make prayers.
Don't think that this whole world is
like this.
Half of this world is burning,
half of this world they are suffering,
and the leaders of this world they are coming
together
and they are planning what?
To make this world into a paradise,
or they are planning
to turn this world
into a hell?
To burn this whole world.
So, which type
are we living in?
If we are living in a very dangerous
times
which sad to say not too many people
not too many.
Those ones who have
authority and those ones have knowledge
they are warning the people
that we are living in very dangerous
times we are living the times of dajjal,
they are not warning them.
That is not in their agenda, because this
wishing and
hoping this world is going to last
longer forever if necessary
and for them to have more comfort them a
luxury from this world
but the signs that Holy Prophet SAW
has said
about the coming of deccal
about the cebabire time, it's
already here
we're living in it
we're living
dangerous times
very dangerous
what do we do in dangerous times
we sing and we dance
we enjoy ourselves
uh...  are we preparing ourselves
for the murids of our Seyh
Holy Prophet SAW
has given to us
and advise and a warning
for us to keep ourselves clean
keeping ourselves clean
to prepare for the time when the Mehdi AS is going to come
prepare for that time
to make ourselves to more useful
to the Shariat
to the laws
that Allah SWT has brought
Holy Prophet SAW
teaching his nation that is not going to
change until Kiyamet
prepare ourselves for that
get ourselves used for that
are we getting more and more used to new
and new things
Are we getting more used to innovations
are we getting more used to new things
being introduced
our group
into tariqat into islam
what are we
looking for
is that what we're looking for
we will find it
if that's what we're looking for
deccal is going to bring it
deccal is going to bring and
he's going to say
this world it is a paradise
but this world
it is a hell
from the skies to the earth to the
waters to the air,this world
this planet
we have turned it
into a hell
who's saying otherwise
which ignorant one's going to say otherwise
and deccal is going to say no
we are going to continue with this
and we're going to continue
to use the world and to suck the world
and to make it into a paradise for us
but that Sahib ul Zaman is going to
come
and he's going to say
do not believe that
because now is a time
when black is white
and white it's black
and unless you are following a Seyh
and consulting with him
and holding on to him tightly
and not being rebellious and challenging
when the very dangerous times comes there
is no more time for explanation
for arguing
that is a time
insAllah u Rahman
we'll be in safety
blindfolds will be put to us insAllah
for us not to understand
that is
stepping on the edge of a cliff
and we will hear his voice to say just
walk don't turn left and right
just walk follow me
that is the time
we're living in those times
so we need to check ourselves
we need to check ourselves
are we preparing ourselves for the Shariat
to come
uh... we're getting more and more use to
Shariat
in our lives
are we getting more and more use of the
laws in the orders
that our Seyh has put into our life's and
to hold onto that tightly
and not change
are we looking for an out now
especially since his past for a change
for uh...
adjustment
if we are
there's a very big danger up ahead
it we are
it is going to be very
difficult times for us
if we're holding on tightly
he's going to carry us trough insAllah ur Rahman
as much faith and as much sincerity that we have
and as much obidience that we have
we will be in safety
here in here after
we have a big job ahead of us
our job
our intension
our mission is to continue his mission
and his mission
is to bring down kufur
to bring down
disbelief and unbelief
that time when the war comes it is no
longer
with Muslims and Christians or Muslims and
Jews and know it is  between believers
and unbelief
because they are believers everywhere in
every religion and there are unbeleivers
with the appearances that you believe
in every belief in every religion in
every group
if we are preparing ourselves for the
time of Mehdi AS
when he comes and he's going to come
with nothing but the Shariat of the Resullulah SAW
we're going to be happy
we're going to be in safety
it we're looking for changes
if we're looking for
completely no Shariat
but we're looking for mixing everything
together
then deccal is going to offer as that
it is already here
it is already
because this Shariat this separation of Hak and batil
this separation
it is very strange
to people living
these modern times
They say we're very backward people
we have a strange antiquated
we have a strange old fashion people who
have no touch
with reality
if this is a reality
this cehennem out there is reality yes
we have no touch we're not in touch
with that reality
but we in touch of the reality that our Seyh
that he has brought from our Grand Seyh
from Holy Prophet SAW
we're in touch with that
and we're very happy with that
we're not here to please the world
we're not here to please this dunya
to please this society that we're living in
we respect everyone we love everyone
and want to live according to that
respect and the love
that is nothing
but is contained in the holy Shariat of Prophet SAW
though the Ottomans had brought
bringing justice
to Muslims Muslim Nations different
Muslim Nations
and to Christian nations and to
Jewish Nations
believers and unbelievers
giving each one their rights
and we are
waiting for those days to come insAllah ur Rahman
we preparing ourselves for that
and to keep ourselves holding on tightly
to the way
of our Seyh
to the way of our grand Seyh to the way of
Prophet SAW
we're not here
wanting to build
palaces for ourselves
the drive big
fancy cars wear nice clothes to eat to drink
No
that's why we are here on the
top of the mountain
that is why you have taken biat
with our Seyh
to say let us begin this first step
where we die before we die
where we gonna turn away
from this world and turn our faces to the Uhva
to the reality to the Ahiret
to turn our face
to that reality
that our Seyh has brought
from his Grand Seyh from the Holy Prophet SAW
that this the reality
this is not reality,this is fake
and it's passing
and this dunya has no value
has less value
than a wing of a mosquito
as Holy Prophet SAW is saying
Allah SWT is saying
inshaAllah ur Rahman
we are asking Allah SWT
to bless our Grand Seyh
to bless our Seyh
to raise their stations higher
and higher
for us to hold on tightly
to them
and for the himmet
and the Medet
come to us
for us to continue this way strongly
for things
to get bigger and to get stronger for us
not to deviate
for the sake of this holy month for the
sake of this holy nights for the sake
of the most beloved one in the divine presence
Fatiha
to everyone who's watching us
inshaAllah ur Rahman
this
time this day
next week
we will be
celebrating commemorating
the fortieth day of of our Seyh
Shaykh AbdulKerim el Kibrisi el Rabbani
if Allah gives us long life
that is what we're going to do will have Zikr
we will continue the program
we're not going to change
so be with us
Allah has opened the doors Allah has
opened the doors also for this
technology
to be used in the way of islam
we are not relying on this technology
because we are relying on the technology of
our Shaykh technology of the Evliyaullah
but this is come to us
and we're using it use it for the sake of Allah
that time it's going to be blessed
but we're not relying on it
because the first thing that is going to
go when Mehdi AS calls the Tekbir
it's electricity
that time
if you don't build this technology
this technology
with the Shaykh
with a community
if we just relying on this camera this
electricity
easily can be cut
that time
your connection will be lost
and you will be lost
will be lost forever
big loss coming to us
big confusion coming
in those days to bigger confusions
we don't want to do that
because with the end of the race
the race is almost done, dont quit now
don't turn now
there is a tape is there we're running
towards the tape now whole world is
looking for that foolish olympics are
not understanding what it is
but that tape there
we almost there
there's a lot of
darkness now definitely
but don't suddenly now because you're
running there and you seeing something
and you running towards to other direction
running to the left direction, no dont
keep on going straight ahead
it may seem
because there's a lot of confusion now
there's a lot of dust
like they say in Turkish
you all know
when the dust settles
whether it is a donkey
or a horse
so there's a lot of dust
covered now
as long as we're holding on tightly to
our Shaykh inshaallah we will not
be the losers
Fatiha
Same time next week insAllah
if you have any questions you can ask
if anything that you want to say, say
we are available
InshaAllah
if there's anything
you wish to do, to participate
to make this way stronger and clearer
to make this work that we're doing
to progress
don't hesitate insAllah
have a good Teravih
and have a good week