When you're searching for the light
And you see no hope in sight
Be sure and have no doubt
He's always close to you
He's the one who knows you best
He knows what's in your heart
You'll find your peace at last
If you just have faith in Him
(Allah) You're always in my heart and mind
Your name is mentioned every day
I'll follow you no matter what
My biggest wish is to see you one day
Coz I believe... I believe... I believe
Do you believe, oh do you believe?
Coz I believe
In a man who used to be
So full of love and harmony
He fought for peace and liberty
And never would he hurt anything
He was a mercy for mankind
A teacher till the end of time
No creature could be compared with him
So full of light and blessings (Muhammad)
You're always in my heart and mind
Your name is mentioned every day
I'll follow you no matter what
If God wills we'll meet one day
Coz I believe... I believe... I believe
Do you believe, oh do you believe?
If you lose your way
Believe in a better day
Trials will come
But surely they will fade away
If you just believe
What is plain to see
Just open your heart
And let His love flow through
I believe I believe, I believe I believe
And now I feel my heart is at peace
I believe... I believe... I believe
Do you believe, oh do you believe?
I believe I believe, I believe I believe