I was a foolish little child
Crazy things I used to do
And all the pain I put you through
Mama now I'm here for you
For all the times I made you cry
The days I told you lies
Now it's time for you to rise
For all the things you sacrificed
Oh, if I could turn back time rewind
If I could make it undone
I swear that I would
I would make it up to you
Mum I'm all grown up now
It's a brand new day
I'd like to put a smile on your face every day
Mum I'm all grown up now
And it's not too late
I'd like to put a smile on your face every day
And now I finally understand
Your famous line
About the day I'd face in time
'Cause now I've got a child of mine
And even though I was so bad
I've learned so much from you
Now I'm trying to do it too
Love my kid the way you do
Oh, if I could turn back time rewind
If I could make it undone
I swear that I would
I would make it up to you
Oh, if I could turn back time rewind
If I could make it undone
I swear that I would
I would make it up to you
Mum I'm all grown up now
It's a brand new day
I'd like to put a smile on your face every day
Mum I'm all grown up now
And it's not too late
I'd like to put a smile on your face every day
You know you are the number one for me
Oh, oh, number one for me
There's no one in this world that can take your place
Oh I'm sorry for ever taking you for granted
Ooh, I will use every chance I get
To make you smile, whenever I'm around you
Now I will try to love you like you love me
Only God knows how much you mean to me
Oh, if I could turn back time rewind
If I could make it undone
I swear that I would
I would make it up to you
Mum I'm all grown up now
It's a brand new day
I'd like to put a smile on your face every day
Mum I'm all grown up now
And it's not too late
I'd like to put a smile on your face every day
Mum I'm all grown up now
It's a brand new day
I'd like to put a smile on your face every day
Mum I'm all grown up now
And it's not too late
I'd like to put a smile on your face every day
The number one for me
Oh, oh, number one for me