How beautiful, is this worldly life
But not a soul shall remain
We've all come into this world
Only to leave it one day
I can see that everything around me
Rises then fades away
Life is just a passing moment
Nothing is meant to stay, oh
This worldly life has an end
And it's then real life begins
A world where we will live forever
This beautiful worldly life has an end
It's just a bridge that must be crossed
To a life that will go on forever
So many years, quickly slipping by
Like the Sleepers of the Cave
Wake up and make a choice
Before we end up in our graves
O God! You didn't put me here in vain
I know I'll be held accountable for what I do
This life is just a journey
And it's taking me back to You
This worldly life has an end
And it's then real life begins
A world where we will live forever
This beautiful worldly life has an end
It's just a bridge that must be crossed
To a life that will go on forever
So many get caught in this beautiful web
Its gardens become an infatuation
But surely they'll understand at the final stop
That its gardens are meant for cultivation, oh
This worldly life has an end
And it's then real life begins
A world where we will live forever
This beautiful worldly life has an end
It's just a bridge that must be crossed
To a life that will go on forever
This worldly life has an end
And it's then real life begins
A world where we will live forever
This beautiful worldly life has an end
It's just a bridge that must be crossed
To a life that will go on forever