(Potter Puppet Pals theme opens)
(ticking)
What is that mysterious ticking noise?
(quietly)
Look over there...
Hmm, kind of catchy
(sings with ticking)
Snape, Snape,
Severus Snape
Snape, Snape
Dumbledore!
-Snape, Snape, Severus Snape
-Dumbledore!
(jumbles)
-Snape, Snape, Severus Snape
-Ron, Ron, Ron Wesley
-Dumbledore!
-Snape, Snape, Severus Snape
-Ron, Ron, Ron Wesley
-Dumbledore!
(Snape and Ron sings their names.)
-Hermonie, Hermonie.
Dumbledore!
(Snape, Ron and Hermonie sings their names)
-Harry Potter!
Dumbledore!
(Snape, Ron, Harry and Hermonie sings their names)
(Dumbledore shouts his name)
-Snape
-Harry
-Snape!
-Harry!
-Dumbledore!
-Her-rr-rmonie!
(All sing and shout their names)
(All)
Sing our song...
...all day long at...
...Hog-gg-ggwarr-rr-rts
-I found the source of the ticking!
It's pipe bomb!
(Harry and Hermonie cheers)
(explodes)
Mwah-ha-ha-ha!
(Cane taps)
Voldemort, Voldemort.
Oooh, Ahh
Voldy, Voldy, Voldemort!
(music "Wha, wha, whaaaa")
(Curtains rustle)
Captioned by cartoonlover89