Hill tribes in the Golden Triangle (of Thailand Laos and Myanmar) were once cultivating opium as a cash crop.
In 1984, with the encouragement of the Thai monarch, King Bhumibol,
they switched to Arabica Coffee.
So successful was this initiative that some of the best coffees in the world
are to be found growing in this region.
In Doi Chaang or Elephant Mountain in Northern Thailand,
the Akha hill tribes have been a role model for successfully
cultivating, processing and marketing of their coffee worldwide.
Here, in the cool highlands, amidst pear, peach and macadamia nut trees,
Arabica coffee thrives best, producing coffee cherries that have
a more complex and intense flavour, low in caffeine and therefore less bitter.
The Akha hill tribes together with other hill tribes have been living along the borders
of Thailand, Laos and Myanmar for the past 2000 years.
Recently they have settled in  Northern Thailand to avoid
persecution and harassment from other neighbouring Governments.
After 20 years of successful cultivation, the Akha villagers
have established themselves as independent coffee producers
building their own processing, R &amp; D facilities and marketing outlets,
selling their coffee throughout Thailand, Asia and America.
If you are searching for that best cup than you have to look no further
than in the Golden Triangle.