On the 4th of July, 2011 we posted a request online
to participate in a short film about interdependence.
Artwork and videos emerged from around the world.
Here is what unfolded...
When in the course of human events...
It becomes increasingly necessary
to recognize the fundamental qualities
that connect us.
Then we must reevaluate
the truths we hold to be self evident.
That all humans are created equal
and all are connected
That all humans are created equal and all are connected.
That we share the pursuits of life
liberty
happiness
food
water
shelter
safety
education
justice
and hopes for a better future.
That our collective knowledge
economy
technology and environment
are fundamentally interdependent.
Interdependent.
That what will propel us forward as a species
is our curiosity
our ability to forgive
our ability to appreciate
our courage
and our desire to connect.
That these things we share
will ultimately help us evolve
to our fullest common potential.
And whereas we should take our problems seriously
we should never take ourselves too seriously
Because another thing that connects us
is our ability to laugh
and our attempt to learn from our mistakes.
So that we can learn from the past
understand our place in the world
and use our collective knowledge
to create a better future
So perhaps it’s time
that we as a species
who love to laugh
ask questions and connect
do something radical and true.
For centuries we have declared independence
Perhaps it’s now time
that we as humans
declare our interdependence
Interdependence
To declare your Interdependence...
let it ripple [letitripple.org]
let it ripple [letitripple.org] -- declare
Let it Ripple: Global Films for Mobile Change