Travelling up the Mekong River, we are heading for the point known as the Golden Triangle
where Loas on the right, Thailand on the left and Myanmar up ahead share a common border
When Mao Tse Tung's Red Army swept into Yunnan 10,000 Nationalist from the Kuomintang Army
fled into this region led by General Tang, better known as Khunsa
With the fall of Vietnam to Communism in the 1960's the United States and the West were fearful
of the Domino Effect in South East Asia, provided Khunsa with funds and arms to enable him
to fight Communist expansion.
Instead Khunsa expanded the existing opium cultivation by the hill tribes
He commenced opium cultivation and opium manufacturing to an industrial scale
In the 80's up to 70 % of the heroine in the west came from the Golden Triangle
Kunsa became the most wanted man in the world.
In the early 90's the Royal Thai Army destroyed Khunsa's Opium base and together with the
United Nations International Drug Control Program converted most of the opium fields to
tea, coffee and tobacco plantations.
Khunsa surrendered to the Burmese Govt in 1996 and passed away in 2007
All this while the Myanmar refused to extradite him to the USA even though he was charged for
opium smuggling in a New York Court.
With the opening of casinos at the Myanmar and Laos borders, the Golden Triangle looks set to
regain some of its previous notoriety and reputation.