\}
Not late until the bell rings.
Uh-oh.
\}
Sex...
...the sex drive in the human animal is intense.
Hello?
I'm Edward Cullen.
\}
So spill, what was that all about?
Nothing serious I think.
It looked like more then that to me, he got all googly eyed.
Survey says...
...vampire!
\}
I'm sorry, I'm just trying to figure you out...
...you're very difficult for me to-- [cut off]
I'm the Slayer.
Um.
S-l-a-y-e-r.
Chosen one?  Look it up!
\}
You know, I'm on a special diet.
What are you doing?
Here, at this table, talking to me like we're some kind of talking buddies?
I feel...
...very protective of you.
Don't leave.
\}
Hello?
You and I, we are gonna go somewhere, alone.
What? No!
I'll do whatever it takes, I don't have the strength to stay away from you anymore.
\}
He actually told you, he said I love you?
Well I didn't let him get that far.
Buffy I'm really worried, these things can become pretty twisted.
Hi.
Well-- [cut off]
Stop trying to see me, and stop calling me!
[mutters] Women.
You know, being stalked isn't really a big turn on for girls.
\}
Get out.
I like watching you sleep, its um,  kind of-- [cut off]
Get out or I will drop you out head first!
I just want to try one thing.
\}
As if you could out run me!
It's you, your scent.
Didn't anyone ever tell you the whole smelling people thing is a little gross.
It's like a drug to me, you're like my own personal brand of heroin.
Oh my god are you twelve?
I've killed people before.
And you're sure this isn't just some fanboy thing...
...cause I've fought more then a couple pimply overweight vamps who called themselves Lestat.
I wanted to kill you...
...I've never wanted a human's blood so much in my life, are you afraid?
No, you know what I feel?  Bored!
\}
This transformative work constitutes a fair use of any copyrighted material as provided for in section 107 of the US Copyright Law.
Media appropriated from: Buffy the Vampire Slayer (seasons 1-7)
Twilight (2008)
Twilight (motion picture soundtrack)
Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire (2005)
Remixed by Jonathan Mcintosh
rebelliouspixels.com