We started Universal Subtitles because we believe
every video on the web should be subtitle-able.
Millions of deaf and hard-of-hearing viewers require subtitles to access video.
Videomakers and websites should really care about this stuff too.
Subtitles give them access to a wider audience and they also get better search rankings.
Universal Subtitles makes it incredibly easy to add subtitles to almost any video.
Take an existing video on the web, submit the URL to our website
and then type along with the dialog to create the subtitles.
After that, tap on your keyboard to sync them with the video.
Then you're done— we give you an embed code for the video that you can put on any website
at that point, viewers are able to use the subtitles and can also contribute to translations.
We support videos on YouTube, Blip.TV, Ustream, and many more.
Plus we're adding more services all the time
Universal Subtitles works with many popular video formats,
such as MP4, theora, webM and over HTML 5.
Our goal is for every video on the web to be subtitle-able
so that anyone who cares about the video can help make it more accessible.