Translated by (your name here)
Last time...
It was supposed to be a standard mission.  Get in.  Get out.  Get paid.
Now my men are dead.
Who killed my mates?
The name is Bobby-
Kotickovich!
ActivistSun is proud to announce our acquisition of Outer Heaven.
Liquid and Makarov are creating a new weapon.
Modern Gear!
The Boss is arming Modern Gear as we speak.
Act 3:  Sun Down
Sorry it's taken so long.
But I've finally found him.
That bastard who betrayed us.
His name…is Bobby Kotickovich.
Isn't he that guy that clubs baby seals?
Well, yes, but he's also the head of ActivistSun.
A powerful shadow military.
And it's our job to bring them to light.
Kotickovich has stayed one step ahead of us.
But we've tracked him down.
Booyah!
It wasn't hard to follow the trail of bodies.
We believe he's using this abandoned arms depot to launch his new weapon.
Modern Gear!
Once Modern Gear is finished, Kotickovich will be unstoppable.
We have to face reality.
It's unlikely that you'll be coming back from this mission.
But when they speak of this moment
It won't be us that stood idly by while Kotickovich destroys everything we stand for.
Snake.  Ghost.
The fate of the world is in your hands now.
I won't stop until I've brought that bastard down.
I swear it.
You will be avenged.
No matter what the cost.
Even if I have to sacrifice everything.
We're not sending you in empty-handed.
We've been working on some new gear for you.
Whoah, what is it!?
I hope it's a puppy.  I'm gonna name it Solid Dog.
(Ghost:) Oh yeah, nice one brother!
Whoah!
Sweet!  Thanks Naomi!
We got something for you too, Ghost.
Oh thanks mate, you shouldn't have-
-Uhhhhh. . . . .alright.
It's a bit small, innit?
Uhh…
I thought they’d go well with your mask.
(sigh)
Well, try them on!
(Snake hums)
This may be a suicide mission.
But the world will remember us…for this.
We…will…kill him!
(Snake:) In position.
Don't you just love this weather?
Make's you feel good to be alive.
Hey, what is that?
Awww, it's just a box.
What's it doing out here?
Beats me.
Did you order anything?
No.
Hey, you cardboard son of a-
Hello!
Sleepy time!
Moving out.
Got you covered!
Let's go.
Clear!
Watch your corners. Kotickovich could be anywhere.
I'm gonna kick his puny ass.
Clear!
Whoah.
Do you hear something?
(industrial noises)
Holy --CENSORED-- What is that!?
Modern Gear
Oh, this was a bad idea….
(snake groans)
Well well well, look what we have here!
Snake and Ghost!
Kotickovich!
We have some unfinished business, you and I, Ghost!
Right, I forgot to send you back to hell!
Seriously, is that it?
Is that all you got?  My turn!
Aw crap.
How do you not see him!?
Where are you going, Ghost?
(evil laughter)
Oh crap!  Crap!  CRAP!
No. No! NO!
Oy, toaster oven!  Where's my pop-tarts?
Hey, that's not my name!
No-no-no-no-no-no-no-no!
Die already!
Oh crap!
Stop hiding, Ghost!
Oh no.  Damn it!
This is not gonna work.
Oh crap- oh crap- oh crap- oh crap- oh crap- oh crap!
Oh this is not fair!
Come on Ghost!
No.  It can't end like this.
(Ghost yells)
Ghost!  Come out and play!
I'm gonna finish what I started with your team!
What's this?
(Ghost laughs)  Oh yeah!
It's been a long time, old friend.
On the next episode…
Translated by (your name here).