Excuse me, do you have some time?
Ah...Oh...I am Korean [&lt;i&gt;in Japanese.]
I am Korean. [&lt;i&gt; in English.]
I know. I know. &lt;br&gt; You are Korean. [&lt;i&gt; In Korean.]
It's me, Man Ok!
Oh, Kang Hwi. What a surprise!
How do I look? No one will be able to tell, right?
Yes, if you said you were a duck, they would believe you.
--What? &lt;br&gt; --I'm just joking! Just joking!
Lets go, Man Ok.
Huh? Where are you going?
I'm hungry! I will buy you something really good to eat. &lt;br&gt; Let's go eat delicious food.
You waited a long time.
Here.
Try it. The udon here is really the best.
Ah! And...
This is a secret.
I will only give this to really special people.
I like shrimp. &lt;br&gt;I will enjoy it.
Yes.
How is it? &lt;br&gt; Yummy?
It is similar to the taste of udon sold at rest areas.
What did you say?
Man Ok, don't eat it.
I will eat it all.
Just joking!
It's actually really delicious! &lt;br&gt;The noodles are so chewy!
This is really awesome!
Is it, isn't it?
Is it delicious?
Kang Hwi-nim, you should hurry and eat, too.
Yeah.
I will enjoy it.
But, Kang Hwi-Nim
You didn't find the voice recording, did you?
Ah! That is...
If you had found the voice recording, there is no way you would have come here with the President.
Hurry and eat up. &lt;br&gt;It's not good if it gets bloated.
Let's hurry up and eat, then go shopping later. &lt;br&gt;It feels like a million years since I went shopping.
--Hurry and eat. &lt;br&gt; -- Yes.
Woah! Wow! &lt;br&gt; It's awesome.
This...
Are you going to buy a hairpin?
Yes.
Which one among the two do you think is prettier?
Well...let's see...
They're both pretty! &lt;br&gt; I'll buy them both for you.
No, I'll only get one.
I'll just get this one.
Why? I said I'll buy them both. &lt;br&gt;Buy them both.
My grandfather... &lt;br&gt; A long time ago, he used to say
wanting to have this and that is greedy.
If a person is greedy, &lt;br&gt; eventually he ends up losing everything he owns.
Let's go pay.
This is also pretty.
Man Ok!
Let's go here!
What?
&lt;i&gt; Episode 10, Part 2&lt;/i&gt;
Excuse me, Kang Hwi-Nim.
How did it happen?
Why are you with the President...?
Wow! This place is more spacious than I thought.
Aren't you going to tell?
I'm not asking either.
Why Man Ok came to Japan.
So, Man Ok, just don't ask either.
Today, the things that we couldn't do so far because I was locked up in the basement,
let's do them all and have fun, huh?
Man Ok, let's go here!
They said this place is really fascinating.
Let's go.
Quickly.
Let's go. Let's hurry and go!
Ya-ho. &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ya-ho.
Wah! Wah! This is really fascinating. &lt;br&gt; Man Ok, hurry and try it, too!
Ya-hoo. &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Ya-hoo. &lt;/i&gt;
Omo!
What I said is true, isn't it? &lt;br&gt; The sound really echoes!
It really does!
Ya-hoo! Kang Hwi-nim! &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt; Ya-hoo!
It's really awesome. &lt;i&gt;Kang Hwi-nim! &lt;br&gt; It's like an echo!
Me, me! Let me try one more time.
Jang Man Ok! &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt; Jang Man Ok!
More than the actress, Jang Man Ok &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt; More than the actress, Jang Man Ok
is much more... &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt; is much more...
pretty! &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt; pretty!
Man Ok,
I have something to tell you.
Thank you for being by my side when &lt;br&gt; I was having a hard time.
In the future, like now,
can you be by my side?
&lt;i&gt;Subtitles by The Maid of Full House 2 @ Viki
Just a moment.
&lt;i&gt; Where are you?
&lt;i&gt; Didn’t you hear that you have a meeting with the reporters tonight? &lt;/i&gt;
I will be there.
&lt;i&gt; There isn’t much time. Where are you? &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I will send Go Dong, so tell me your location. &lt;/i&gt;
I'll be there on time.
That's why I'm asking where you are!
You said you will earn your keep.
I’m asking because you talked big saying that you will serve.
Come quickly and work!
What are you looking at so intently?
Do you want a drink?
If you have gotten some fresh air, let’s go back.
Go back,
and start afresh with me from the beginning.
I will help you.
You will help me?
Senior Manager Hwang, you will help me?
In your eyes, I may not appear trustworthy.
But, fellow... at least I am different from LJ.
What is different?
You or President LJ...
are all businessmen, aren’t you?
People who sell people…
No.
I never once thought of you guys like that.
At least I know what you truly want.
What I truly want?
What is that?
You...
said you weren't a singer because &lt;br&gt;you wanted to be one.
It was because of money,
because of the house,
because of L. J..
You said that you were dragged all the way here.
But that's not it.
You.
Tell me...
You want to stand on stage again, don’t you?
Stand!
Stand on the stage and get it all back...
Your fame, Full House...
and the person you love.
Return,
and get them all back.
On your own!
That is what you need to do now!
Look, look here.
Your fans are asking you to come back.
I don't need it!
Just leave me alone.
Tae Ik!
Tae Ik oppa, please come back! We love you!
&lt;i&gt;Man Ok! I really must tell you something! &lt;br&gt; See you in Seoul!
Tae Ik. Tae Ik. I love you. &lt;br&gt; Tae Ik, Tae Ik. I love you !
Do you want a drink?
Is that a trend these days?
That’s all right.
I already had a drink, so you drink.
Then, since you already had a drink, have another.
What is this? &lt;br&gt;Where is it that you can just come in?
I’m leaving tomorrow.
It’s my last night in Japan. &lt;br&gt;You can’t even do this for me?
You said that you won’t go if I don’t go.
That’s what I planned on doing.
But the ticket is only for tomorrow.
I bought that cheap by fixing the date, &lt;br&gt;so they said that I can’t even change it.
Ha!
Aigo!
So, let’s go together, huh?
If you came to drink beer, just have beer and go.
Ah, seriously!
Can’t you just go back with me?
Look here!
Mr. Rude Bastard!
You know, I, to come all the way here,
spent all the money I have completely.
You!
Do you even know how expensive &lt;br /&gt;the exchange rate is these days?
What? You?
Rude bastard?
There is some more.
Stop drinking.
What is this?
That stormy change of temperament?
This rude...
This rude bastard, what is so nice about him?
Still, you...
are very blessed.
Having people who love only you,
and having people who look only at you…
It is such a happy thing.
So! Don’t run away!
What fault do your fans have?
Their only fault is loving you!
You have multiple personalities!
What, on earth, is so nice about a guy like this?
You are indeed good-looking.
Jang Man!
Tell them to bring more alcohol.
Alcohol...
&lt;i&gt;♪ Whenever I see your eyes, I can't sleep. &lt;br&gt; ♪ Tonight
&lt;i&gt; ♪ when I feel your breath, I am thrilled.
&lt;i&gt; ♪ When I look deeply into your eyes, &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt; ♪ I need you.
Tae Ik! Tae Ik! Come back! &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt; &lt;i&gt; ♪ I need you.
Tae Ik! Tae Ik! We love you!
Tae Ik! Tae Ik! Come back! &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt; ♪ I want to have you gently.
Tae Ik! Tae Ik! We love you! &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt; ♪ Everything is so sweet, Girl!
Tae Ik! Tae Ik! Come back! &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt; ♪ Everything is so sweet, Girl!
Tae Ik! Tae Ik! We love you! &lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt; ♪ I don't stop dreaming of you all night.
Tae Ik! Tae Ik! Come back!
Tae Ik! Tae Ik! We love you! &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt; ♪ I want to hold you.
Tae Ik! Tae Ik! Come back! &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt; ♪ Whispering with moist lips into my ears,
Tae Ik! Tae Ik! We love you! &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt; ♪ Whispering with moist lips into my ears,
Tae Ik! Tae Ik! Come back! &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt; ♪ I want to hold you.
Tae Ik! Tae Ik! We love you! &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt; ♪ I want to hold you.
Tae Ik! Tae Ik! Come back!
Tae Ik! Tae Ik! We love you! &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt; ♪ You can fly. Be my girl.
Tae Ik! Tae Ik! Come back! &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt; ♪ You can fly.
Tae Ik! Tae Ik! We love you! &lt;br&gt; ♪ Let me love!
Tae Ik! Tae Ik! Come back! &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt; ♪ Give all for you.
Tae Ik! Tae Ik! We love you! &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;♪ Be my girl!
Tae Ik! Tae Ik! &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt; ♪You can fly.
&lt;i&gt; ♪ Let me love, love you, tonight.
&lt;i&gt; I will contact you once I reach Korea, Kang Hwi-nim. &lt;/i&gt;
I packed all your luggage, hyung-nim.
Yes. All right. Let’s go.
We were really indebted to you all this time.
Indebted? No.
I was more thankful during your stay here&lt;br /&gt; because you helped me out.
You made a lot of delicious things also. Thank you.
Miss, are you going home now?
I want to go, too. Huh?
I want to go home, too.
Mina, why are you acting like this again?
- Take me home also. &lt;br&gt; - Mina!
Lee Tae Ik will come to take you soon.
You must be healthy till then.
But, where has he gone off to since this morning?
He isn’t even coming out to see the guests off.
It’s all right.
Let's go, Stylist Jang. &lt;br&gt;We'll be late.
Yes.
Goodbye!
- Let’s go. &lt;br&gt; - Yes.
Bum Soo hyung!
Tae Ik!
Lee Tae Ik!
Jang Man, you be in charge of this.
Hey, this fellow!
You have an aptitude for shocking people! Let’s go.
I will check in the baggage. &lt;br&gt; Go have some coffee.
Yes.
What are you going to drink?
Don't smile.
I'll develop affections for you.
What are you going to drink?
I want to drink water.
7 parts cold water and 3 parts hot water. &lt;br&gt;Make sure the ratio is exact.
Yes, Tae Ik-nim.
We must hurry.
The President and Se Ryeong are already waiting at the lounge.
Hyung-nim, hurry and come.
When we arrive, you will be crazy busy.
First of all, your damaged image, the company will…
President, take care of it as you wish.
Yes, all right.
And... the problem about Stylist Jang…
She has a history of being exposed &lt;br /&gt;to the media because of Tae Ik.
I wonder if we would be creating &lt;br&gt;a problem by insisting on using her.
If you are thinking of reneging on the promise&lt;br /&gt;you made with me, tell me now.
I will disappear again as soon as we land.
Oh! Oh! Run! Run!
Oppa!
Reporter Han! Reporter Song! Come to your senses! &lt;br&gt;We came here to cover news.
Covering news is not important now.
Our Kang Hwi oppa has made a reappearance after such a long time!
Oppa!
Ga Ryeong! Don't cry!
- Hey! &lt;br&gt;- Kang Hwi oppa!
Come to your senses!
You should never forget the spirit of journalism anywhere.
What is Kang Hwi? Seriously!
The best in the universe, Won Kang Hwi!
We love you, Won Kang Hwi!
Why aren't they coming out?
Senior Manager Hwang, did you sell roast chestnuts before?
This was fashionable back then!
It's called a military hat.
What military hat?
Lee Tae Ik, if you really don't like it, do you want to exchange it for my scarf?
With that wrapping cloth? Forget it!
Let's go out first, huh?
Here, here, here...
Please ask your questions one person at a time.
What is the reason for being ousted?
Is it because of your discord with Lee Tae Ik and the love triangle with Miss Jang?
No, it isn't.
There was a small misunderstanding with the company.
Now, it has been amicably solved.
How have you been since you were ousted?
You must have had a really hard time.
Personally, it was a hard time. &lt;br&gt;But, since my schedule was so busy, in the past,
I couldn't think about a lot of things.&lt;br&gt;This was an opportunity to reflect on them.
Being ousted from the team and being reinstated,
during this time, the problem of Lee Tae Ik's contract engagement surfaced as a problem.
Won Kang Hwi's come back and Lee Tae Ik's incident,
are they related?
That is...
They are separate issues.
Whatever happened so far, because of the shameful incidents,
I apologize once more for causing the fans to worry.
Lee Tae Ik has voluntarily withdrawn himself.
Then, will Won Kang Hwi go solo?
Whatever may happen, with an improved image,
I will try my best to stand like that in front of the fans.
Let's stop now. &lt;br&gt;Kang Hwi is tired.
Reporter Park, Reporter Kim, let's meet separately later. &lt;br&gt;Let's go!
- Please look here! &lt;br&gt;- This side please!
Hey! It's quieter than I had thought.
The reporters don't seem to be around.
I think it would have been okay for you not to wear that hat.
Will you go to the office?
Stop by the office and drop the kids off at Full House. The remodeling is over.
It must have been uncomfortable, move to the main building.
I'm fine.
I already got furniture in, so the room I was using is more comfortable.
Then Kang Hwi, the room you were using originally in the main building…
It’s all right. I will just stay at the annex.
Annex?
I will take care of it, so don’t worry too much.
The annex went into the President’s hands?
How did that happen?
It won’t suffice even retrieving back the main building, how can you lose it like that?
My words exactly.
If you are going to create trouble, consult me before making trouble.
If it goes into Lee Jun, that jerk’s hands,
he will never give it up just like that even if he dies.
What are you going to do now?
Then where will Lee Tae Ik live in the mean time?
What?!
Don’t worry about that.
You think I wouldn’t have even prepared that when I brought Tae Ik back?
Ah, seriously!
I couldn’t clean up because I was in Japan.
Come in. Come in and sit.
Excuse me, Senior Manager, where do we sit?
Ah! This way, this way.
Excuse me, Senior Manager,
it seems too small for the two of you to live here.
Why?
It’s just because it is a little untidy now.
For two men to live together, this place is just right.
I'll go to a hotel.
What? Hotel?
Hey! Whether it is a hotel or other lodging,
we don’t have money to use at the moment.
And it's tiring if reporters or Lee Jun find out where you are.
It is safest and best to be here right now.
Then Lee Tae Ik, would you like to come to my home?
Never mind!
I will take care of my business, so go home now.
Still...
Yes, yes.
It’s just a little messy. &lt;br&gt;It’s not like my house is uninhabitable.
Let’s clean up first.
Yes, yes.
Where was the vacuum cleaner?
Will you really be okay here?
I will be fine.
Now go.
Will Lee Tae Ik be all right here?
He will be. He said so himself.
&lt;i&gt; President Lee &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Subtitles brought to you by The Maid of House 2 Team @Viki&lt;/i&gt;
Senior Manager Hwang! &lt;br&gt;Bum Soo hyung!
What is that?
Why aren’t you sleeping and calling me?
Jang Man, this house is weird.
Huh? Why? You can’t sleep because it is uncomfortable?
I think there is somebody here.
Huh?
Are you talking about Senior Manager Hwang?
No, scatter, scatter…
It is full of crawling strange things&lt;br&gt; that make these noises.
Scatter?
Ah! Something like cockroaches?
I wondered what it was.
This is not a place inhabitable by humans.
Why are you making it sound so serious because of cockroaches.
Spray some insecticide. Or catch them by smashing them with some tissue.
You savage!
How can a woman catch insects so easily?
Seriously! Then learn to live &lt;br&gt;on good terms with the insects.
So, why were you being obstinate?
It would have been good if you followed me earlier.
Forget it!
Where are you now? &lt;br&gt;You aren’t at home, are you?
I’m at home.
Bull shit!
What? What did you say? &lt;br&gt;Bull shit?
Lee Tae Ik, you also use words like that?
You aren’t at home.
I am at home.
How can you insist without seeing?
I can see you now.
What?
What is this?
Please…
What?
Please let me sleep here.
&lt;i&gt;Thanks for watching with us!&lt;br&gt;See you all next Monday!&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Would you like me to... stay here for a long time? &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I miss you... really! &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Pull yourself together, Jang Man Ok. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; He is a star, a star! A star in the sky. You know? &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;HEY!&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Come! Say hello! &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; He is called "Sangsu-dong Wolf." &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Hyung-nim!&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; You can't even sing. You only rely on your looks. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Hey!&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I will do everything that you want. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; If you want to get back Full House,&lt;br&gt; I will also do that for you. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; The person who is next to me... &lt;br&gt;It is more important to guard that person. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; You fell in love. And, now you aren't even afraid of the President. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Now, all sorts of useless people are getting me mad! &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Jang Man Ok, Grandpa is here. &lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Subtitles brought to you by The Maid of House 2 Team @Viki&lt;/i&gt;