I'm going to briefly talk of AI as something else,
which is AI is the technique of uncertainty management in computer software.
Put differently, AI is the discipline that you apply when you want to know what to do
when you don't know what to do.
Now, there's many reasons why there might be uncertainty in a computer program.
There could be a sensor limit.
That is, your sensors are unable to tell me
what exactly is the case outside the AI system.
There could be adversaries who act in a way that makes it hard for you
to understand what is the case.
There could be stochastic environments.
Every time you roll the dice in a dice game,
the stochasticity of the dice will make it impossible for you
to be absolutely certain of what's the situation.
There could be laziness.
So perhaps you can actually compute what the situation is,
but your computer program is just too lazy to do it.
And here's my favorite: ignorance, plain ignorance.
Many people are just ignorant of what's going on.
They could know it, but they just don't care.
All of these things are cause for uncertainty.
AI is the discipline that deals with uncertainty and manages it in decision making.