Let's get started and learn how to convert percentages to decimals,
and if we have time maybe we'll also learn how to convert decimals into percentages.
So let's get started with what I think is a problem you probably already know how to do.
If I said I have fifty percent.
I don't know if I wanted to write that thick,
but we'll go with it.
Actually, let me change it to a thinner one.
And I want to turn that into a decimal.
Well you probably already have a sense of what decimal represents fifty percent.
If I told you we're having a sale and it's fifty percent off,
you know that's roughly half off, or another way,
how do you say half as a decimal?
Well that's the same thing as zero point five.
So you might have known that in your head,
but is there a system for being able to convert this fifty percent to point five?
Well, it turns out it's pretty straightforward.
All you do is you say-- whatever percentage it is,
that's the same thing as the number over one hundred.
And fifty over one hundred is the same thing as five over ten or point five.
Now even a simpler way of converting percentage to decimals.
And this, I think, you're going to realize converting a percentage to a decimal
or the other way around,
you can pretty much do in your head.
If I say, let's say fifty-- and I'm just going to add one decimal of accuracy here
just to show you a point-- fifty percent. Right?
If I want to convert that fifty percent into a decimal,
all I do is I get rid of the percent sign.
So I'll do it here.
Fifty percent.
I get rid of the percent sign and I take the decimal point
and I move it over two spaces to the left.
So I say one, two.
So this is where the new decimal is.
So this equals, we could say zero point five zero zero.
So fifty percent is equal to zero point five zero zero.
And of course, these last two zeros really don't mean anything for our purposes,
so we'll get rid of them.
So that's the same thing as zero point five or just point five.
Fifty percent equals point five.
So you're probably saying, well, sure.
That looks easy,
but what if the problem gets a little harder?
Fifty percent I could have done in my head.
So let's try some, I would say, slightly harder problems.
If I were to tell you that-- let's say sixteen point three two percent.
Well, let's just do it the way I just showed you.
I'll rewrite it down here.
Sixteen point three two percent.
So if we get rid of the percent sign, scratch it out,
we just have to move the decimal over two spaces to the left.
So one, two.
This is the new place for the decimal.
That decimal goes away.
So it's point one six three two is equal to sixteen point three two percent.
I think you might be getting the idea now.
Let me do another one in green.
Let's say I had--
and this one actually confuses a lot of people.
Let's say I had zero point two five percent.
So the important thing to remember is, I'll rewrite here.
Zero point two five-- and maybe I'll write zero zero point--
And you're probably wondering why I'm doing this,
but I think you'll see in a second why I wrote that leading zero there
even though it doesn't seem to add much to it.
Zero zero point two five percent.
Well, what's the system I just showed you?
You get rid of the percent sign,
and you move the decimal over one, two spaces.
So that equals point zero zero two five.
So point two five percent is equal to point zero zero two five.
And you could put a leading zero here if you want.
Actually, I should probably tell you to always do that
because it makes it easier to read.
So point two five percent is equal to point zero zero two five.
And I want to just contrast that with twenty-five percent.
Twenty-five percent, what do you think that equals?
Well, you do the same thing that we've been doing.
You get rid of the percent sign and you move the decimal space.
In this case-- actually, let me leave that there.
I'll just rewrite it here.
Twenty-five percent.
And you're probably saying, where is the decimal in this?
Well, the decimal is after the number
because that twenty-five percent is the same thing as twenty-five point zero percent.
So if we get rid of the percent sign,
we move the decimal over two spaces to the left,
and that equals point two five as a decimal,
or point two five zero, but we can ignore that last zero.
So twenty-five percent equals point two five,
while point two five percent is equal to point zero zero two five.
And I want you to maybe sit and think about how small of a number point two five percent is.
Let's do a couple more
and maybe we'll convert going the other direction.
Let's say I have the decimal point zero one
and I wanted to convert that into a percent.
Well, here we just do it the opposite.
We could look at it two ways.
We could say well, whatever number this is,
we multiply it by one hundred and add a percent sign.
So if you say point zero one times one hundred,
and then we'll add a percent sign.
So point zero one times one hundred?
Well that's just one.
You could do the math.
You add the percent sign.
Well, that equals one percent.
Or an even easier way, when we go from a percent to a decimal,
we move the decimal place over two to the left.
So when you go from a decimal to a percent,
we'll do the opposite.
We move the decimal two to the right.
So if we do that, let me just rewrite it.
Point zero one.
Just go one, two.
The new decimal place is here.
If I get rid of that decimal, that's zero one decimal zero zero-- whatever.
Obviously, this leading zero means nothing,
so that's the same thing as one point zero zero.
Which is the same thing as one.
And does it make sense that moving the decimal space two to the right--
that's really just the same thing as multiplying it by one hundred, right?
If I multiply something by ten,
it's like moving the decimal space one to the right.
If I divide something by ten,
it's like moving the decimal space one to left.
Let's do a couple more while I have time.
I think I have three more minutes.
Let's say I had one point two five,
and I wanted to convert that to a percent.
Well, the easiest way is just to take-- I'll rewrite it here.
One point two five.
Take the decimal point, move it two to the right.
That's here.
And then I'll add a percent.
So that equals one hundred twenty-five percent.
And if you think about it,
the way people talk about percent it makes sense.
If I told you that I'm going to pay one point two five
times the price of something.
That makes sense that that's also one hundred twenty-five percent of the price.
Or if it doesn't make sense,
hopefully if you do these problems enough it will start to make sense.
Let's do a couple of more.
And you can go back and pause this if you think I'm going too fast,
which I might be doing.
Let me think.
If I were to say point zero zero three
and I want to write this as a percent.
Well, once again,
we can move the decimal space two to the right.
So one, two.
And that's analogous to multiplying it by one hundred.
So if we multiply the decimal two to the right
we get zero zero decimal point three.
And then we add the percent.
These don't-- at least this first leading zero doesn't mean anything,
so that's the same thing as zero point three percent.
The important thing to realize
is when you're converting from a percent to a decimal or a decimal to a percent,
you're really just moving where that decimal point is.
And if you run out of space,
you just have to add or get rid of zeros accordingly.
And the important thing to always have in your mind is,
when I convert from a decimal to a percent,
the number in front of percent signs going to get bigger.
And when I go from a percent sign to a decimal,
I'm going to get a smaller number.
If I say twenty-five percent, that's the same thing as point two five. Right?
So this is a percent, and this is a decimal.
So I went from a bigger number, twenty-five, to a smaller number, point two five.
Twenty-five percent is equal to point two five.
Similarly, if I had a decimal, let's say point one.
When I convert it to a percentage,
it's going to be a larger percentage.
So point one is the same thing as ten percent.
And how did I do that again?
Well I said point one, I added an extra zero
because I'm going to have to move the decimal space over to the right twice.
So I go one, two, and I get a ten.
Ten percent.
Hopefully that answers all your questions for now.
Have fun!