Hey. Hey Square.
Where have you been all this time?
With you we sang. And with you we labored.
We fought our fears. And we prayed.
All as one hand. Day and night.
And with you nothing is impossible.
The voice of freedom brings us together.
Finally our lives have a meaning.
There is no going back. Our voices are heard.
And the dream is not forbidden anymore.
Hey. Hey Square.
Where have you been all this time?
You brought down the wall. You lit the light.
You gathered around you a broken people.
We were born anew.
And a stubborn dream has been born.
We've disagreed with good intentions.
Sometimes things weren't clear.
We'll protect our country and our children's children.
We'll protect the rights of the lost lives of our youth.
Hey. Hey Square.
Where have you been all this time?
With you we felt and started
After we had been far and had come to the end.
We have to change ourselves with our hands.
You gave us a lot and the rest is up to us.
Sometime I worry that you'll become a memory.
That you'll become distant from us and the idea will die.
And we'll go back and forget what happened.
And tell stories about you in our tales.
Hey. Hey Square.
Where have you been all this time?
The Square is full. With all kinds.
The reckless one. And the courageous.
There is the passionate one. And the one who are on a ride.
The loud one. The quiet one.
We get together. Drink tea.
We now know how to get our rights.
You let the world hear us.
And you let the neighbors get together.
Hey. Hey Square.
Where have you been all this time?
Our idea is our strength.
Our weapon is our unity.
The square says the truth.
It always says no the oppressor.
The square is like a wave.
There are people riding it. Others are pulled in by it.
People outside of it calling it chaotic.
And what has been done is now written.
Hey. Hey Square.
Where have you been all this time?