Presented by KM Culture
in association withShowbox/Mediaplex, Inc
REALies PicturesKM Culture production
Released byShowbox/Mediaplex, Inc.
Original Storyby Suzuki Yumiko
Forget about him.
And coming here every week
won't change your fate.
If that were the case,I'd be making a fortune.
But it's not.
Should I tell you again?
You've had a tough life,and you will.
And you don't standa chance with this man.
I wish otherwise,but it's the truth.
Don't tell meit's written on my face.
It is.
But you never know.
Then why try to find out?
I'll write you an amulet.
Look at your hair.When'd you wash it?
Have him carry this.
I can't guarantee anything.
Free of charge.Take it and leave.
What?
Let me bow to you.
You don't need to.
To show my gratitude.
No, just go.
Thank you.
Way to go, girl.
Keep it up.
I'm so curious.What are you good at?
Oh, not that.
Yes, that's it. I love it.Hit me with a belt.
produced byPARK Moo-seung, WON Dong-yeonWhy do I do this?
You don't need the lookfor this job.
And I need to make lots of money.For my dad.
- Tell me your body size.- That's it for today.
Tell me your body size.
It's a secret.
Please!
You'll be amazed.
Yes... Tell me.
My bust is 34 inches.Waist is 24, and hip is 36.
What is it?
Bang!
Answer the phone.
My wife is in the shower.
I'm so scared.Why is she showering?
- Honey.- Yes?
starring by JOO Jin-moShe's just taking a shower.
- You think?- Calm down.
Should I sing youyour favorite song?
KIM A-joongShould I sing youyour favorite song?
Jesus blessed me with...
Most of my customers havebeen emotionally hurt.
Honey, cheer up.
I'll help you through this.
Okay, I'll take them off.
What?
Here we go. You're a nurse today,giving me a shot.
Pull down your pants.
I have to stay hidden.
directed by KIM Yong-hwait's my voicethat makes people happy.
it's my voicethat makes people happy.
Don't be mistaken.My real job is a singer.
200 POUNDS BEAUTY
HAN Sang-jun. A man who'sgiven me a reason to live for.
Sang-jun, you're my light.
Sang-jun, can I love you?
Sang-jun... Sang-jun...Sang-jun!
Hanna? Hanna!
Ammy, turn around. Now!
- Damn it!- Chorus, take over!
Hanna? Hanna?Can you hear me? Hanna?
Hanna? Can you hear me?
- Sang-jun, I'm fine.- Okay.
Ammy, at the count of 3.
Three!
Two!
One!
Good job.
Encore my ass!
What's wrong?
It was a good show.Thanks.
Tired?
Don't you ever dance.
You almost blew it.
I dance along with youto make it seem real.
Are you performing?
Wear a sweat shirt.
There isn't any that fits me.
Sang-jun?
Why'd the stage collapse?
Good job.
Great job.
You okay?
They built the stage poorly.
I was worried sick.
Okay.
I need to assess the situation.
So he's interested in you?
It's the feeling.He's very nice to me.
Save it.
There are 3 types of womenfor men.
Look. Pretty ones.They're a treasure.
The average ones.We're a present.
You? A reject!Get it now?
Don't eat the fat.
Listen.I have a woman's intuition.
It's your illusion.
Intuition is from experience.
Have you ever been in love?
- Tell me.- Have I been in love?
Yes, I have. My first love.
Sweetie?
Did I ask you to buydiet pills from me?
What am I?
A guy who sells you diet pillscosting 3 grand?
Don't say that.
Your business is slow.I just wanted to help.
It is.And you're not helping.
You made me feelso miserable.
I'm sorry.
I'm warning you.Don't do it again.
Give pills to Jung-min.
You're as pretty as you are.
Try to lose weight,and we're through. Okay?
These are checks.
- Okay.- Endorse them.
Just do the first one.
If you do this again,we're done.
It was the last of him I saw.
I'm sorry. I don't deservea girl like you.
I'll pray for you to meetsomeone better than me. Amen.
That day,I decided not to eat.
And to lose some weight.
Move.
This requires a skill.Grab that end.
Lift her at the count of 3.
One, two, three.
Lift her.
I said at the count of 3.
You lifted at 2. Hey!
Yes?
Lift at 3, okay?
We need to work together.
Grab it.At 3, okay?
One, two, three!
Bring that bed.
Put them together.
We'll roll her over.
I'll do it.
Excuse me?
I'll roll over.
Why didn't you wake her?
I learned that night.
I'm not cut outfor love and diet.
It's Hakuna Matata.
Africans believe
it grants them their wishes.
Oh!
Nicely done.
Are you hung over?
Give it some feelings.
God!
It's a vital part.
Try to feel the rhythm.
It's taking forever.
She's trying hard?
Is trying hard enough?
Everyone does that.
Doing well is what counts.
Like you.
Keep up the good work.
- Chances are slim.- I believe in you.
Why does my hope get higher?
Thanks for the ride.
You're welcome.
Who are you visiting?
Someone that I love.
Who's he?
Check me out.
Sorry! Bye.
Wait. I'm having abirthday party tomorrow.
Don't miss it.
I'm dancing with my dad.But he's dancing with my mom.
What do I mean?
Darling, how's Hanna?
I told you.She's become a singer.
And she's in love.
Darling? Why do youget heavier by the day?
Let's keep on dancing.
A delivery for you.
"Hanna, I'm so gratefulfor your hard work."
"Wear this dressto my birthday party."
"HAN Sang-jun" HAN Sang-jun?
It's a dress?
What's this?A strap on the bus?
I'm not so sure.
Hi!
Hi.
Hanna, sit here.
Come on.Pass around drinks.
Excuse me.Excuse me. Sorry.
You could've come around.
Thanks.
Just come!
I got you something.
You shouldn't have.
Oh, I love this.
Thanks.
Take off your coat.It's so heavy.
Aren't you hot?Make yourself comfortable.
Yes.
Go ahead.
You sent it.So I'm wearing it.
Yeah?
Yeah, Hanna.
Wear a dress likethat more often.
I'm totally fine with that.
Right?I love the design.
She's here.
Is she the Queen?You don't need to announce her.
Let her in.
Where are you going?
I feel like dancing.
Let her through.
- Hold on.- What?
They're cleaning.Use the other restroom.
You're so funny.
How stupid can you get?
I'd never know.
I wanna live with style.
But you're not helping.
That's a problem for me.
Miss backup dancer days?
The bitch gets on my nerves.
If so, you sing.
You think I like her?
You don't have to remind her
what a turnoff she is.
Leave her be.
Be grateful she's come to us.
I'll teach her a lesson.
Give me back the keysto the house and the car.
Then teach her a lesson.
Why are you crying?Why?
Hanna is the one to be crying.
She's talented,but ugly and fat.
You're untalented,but gorgeous and sexy.
You got it all going.
She exists for you.
Listen.We're just using her.
Understood?Be nice to her.
If she walks, it's over.
I couldn't be happierdreaming about you.
Even if it didn't last long...Thanks for making me happy.
Thank you so much.
My wife is showering again.
Why can't I die with style?
I'll make love to her,but it's gonna be hard.
I wanna hear your voice.
Aren't you there?
Pick up the phone.
What a story!Don't tell me you made it up.
Can you make it happen?
Your willpower can.
All I do is to remove a scar
from your hurt soul.
How much will it cost?
I'm a doctor,not a businessman.
Is it expensive?
All the things you want donewith 30% discount...
I'll pay you every pennywith interest.
Can I do it on credit?
- Ms. KIM?- Yes?
Will you show this lady out?
Don't validate parking.
Jesus protects meHow blessed I am
Don't you recognize my voice?
Shall we goto the injection room?
And tear up stockings?
Right.
Did you make love last nightafter she showered?
Who did the eye jobon that patient yesterday?
It was horrible.
And what's up with mealsfor patients?
They complained to me.
Get out! Leave!
Who are you?
I know you're a good person.
You've given your wifea full body makeover.
Now you dreadlaying your hands on her.
You must know how I feel.
I've done crazy thingsduring phone sex.
You say they don't respectplastic surgeons.
That's because they don'tdeal with lives.
I'm doing thisso I can live a life.
Not to satisfy my vanity.
It's the right causeyou've been looking for. Right?
Did you memorize all that?
You could die from all these.
I died yesterday.
Go ahead.
I knew you'd do thatso I made a copy.
You'll put it on the net?
You can't blackmail me!
My life is in your hands.
You can end it.Or save it.
- Yes?- Get me my operation schedule.
These eyes.
What about a nose?
Okay, this.Without a mole.
Pick the face shape
from these actresses.Which one?
Kate Moss!
Meet a skinny, pretty master
and live happily. Okay?
Love... I love you!
Here we go.Count backwards from ten.
Ten, eleven, twelve...
Backwards!
Nine, eight, seven...
Ammy's 2nd album postponed
You call yourself an agent?Don't take it out on me!
How can you do this to me?
Call me now,or I'll report you missing.
Years of suffering is over.
Make peace with yourselfand enjoy freedom.
What was once you...It's gone forever.
We'll redo the nose.
You bought me thissaying that I'd be as pretty.
Remember?
I'll be pretty soon.
That...
That's me?
Sir, it's flawless.
That's the only flaw.It's too natural.
I even cry prettily.
Hey! Take it easy.Your jawbone will drop.
- Hi.- Hi.
Nurse Locker Room
# I'm a beautiful girlSo beautiful
# Beauty is my weapon
# I'm a beautiful girl
# So beautifulEverybody loves me
Line up, please.
What a surprise to see youat a signing event.
I love your sitcom.Rating is 5%?
That's hard to achieve.
5%!
Give me those songsyou're not using.
For Pink.
Bye. Smile, dude.
Miss?
That's for your eyes.
I don't wanna do the sitcom.
It cost me a fortuneto get you in it.
Get in the car.
Sure.
Sir?
Are you okay?
God, it must hurt.
What a waste!
Were you delivering? Or...
You got a cut here.
What am I doing?I'm sorry.
Dude, are you okay?
- Are you okay?- Yes.
An automatic transmissionwith full options.
You're into speed?
What?
How much is this?
I wouldn't recommend it.
It has a lot of miles on it,
and the brakes are bad.
No air conditioning?
What do you expectfor 5 grand?
It's pretty bad.Who would buy this?
- I'm sorry.- It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
This can bea good practice car...
...for novice drivers.
Check out something else.
I'd be happyto get rid of this junk.
But my consciencewon't allow me.
Bye.
Come on.
You know what?You're gorgeous.
Don't mind me saying this.
You're beautiful.
I made the right decision.
I needed a car.
The seatbelt?
It's only 5 grand.No problem.
"You're gorgeous."
"You're beautiful."
It's a bad business day.
And you've added insultto injury.
Get out of the car.
Get out!
I'll bill youfor a year's treatment.
I can't believethis is happening.
See what she's done?
Damn!
What'd you honk for?
Get the hell up, asshole.
What?
Fucking lunatic.
No name calling, asshole!
Bring it on, fuckface!
Yeah, run!
What a moron!
Can you believe this?
She has no conscience.
Damn!
Sir...
If you can't drive, don't!
The road is so wide.Why crash into me?
I live from hand to mouth,and you ruined...
- You okay?- What?
You look familiar.Ever been in my taxi?
You're blocking the traffic!
Direct the traffic.Move it.
We have an accident here.
You okay?
Yes.
Not hurt?
No, I'm totally fine.
God!
Hey, you're bleeding.
Are you okay?
Absolutely.
But...
It doesn't hurt.This is embarrassing.
I'm really okay.
The damage to your car is bad.
Know any garage?I know a good one.
What's your cell number?
What?
I saw the whole thing.
You cut in front of her.
Didn't I?What was I thinking?
Check her license.
She might not have one.
Are you a cop?
Check her license!
Can I see it?
Here.
There's nothing to worry.
If your friend confirms your ID,we'll let you go.
I knew she didn't havea license.
How convenient.Plastic surgery?
Which hospital is it?I should get it done, too.
Ma'am?Her friend is coming.
We don't need her, do we?
Right.
Hanna?
Pork.
I want some... Pork.
Why didn't you feed her?
We sure did!
You should've fed her3 portions at a meal.
Let's get out of hereand eat some pork.
God, you've lostso much weight.
When'd you get a perm?
Jung-min?
Do I know you?
Hanna?
You...
It's really you!
What?
The silicon might slipout of place.
Look at you!
What? Go where?
I shouldn't?
They'll recognize you.
You disappeared a year ago.
They've been lookingall over for you.
You ruined Ammy's 2nd album.
They're looking hardfor your replacement.
I can be the replacement.
They'll like mesince I have the same voice.
No?
If they find out, you're done.
You didn't recognize meuntil I told you.
No way!
I hate myselfI know I'm fool
But, I can't stop loving youIt hurts me
You're hurting my ears.See you later.
I'm just so nervous.
Give me another shot.
Get out!
Okay.
Excuse me? Here.
A Korean-American?
Yes.
Send her in.
Jenny?
It says hereyou're fluent in Korean.
A little bit.
Lose those shades.
Face us, will you?
Hit it.
# The wind knocks on the window
# Over the room as small as me
# Twinkling stars so beautifulFilling the room with love
# Don't be hurt
# Caressing my wound gently
# Embracing me to sleep
# Too hurt for my legs to walk
# Eyes so blurry with tears
# Before loveNever meant for me
# I will keep on smiling
She's a slugger.
Look at her, man.She's far from a slut.
# Like those starsembroidered in my eyes
# I will love you forever
I think it's over.
Wait outside, please.
Okay.
We're good now!
We're good!
Sang-jun, congratulations.
Putting out my album now?
Leave us alone.
Leave.
Ammy, let's go.
Look.
Can't you see who she is?
Huh?
You know me, don't you?
I think I know you.
You can tell?
You can, can't you?
Of course I can.
Why can't you be honest?
Thought you could fool me?
I'm sorry.I'm so sorry.
Listen. I just...
You're no different.Why lie to me?
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
The department store,the used car market...
You followed me?
Thought I wouldn't know?
You told her I'm the bestproducer in the business?
Yes, I am.
Why couldn't you face me...
...and tell meyou wanna be a singer?
Yes, I do.I want to be a singer.
Right?
Yes, she'll be awesome.A top singer.
Let's go!
What's wrong with you?
Bye.
She's a dog.
Why the tears?
Look what you did.You made her cry.
By the way...Let's get your face fixed up.
Slit your eyes biggerand get your nosed raised.
No! No way.
You know what?
I'm too scared to gounder a knife.
Plastic surgery?I would never do it.
It's for those who lackconfidence in themselves.
What?
Wait.
Are you telling meI'm not pretty enough?
No, I'm not.
A natural beauty?I love it!
Good for building your image.
Right, Sang-jun?
So you're all natural?
I surely am.
Let's sign a contract.
Take a good look at her.
Think about it, Dad.
Jenny has a qualitythat you can't find...
...in any other girls today.
What's so special about her?
She looks a bit awkward.
Personally, I prefer Ammy.
An image of innocence.A natural beauty.
It's what money can't buy.
Right. That's what it is.
You're sleeping her,aren't you?
She's not a tramp.
She has a special qualitythat money can't buy.
Can't you see that?
You're a hound dog.
Look who's talking.
Dad?
Come on!
We don't need his help.Let's just do it.
Don't disappoint me.
It'll speed up things.
I can't kiss his ass anymore.
Come on!
What?
This isn't so like you.
What's your good quality?
Perseverance!
Why trashing it now?
I'm counting on you. Big brother.You trust me, don't you?
Don't call me that.I'm only 13 months older.
Let's do this, okay?
God damn it!
You're bad!
Dad, please... Dad!
Okay, that's it.
Just like that.That's good.
Good! Okay!
Ammy!
Drag it out at the end.
They'll go crazy.
Pee...
Pee... Pee is coming.
Excuse me? Nurse!
What's new isn't always good.
That's not it.
You're making me sickof what I had before.
You want me to walk?
You'll be sorry.
I never look for a dogthat's run.
I always find my dog,no matter what.
Watch me. I'll find Hanna.
Don't bring Hanna up!
Stop talking about her.
More coming.
If she was worriedabout her father...
...she would've showed uplong ago.
You're wasting your time.
Focus on the sitcom.Memorize your lines.
I'm a singer.
You realized that now?
Hello?
I'm a singer. A singer!
I want to be a singer!
A singer!
God is the only onewho can do everything.
We humans dowhat we're capable of.
Jung-min, look at him.
He's been waving at me.
What took you so long?
I've been admiring you.
What are we doing today?
We're making you happy.
How does that sound?
That's right.I'm THE Jenny.
Put suntan oil on me.
Why should I?
You have nice boobs.
Of course.You know how much...
I love them so much.
They're natural, right?
You're a natural beauty,aren't you?
Of course!It's done so naturally.
I'm natural.
Turn around.Come on. Good.
Hey, you're so fair-skinned.You're from California, right?
Yes.
Did you live in the basement?
You look like a bean curd.
So tacky. Never got a tanning?Never been to a tanning saloon?
So? You covered your breastsfor 3 hours?
You thought they'd popinside the tanning machine?
That's a load of bullshit.
She got a boob job, too.
You're talking about oneon that sitcom, right?
She has bags of saline solutionfor boobs.
They hurt when touched.
And they don't feel goodto touch.
That's whyI put silicone bags in you.
Right?Not because they're cheaper.
Right? Please, tell me.
I'm sad. So sad.
Do you know what it is?
It's lack of confidence.Didn't I tell you?
Unless you act confidently,
you can't win his heart.
Beauty is attitude, okay?
This is an engine.
No way I'm doing that.
# Here we go again
# Make it hot, Baby
# Oh. Don't be afraid
# High in the sky
# The sun shines the way
# Oh. Don't you stop, Baby
# Maria...
Let's call it a day.
What do you say?
The video quality is good.
What cam did you use?
Not that.What do you feel from her song?
Her song carries her heart...
...for someone that she loves.I think. No?
Can't you sing like her?
You care too muchabout how you look.
Come on, she's ugly.
You must've been embarrassedseen with her.
Stop it!
She was special to me.
You're here, thanks to her.
Still...
You're no half of her.
Why are you crying?
Are you nuts?
So you'll confess to him?
After all this?
You've committed a fraud.
So I should do itbefore it's too late.
He'll understand.
Remember 3 types of womenI told you about?
I'm a pretty one now.
No, it doesn't apply.
You know why?
Those with plastic surgeryaren't women. But monsters.
Jung-min...
What are you,an expert in relationships?
You sound like you havetons of experience.
More than you.At least, my love isn't one-way.
Oh, you're in a crazy love?
With whom? This guy?
Is he in love with you, too?
Or trying to sell you stuff?
You ransacked my bag?
You didn't empty the pocketsafter wearing my clothes.
Whatever it is...Don't buy anything from him.
I'm not like you.
I know. Like I did.No, like the old Hanna.
Don't do everything his waylike a fool.
At the end of the day, you getthe same thing. "We're too different."
He'll never sayyou're ugly and fat.
Like the old saying,nothing beats experience.
Confess to him.
What are you doing here?
That video...Should we study it more?
Come in.
Mr. CHOI once told me.
Do many Korean girlsdo plastic surgery?
I'm just asking.
What do you think about it?
Didn't you tell meyou didn't understand?
What are you doing?
You said it was for thosewho lack confidence.
I think the same.Stop it.
Come here.
Sorry. Let's go.
We're doing the concert.
It's been a while.
Love!
How'd you end up here?What happened?
I'm sorry.It's my bad. Love!
You feed her raw fish?
Why am I yawning?She loves raw fish.
Anyway, we're on the same pageabout plastic surgery.
Go away.Then again...
Desire to become prettyisn't a bad thing.
Men who are only afterpretty women are bad.
And these days...Okay, okay. And these days...
Hey. Bang!
And it's like cosmetics today.
Why do they hide it then?They hate revealing it.
It's a lame self-justification.
Can't you see?
That's why you stand outin this business.
This is fresh.Eat some.
About plastic surgery...
I've thought about it.
I think I can understand.
Only if it's not my girl.
I absolutely hate it.
But I understand.
Let's go.
Go, Natural beauty!
Goodnight.
Jenny!
Out of the way!
Hi.
What's wrong?
You shot a film here.
How long has it been?
Who put you up to this?
Put it out.
Nobody did.I just like her so much.
Aren't you that delivery man?
That's right.You remember me.
I understand, but...
Why laughing?
It tickles.
If this gets out,it's the violation of publicity.
I like her so much, and...
You like her so much...
...but didn't carehow she feels being watched?
Documenting her private lifeis a crime.
No, it was for myself.
Stop laughing.
This is what stalkers do.
Aren't you ashamedof yourself?
Wait.Don't be too harsh.
Give him a break.He did it out of liking me.
What's the big deal?
What's a person to dowhen all they can do is...
...watch from afar?
Do you have any ideawhat it feels like...
...not being able to confessone's love?
Excuse me.
How do you know so wellhow I feel?
This is whatyou had to say, right?
Daddy...
Ammy!
Let go of me. Let go.
Becoming someone new?
You have to forget yourself.
Your past, memories...Erase them all.
I even sweat pretty.
Maria.
Ave maria, a~ maria~ mari
Practicing at the saunawill help.
Tell me.Do you have to sing?
Of course! Singers sing.You kidding me?
No. All I'm saying is...
Do what you can.
You'd be God if you dideverything you want.
What?
It's what my dad says.
God is the only onewho can do everything.
We humans dowhat we're capable of.
You're a phony
Is this van a phony?
Jenny, it's your phone.
Hello? What?Jung-min did?
To a hospital? Why?
Jung-min tried to kill herself.
It's your first TV show.You can't screw it up.
My friend is more important!
We were quiet worried.
But we found nothingin her stomach.
It'd been digested.
30 sleeping pills can belethal for others.
So she's in a coma?
She's just sleeping.
Like a bear hibernating.
It can't be explained medically.She was lucky.
30 sleeping pills couldkill an elephant.
What's this?
She bought this?
A home sauna?
Jenny?
I've been calling you, Babe.
What's going on?
Think of what you wantfor lunch.
Hey, Su-jin.How are you?
Su-jung! I meant Su-jung.
Wanna go swimming?
Excuse me.
I'll call you back.
Did you dump herbecause you loved her?
Why so fast?
You should've waited to seewhat a home sauna can do.
Did you tell hernot to go on a diet?
"I'll be upset if you lose weight."You told her so?
Why didn't you be a manand tell her the truth?
That you hate her being fat.And you were desperate...
...to sell your products.
If you loved her...
Why'd you have to dump her?
You bastard!
Wait! What's wrong?
You don't know?Is it a crime to be ugly?
We're not charity cases.I have so much to say, but...
Wait! Who are you?
Damn!
What's going on?
Who's this?
Who are you?
Oh, you're in this together.
Calm down!
Hey! You two are dead.
Stay right here.
I'll call the cops.
You okay?
My nose...
Call the cops.Or take this and shut up.
What'd I tell you?
That miniskirt isan invitation to a rapist.
Look what happened.
Sorry. What if I was late?Let's go.
Get her dress!
She's here.1 minute to go. Standby.
What happened?
How much time?
Look who's here.Isn't this Sang-jun?
What's that?Is that her concept?
Sang-jun, this conceptdoesn't appeal to me.
Hurry!
Don't worry.They'll love your voice.
This is it.
Show them what you got.
We can't lose to them.
Right.
Can you do it?
Okay. I believe in you.No matter what...
Get a room!Get out there!
Okay, Jenny.
They're not a couple.Trust me.
Here is Jenny!
"Maria"
# Here we go again
# Make it hot, Baby
# Oh, don't be afraid
# High in the skyThe sun shines the way
# Oh, don't you stop, Baby
# Maria Ave maria
# Fly and catch those clouds
# Strong against violent waves
She's pretty good.
# Maria Ave maria
She's good.
# Fly and catch those clouds
# Maria Ave maria
# Strong against violent waves
What's her concept?
It's singing.
What's yours?
Strawberry milk?
# Maria Ave maria
# Flay and catch those clouds
# Strong against the violent waves
# Maria~
This sauna thing is okay.
You're a phony
Thanks to a new model,the sales have...
Skyrocketed! Dad?
Spit out the gum.
"Jenny"
"New star comes up!"
I'm drunk.God, this is awkward.
He'll know they're fakeif he touches them.
Not there.
Not there, either.
Should I sing for you?
You wanna work now?
This way.
What?
Come on.
Jenny?
Answer it.Answer it, will you?
I know it all.
You even watch porn.
What are we doing?
What type do you want?
A nurse, a high school girl,a secretary?
What? A nurse?
Okay, it's a favorite pick.A nurse it is.
Jenny, open the door.This isn't it.
Just try to relax.It'll help.
What should I do with it?
Should I rip it?
See? There you go.You can wear it over your head.
Hakuna Matata. The African symbolhas granted me my wish.
Do many Korean girlsdo plastic surgery?
Do you know how it feelshiding your love?
You wrote this song?
Yes.
When you were writing it...What came across your mind?
I just wrote itlooking at the stars.
What are you doing?
Watching porn again?
About last night...It never happened, okay?
Last night...
Leave, will you?Let me finish watching porn.
Jenny's Album Launching Party
Pull that up. If Sang-jun sees it,he'll be upset. Hello?
Damn, she's almost naked.I'll be back.
Hey. Hey! Congrats!Your fan is here.
Someone dying to see you.
I can't hear you.What?
I brought this for you.
- Here.- What are you doing?
What are you doing?
Take it.
You know him?
Just... A fan of mine, I hear.
Who brought him?
Did you?
Take him back home.
He's your fan.Why didn't you take the doll?
Jung-min...
Let's go.
Still here?
Go to bed earlyfor the concert tomorrow.
I know that old man.
I know.He's your fan.
No. I mean he is...
Stop it. KANG Hanna.
What'd you just call me?
Don't worry.Nobody else knows.
I didn't, either.
When'd you find out?
Is that important?
You're Jenny now.
And it's Jenny'sfirst concert tomorrow.
How... You knewhe was my dad?
I gave both Hannaand Jenny a chance.
It's scary.So I'm only a product.
Hanna is worthless,
but Jenny is worth a fortune.Is that it?
Because of you...
That I've been deceiving you...It's been so hard.
Now I see I was a big fool.
Why'd you take my dog?
As a hostage?
That's enough.
You find me repulsivewith plastic surgery?
I said enough! Stop it.
So you avoided me.
Watch your voice.
I'll do the concert.I'll do it well. But...
Get rid of these.
They're repulsive and scary.
I'm fine.It doesn't hurt.
It's nothing, compared towhat I went through.
I cut off my bone and skin.
Laying on the table...
You know whom I thought of?
I never knew...
I thought that was painful.
But this is worse.
You broke my heart.Tissue won't fix it.
Now you cut yourself?
You should be able to fixsomething simple like this.
Give it a shot, okay?
Thanks, Doc.
That ticket is expensive.Please, come.
I want money,not a concert ticket.
God damn it!It's complimentary!
What's wrong?Aren't you going to the concert?
Someone sent this.
I'm sorry.I'll take the responsibility.
You will?
Okay then.Cancel the concert.
I can't do that.
Dad, that's unnecessary.
I will quit.
Stay out. If we don't,this will go to the press.
That she was a singerfor Ammy.
It isn't just about the label.
What about cosmetics?You'll eat them all?
You know the contractinside and out.
Unless you'll pay penalty,do as I say.
Put out her nude album.
Do it before it's too late.
We'll squeeze out of herwhatever we can.
Dad!
You're grown old.And scared.
Son of a bitch,I made you who you are!
Company's stock price...
You forgotwho helped it rise?
I know who's behind this.I'll handle it.
We're doing the concert.
And it'll be a success.
Let's go.We have a concert to do.
Get up.
Damn, he messed it up.
I made it worse.
You said it didn't hurt.But it does.
Don't worry about it.I'll handle Ammy.
Jung-min, last night...I'm sorry.
About what?
You brought my dad?
Your dad?
Oh, that old man?He slept at my place.
Cause he was lockedout of the hospital.
And, doesn't he have tosee your concert?
If you got a problem,tell me.
Then again,he means nothing to you.
Jenny! Jenny! Jenny! Jenny!
Why can't you do it?
I said it was okay.
Don't you get it?
This isn't for menor Ammy.
It's your show.Do it for yourself.
For nobody else,but yourself.
Stop!
I can't do this.
I really can't.
I'm sorry.I'm really sorry.
I'm not Jenny.
I'm Hanna. KANG Hanna.
I was an ugly, fat girl.
So... I sang for someone elsehiding in the back.
Then I got plastic surgery.
From head to toe...Everything.
Now that I'm pretty...
I can sing.
I've been in love.
I was so happybeing Jenny.
But I'm sorry.
I ruined it.
I've deserted my friend.
My dad.
And myself.
I don't know whoI am anymore.
I can't remember
what I looked like.I can't.
I miss you, Hanna.
Hanna...
That's me.
KANG Hanna.
It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
Dad!
Jenny isn't here.
But if you wanna hear...
...that fat, ugly girl sing...
Please, listen to me singonce for all.
# Crawling to me like a dream
# My little star up highDazzling my eyes
# Shining brightly
# Falling on my shoulders
# Don't be sad anymore
# Holding my hands tightlyCaressing my wound
# It embraces me warmly
# Too hurt for my legs to walk
# Eyes so blurry with tears
# Before loveNever meant for me
# I will keep on smiling
# Dear moments with you
# Buried deep in my heart
# Like those starsembroidered in my eyes
Look at you.
Your undershirt shows.
Can you tell?
No.
No, you can't.
Dad, I really didn't know.
Sang-jun, I love this.
# Like those starsembroidered in my eyes
# I will love you forever
"A Shocking ConfessionJenny was a fake!"
Jenny went down like that.Completely.
But Hanna made it.
How? Beats me.
Lower it a bit.Make it lower.
That's nice.
It's cool, isn't it?
Leave!
It's cool.
She's got more fans now.More anti-fans, too.
Hey!
"A pig"? I'll kill you!
Stay away from me!
I don't thinkshe likes me anymore.
I'm doing my best.
Your best isn't enough.Doing well is what counts.
I don't wanna admit it...
...but people sayI like her more now.
What do you like about her?
I don't know.
Because she's pretty?
Assholes like youwould say so.
Because she's innocent?
Assholes like mewould say so.
I'm the famous Dr. Lee,
known as Hand of God.
I might win the nextNobel Prize.
What do you want fixed?
My whole body.
Your whole body?