You Wanna Feel My Kiss, Boy You Can't Touch This
Robotic, Hypnotic! Hypnotic, Supersonic!
Superstar, come come come get it!
Is there a heart branching out of the iron
Is love calling on me for the first time
Is love calling me for the first time
Zero (0) goes with one There's scent of flower from today
There are stars in the sky and Lightning in my eyes
Searches within me that Google hasn't seen Girl
Oh girl, I have love for you, that the world has never seen
IRobot.. can I say I Love you in your ears
I Am A Super Girl [I'm your love, Rapper Girl]
You are all the numbers that are inside me
I will borrow electricity from the corner of your eyes
I shall smile with you using my blue tooth
I will hug you with my engine heart
I shall shut myself off when you go to sleep
I shall forever remain a toy in your hands
Watch Me Robo Shake It I Know You Want To Break It
You could get a shock when you touch me
My motor speed could increase when we make love
My battery could be flat at the middle of the night
I imprisoned the young girl in my memory
I was restless when you missed to shut me down at night
I kept reading you till my sensors stopped workings
It's because of you that I forgot my conventions
Will you accept my salivaless kiss without any fight
Will you ask me to leave because this is bloodless love?
I may be a robot biologically
But I am a cupid psychologically
I got the curse of eternity. I came onto earth
and brought along an everlasting love
Hey Robot, don't lure me
You Want it, come and get it Boy
Oh Are You Just A Robo Toy
I Don't Wanna Break You, Even Though it Takes 2
Kind Of Like A Break Through. You Dont Even Needa A Clue
You Be My Man's Back Up
I Think U Need A Check Up
I Can Melt Your Heart Down
May Be If You Got One
Been Doing This For Ages
Since The Time of Sages
Go away, don't hit on me
Are you a snake that goes around my legs
Romancing Robot
You're not needed. Go away
Is there a heart branching out of the iron
Is love calling on me for the first time
Zero (0) goes with one There's scent of flower from today
There are stars in the sky and Lightning in my eyes
Searches within me that Google hasn't seen Girl
Oh girl, I have love for you, that the world has never seen
IRobot.. can I say I Love you in your ears
I Am A Super Girl [I'm your love, Rapper Girl]
Robotic, Hypnotic! Hypnotic, Supersonic!
Superstar, come come come get it!