Liston: We are
so close to the end.
The deadline for submissions
is approaching very fast.
Tonight at midnight,
YouTube.com will no longer
be accepting entries.
But after eight
amazing years,
it is finally time
to review everything
that has been uploaded
to our site
and begin the process
of selecting a winner.
Kamangar:
We started YouTube in 2005
as a contest
with a simple goal:
to find the best video
in the world.
We had no idea we'd get
such a great response.
You've uploaded over 70 hours
of footage every minute,
and we've been blown away
by the variety, imagination,
and anything goes spirit
that has driven the competition.
Dodson: We are all
storytellers.
That's what pulled me
into this contest.
You know, like,
stories about
how to Photoshop,
and stories about
"The Hobbit" trailer HD.
I encourage everybody to watch
as many videos as possible
before YouTube deletes
everything tonight.
Liston: Every video that
has been uploaded to our site
will be reviewed by our staff
of 30,000 technicians.
They'll narrow down
the submissions,
and then our esteemed panel
will select the best video.
Which will be announced when
the website goes back online
in 2023, featuring the winner
of YouTube and nothing else.
Our team of judges is made up
of distinguished film critics,
YouTube celebrities,
and some of our most
prolific commenters.
Judge: Yes,
it's a product un-boxing.
But I think it adds
to the product un-boxing genre,
and it subverts
our expectations as an audience.
Judge 2: I don't suck, you suck,
and so does this video.
Dodson: Look,
I'm pretty sure
that the first ten minutes
of "Citizen Kane" is great,
but what I love about
"Epic Skateboard Fail"
is that it's short,
it's funny,
and it's straight
to the point.
Andrea: But is it
the best video on YouTube?
Judge: We're going to have
the same conversation
about all 150,000 videos
that we watch.
It's an amazing process.
Kamangar: We always
said that this
shouldn't be
a popularity contest.
"Gangnam Style" has
the same chance of winning
as a video with 40 views of
a man feeding bread to a duck.
KassemG: Of course
I'm hoping to win,
but even if I've inspired
just one person
and harass people
on the beach...
that's something I'll still
feel pretty good about.
Matt Harding: I better win.
Otherwise all those years
traveling the world
were just an expensive
waste of time.
iJustine: My strategy from day one has always
been to upload as many videos as possible.
I mean, it's all about shots on goal.
Rafi Fine: It's important to keep
pushing yourself.
We challenge ourselves every day to think
of groups of people that can react to something
that most people already know about. It's
important that the judges appreciate the risks
that we take as artists.
Harry: When we heard
about the contest,
we spent months trying
to come up with the best idea.
Then Charlie bit my finger.
And I was like,
"Write that down!"
Judson: I did dancing.
David: My dad
put a lot of money
into this dental surgery
I didn't even need
just so we could
win this contest.
He'll be really,
really upset if we lose.
Liston: It's not just
about the recognition
of being
the world's best video.
As promised, when YouTube
started back in 2005,
the winner will also walk away
with an MP3 player
that clips to your sleeve
and a $500 stipend
for your next creative endeavor.
So, remember, get all of your
last-minute submissions
in by tonight at midnight.
While your work's finished,
ours is just beginning.
It's gonna be
an exciting decade.