Honey~!
Hey, you can't kick that...
Jeez...
You haven't changed one bit.
Oh it's you, Boeun.
You're a big girl now. Great body!
Nice curves.
Drop it, okay?
Hey, you little girl!
Hey, give me a break!
They look so nice and shiny...
Stop staring. You'll sprain your eyes.
No, it's just that they look familiar.
Anyway, what brings you here?
Did you miss me so much that you had to skip school?
No, it's the school's anniversary.
I was forced to come here.
I'm wasting my time when I really have to study.
Yeah, there's only 2 years left till the national exam.
But people like you really make college look undesirable.
What do you mean?
You're a pervert and a playboy.
I may be a playboy, but I'm not a pervert.
Here's your present.
It's just for you! Keep it a secret to the family.
Okay.
Pretty, isn't it? It's padded. Real thick.
You're a pervert!
Should I help you put it on?
- Should I?- Do you want me to punch you?
- My son! My son's home!- How have you been?
- Welcome home.- Thanks.
- How was your trip?- Fine. How have you been?
- Grandfather's waiting. Hurry.- Okay.
- Mom, it's heavy. I'll carry it.- Okay.
You've changed.
What was all the rush for? And is grandpa really sick?
Son, brace yourself, okay?
Delicious, isn't it?
I made it myself, just for you, grandfather.
Really tasty.
No one but you can take such good care of me.
Of course, I'm your only granddaughter.
You've really grown. Now you look like a lady.
She may have grown, but she's still a child.
I'd be married in the old days.
Right grandfather?
Absolutely. A married woman.
- Sangmin, come sit here.- Yes, grandfather.
You two, hear me out.
You may have heard this story before...
Sangmin's grandfather wasan old friend and war comrade
When we were young, we made a pact,
To marry our kids.
But you two had only sons.
So, our pact was passed down to the next generation.
I hope you two can keep this promise.
What are you saying?
You idiot! Grandpa wants you to marry Sangmin!
Marriage?
You must be joking grandpa!
Marry Sangmin?
Hey! Your grandpa's not kidding!
I can die peacefully after you two get married!
This way, I can face Sangmin's grandpa.
How can a high schooler get married!
Anyone over 15 can marry withtheir parent's consent.
I haven't much time left, you know?
No, I won't.
Never!
Sorry grandpa but I'll forget what you just said.
He hasn't finished speaking!
I'm speechless myself.
It's me. I'm back.
I'm back in Korea,standing in front of the department office.
Hey, there's lots of new blood in the department
- How are you?- Oh, yeah.
The chicks are great!Let's get together after class.
Hey, Sangmin!
What a surprise!
Has it been a year already?
No, I'm back for some family business.
How about you?
Great. My looks...
- keep me too busy...- Come on...
Come back when I'm the TA.It'll help when you skip classes.
Would I, a model student, do that?
Besides, it's my last year...
Friend, my good friend!
- How have you been!- Great dude!
Look at him! Life in the West has done you well!
What brought you back?Problems at home?
- Yeah something's up at home...- Huh? What?
- I'm getting married... damn.- Huh? Bastard!
Hey, is it a black or white girl?
Pounding!
Only you should know about it~
I'm just 17~
Come, come silently ~
Here and there~
Hey!
They're making such a fuss.Losers...
- Shh! They'll hear you.- Why? Do you think you're different?
My doctor said I have 20 more years to go!
Really?
Change of plans.I'll make my move. Just back me up.
I understand.
Good!
They switched it.
Isn't he the guy?
They switched it. Remember?
Yeah...
I really wish they wouldn't play those things on TV.
I guess the wedding's really on.
What am I going to do, mom?
Be strong, son.
Grant your grandpa this one wish.
Let's call it a day!
You're Suh Boeun, 1st grade, right?
You were so funny, don't you agree?
Hey, what?
Come on!
Who's he?
He's just a guy I know.
That's what they all say.
I'm telling the truth!
I really thought about it,
and I'll speak first.
- Let's just do it.- Are you crazy?
I'm kidding.
Do you think I'd want to?
I don't want to do it with you!
Even if I did,
it's insane. I'm just 15!
Okay, I got it.
Anyway, I'll buy you dinner.
Or anything else you need.
Mister, you're a sugar daddy, aren't you?
- Boeun.- Huh?
How can you do this to me?
I may be pretty, but
something like this...
Hey...
Hyewon, stop it!
- I'll leave you two to talk.- Huh?
See you later, Boeun.
- Remember, it's a secret.- I know.
- Bye.- Good bye.
- What's her problem?- It's understandable.
Hello? Yes...
What!
Good, good.
Grandpa!
- Grandpa!- Grandpa!
Grandpa, we're here!
Grandpa, Grandpa!
Grandpa, Grandpa!Wake up, Grandpa!
- Uncle, something's wrong!- What?
Grandpa!
It's doing it again.
We should've gone to another hospital!
It almost gave me a heart attack!
I was out of myself again.
Are you okay, grandpa?
- Let's have a word outside.- Okay.
Be by your grandpa's side, okay?
Yeah.
I'm really worried.
I know. With the kids like that, he's getting worse.
Come on... marriage is out of the question!
They... you have to think about Boeun's future.
Come on, let's just marry the kids.
Let go.
Come on...
This is Sangmin's grandparents.
Soon after this picture was taken, war broke out.
Do you want me to tell you a secret?
Secretly,
your grandpa had feelings for Sangmin's grandma.
She was quite a beauty.
However, after Sangmin's grandpa's death,
I tucked those feelings away.
That's why I took care ofSangmin's father like my own son.
Your father may not have been so happy about this.
- Boeun!- Yes?
Keeping this promise isthe most important thing for me.
- Grandpa!- Grandpa!
Grandpa, wake up. Grandpa!
You can't die!
Open your eyes, grandpa!
Grandpa, I'll get married so open your eyes, grandpa!
I'll keep your promise, grandpa!
I'll get married...
Are you crying?
Stop crying.
You may be behind in your grades,
but you're the nation's first to get married at this age.
Congrats, missus.
Right.
Are you scared that Sangminwill discover your lop-sided butt?
A butt that needs cushioningto keep it on balance?
- Hey, get out!- Ouch, it hurts!
I'm sorry Boeun, for not being much help.
Mom, am I really getting married?
What about school?
I have to go to college...
Marriage won't change anything.
Marriage, accept it with grace. It's nothing.
Just consider you're getting a new brother.
I'm scared that they'll find out at school.
How will I face everyone?
Don't worry. Grandpa will take care of it.
Your grandpa was your principal's military senior.
Really?
Behold the face of a wolfwho'll eat up a 15 year old virgin.
- Is it satisfaction or disbelief?- Satisfaction, of course.
Shit, are you really my friends?
I can't be married at this age.
- To Sangmin!- Cheers~
The chicks here are hot!
Let's go out on the floor!
Hello.
You're here. Thanks.
You're here.
- Sir!!- Yes, come in. Over here.
I won't forget this.
How could our field trip be at the same time?
I know.
You shouldn't keep it from your other friends.
If they found out,the whole school will know.
Then I'd have to quit school.
Anyway, you're so pretty today.I wish I could get married too.
Look here!
Hey, smile!
- How are you doing?- Hello.
- Don't take my picture.- Okay, okay.
Good luck!
I'm convinced that grandpa scammed me.
- Boeun, it's just a wedding, okay?- I can't do it, mom!
Now, don't be a baby.
I'm nervous myself.
I'm telling grandpa, "I can't do it!".
Do you want your wedding turned into a funeral?
I don't know.
I'm scared, mom.
What am I going to do with such a baby?
Now the groom will enter.Welcome him with a big applause.
The groom, please enter!
She's so beautiful!
Respectable guests,
family and relatives.
We are all gathered here tocongradulate the new beginning of
groom, Park Sangmin
and bride, Suh Boeun...
- Dad, we'll be okay.- Yeah, yeah.
Remember, she's only 15.
- What's your point?- I know I can trust you.
You forced me into this marriage, so I'll do as I wish!
Boeun is still in high school!
I don't care! I'll do as I wish with my wife.
Boeun, don't worry.Your father-in-law has had a word with Sangmin.
About what?
- That you... shouldn't do it...- What?
I can't say...
- Call us when you get there.- Yes, auntie.
Stop calling her that. It's mom from now on.
Yes, mom.
Hey, mom! Can I keep the bouquet?
It was so pretty...
Forget the bouquet...
She's such a child.
What am I going to do with you?
Stop, you promised to be cool.
- Bon voyage~- Yes, yes...
- Bye~- Follow right behind, okay?
It's time to board, where is she?
Boeun.
- Boeun? Where is it?- Over there...
- Okay, we'll go inside, thanks.- Okay, go.
- Thanks for everything.- Don't overdo yourself.
- Have a safe trip.- Yeah, give me the suitcase.
Have fun, Boeun.
Don't worry, dude.Be good, okay?
- See you later!- Bye. Bon voyage.
- I've never boarded on time...- Wait.
- What?- I need to go to the bathroom.
Again? It's your first time on a plane, isn't it?
Don't worry. It's only an hour to Jeju Isle.
It won't take long.
You're making such a fuss. Hurry back.
- I'll be at our seats. Hurry.- Okay...
Shit. Where is she?
- Sir, you must be seated.- The plane's leaving. Open the...
Sir, please seat yourself!
Mobiles are prohibited in the cabin.Thank you for your cooperation.
He must think he owns the plane.
It must be his first flight.
I don't believe this.
Wait sir.
- We're in a hurry.- Sorry.
Hey!
Did they arrive safely?
Yeah... they did.
I need to be clear about one thing.Listen!
Until Boeun graduates from college, no grandchildren!
Make this clear to your father as well.
Yes, of course.
When she was little,she would fall and break things,
but she seemed to holdherself well at the wedding.
It's a relief.
Why? Are you disappointed that she didn't fall?
Yes, a little.
Come on...
Not those idiots again!
Having fun?
Hey!
Hey, do you have a place to stay?
Just this once.
Press anything. Wind it and press.
Say cheese.
Take your best shot.
Uh, Sangmin?
I can't believe this!
What brings you here?
Boeun's on her honeymoonand we're on our fieldtrip.
- Don't you remember?- Of course I do.
- Where's Boeun?- Well...
- Hey! Who's the mister?- He's just a friend.
- He's cute.- See you later!
- Hey, stop it. Wait, come here.- Oh god...
Hey!
What are you doing on top of her!
You pervert! You chase after young girls,don't you!
It's not like that.
- I'm not...- Really.
- Really?- Really.
Then what are you doing?
- Uh?- Huh?
Look at him running off!
Aren't you supposed to be on your field trip?
Yes...
Then why are you here?
What are you doing today?
Nothing.
Do you have a boyfriend?
No...I don't.
The cell phone you are tring to reach is off.You will be transferred to a voice mail...
Pest, how can you do this to me...
Our parents shouldn't find out.We'll talk later. Bye.
Then, from now on we're dating.
Okay!
Hey you! Come here!
Wow! Looks so fun! Isn't it?
- Where are you from?- I'm from Canada.
Canada? I know Canada!
Who am I kidding?I've never set foot on Canada.
Teacher!
Hi, how are you?
Uh, Hyewon?
What brings you here at this hour?
It's free time for us.
Haven't you ever been on a field trip?
Of course I have.
Anyway, where's Boeun? Why are you alone?
I don't even know where to begin?It's like this...
Yes.
Boeun...
You're a serial pervert, aren't you!
Hey! Come back!
Feels good, doesn't it?
It's been a while... together. Sit here.
Stop.
Rest your back on this.
I feel great.
It's too late for this
but I'm sure that we did a horrible thing to Boeun.
She's only 15, and going through her 1st year of high school.
Come on! Be more positive.
You were considering him as your son-in-law anyway.
She's not going far away.Let's have some faith, okay?
Besides, our in-laws love Boeunlike their own daughter.
But, she's not their own daughter.
I can understand dad and you,
but I still can't forgive you for it.
Okay, okay, that's enough... enough...
Without Boeun,it seems like there's a big hole in my heart.
Everyone looks like Boeun, that one too...
Candy, sir? Thank you.
Candy, sir?
Boeun, help him.
Honey, honey, here.
Thank you very much.
- Grandpa!- Dad, come on out.
- Sit, sit and eat.- Okay.
So, how was your trip?
Good grandpa. We had a good time.
Yes, Sangmin was kind to me. I really had fun.
Stop, I didn't do anything.
I'm glad you had fun.
Since you're officially married,
love one another so we can seethe fruit of your love.
But you don't look so happy, Sangmin.
Are you sick?
Of course I'm not sick.
They're definitely a great couple,aren't they?
Your room's been cleaned,so go get some rest.
Yes sir.
Stop, we should have a drink with the new groom.
How about it dad?
Right. My grandson-in-law should pour me a drink.
As you wish.
Grandpa, I'll go to bed now.
Yeah, yeah.Go to your room...
Careful!
Honey!
Let's go!
- Hey! Boeun's not a thing.- Good night!
Hey! Be careful.
Hey! Hey!
- Have a good night.- Good night!
Honey!
Ah, you're heavy!
And you stink of liquor!
Hey! Hey!
- You're tearing my dress. Stop it!- Keep still!
He's coming on real strong.
This is the right place.Come in. Look at this tree.
Come in dad. Close the door behind you.
What do you think? Huh? It's nice right?
Look at this, great isn't it?
It's a great place.
Great place Boeun.
- Hey, you put up that picture!- Nice, isn't it? Great huh?
Look at the balcony. I chose this.
Boeun.
It's so clean.
Hey, look at this picture.This picture.
Where should I put this picture?
You're having the time of your life,aren't you?
- What's this, Arabian Nights?- Goodness!
- What's with the pillows...- Goodness...
Separate rooms until you graduate, okay?
I am so pissed!
I like it...
What's this, a flower garden?
What am I going to do?
Stop it!
Language is part of culture...
Language is... a part of... culture...
When we learn of foreign languages,we should also learn about...
that country's culture...
Ah, great!
Hey, stop! Put something on!
I always take everything off.Even my underwear.
Get out!
Out where?
This is my room.
What do you mean?
This is my room. Yours is over there.
Get out!
I don't feel like it.
Let's sleep together.
What, you're crazy!
You sleep together when you get married.
Boeun...
What?
- I think tonight is the night.- What?
Listen to me.
Stay away from me.
Come on. We're married.Boeun, do as I say!
Hey, stop it!
We're married! Do as I say and stay still.
Shit... I was just playing with you!
Oh my god!
Good morning, Boeun.
Your eyes are quite a sight!
Morning exercise?
What? You disappeared from the airport?
Then what did you doduring your honeymoon?
Who, me?
Can you keep a secret?
You have too many secrets.
I'm dating Jungwoo.
Jungwoo? What about your husband?
Husband... are you kidding?I was forced into it.
Then does Jungwoo know you're married?
No. But I'm sure he'll understand.
Let's go.
If I call her, she'll be here in an instant.
Are you sure she'll come if you call her now?
Of course. She'll say"Yes master" and then come.
You're such a liar.
Stop, she'll be studying anyway.
- Wait. I'll show you.- Dude, that's impolite.
- Tell her to come.- Wait.
Wife! It's me!
Your husband commands you to come!
Wow.
- Hurry!- Wow.
- Hurry!!- Wow.
Bye!
Now she'll fly here like a bullet.
Guys... let's drink!
I'm Sangmin. I'm a man, ain't I?
Of course you're a man.
I'm just teaching my wife a lesson, like a real man!
A man of all men. A real man.Have a drink, men!
Men!! Men, drink up!
Drink till we drop!
There'll be an inspection today.Go home and study.
Wife!
She's my wife. Come here wife!
- We're married!- Not today.
He's really her husband.
Welcome, Boeun.
You saw her at the wedding, my wife, Boeun.
How could you call me over to such a place...
like this?
Your husband says it's okay.
Another beer please!
Don't. Would you like a soda?
Yes...
A soda over here.
You're so adorable.
Thank you.
Of course! My wife's adorable.
She's a horrible cook, with a bad temper.
And a bad student.
- She also snores.- Sangmin! You're drunk.
- Stop drinking, okay?- No.
I'm jealous. I have no one to worry about me.
- Wow, I feel great. Bottoms up!- Bottoms up, bottoms up!
I never introduced myself.I'm Sangmin's senior, Han Jisoo.
I'm Suh Boeun.
Boing, boing, Boeun.
She goes boing boing every morning!
Jisoo, do you know what she didto me on our honeymoon?
Hey, Park Sangmin! Get off your butt!
Pretty please...
I'll see you again, Jisoo.
Yes. I'm sure we'll be good friends.
Treat me like a little sister.
But you're my senior in lifesince you're married.
Stop joking.
Stop joking, stop joking.
You know, you two are made for each other.
We were always at each other's throatswhen we were little.
Hitting and teasing each other.
He's the first boy to flip my skirt.
Funny. Boys are mean to girlsthey really like.
Jisoo, Jisoo, kiss me.
At least you could've fixed mesomething for my hangover.
You deserve it.
Besides, I'm still in high school.
You always use that line when you're cornered.
High school is not a crown, you know.
It is too, so there!
Okay, then I'll show you my cooking talents tonight!
- Hey, Suh Boeun!- What?
- Let's go.- Come.
Do you wanna get smacked? Come!
What do you want?
I heard you were telling everyoneyou were Jungwoo's girl?
Fucking unbelievable!
She's boasting that she's slept with Jungwoo.
The bitch thinks we're shit.How dare you, bitch!
Listen up. Watch your mouth.
If I hear about this again,you're dead meat!
Jungwoo and I are in love!
Have you lost your senses!
Hey! Didn't you get the message?
I didn't do anything wrong. I'm leaving!
Hey! How dare you...Lose your attitude!
What are you doing!
Fuck off.
What?
Hey, Lee Jungwoo,you can't treat me like that!
You're in no position to say that to me.
Listen up. It's true that Boeun and I are dating.
Don't mind them. They think they're princesses.
But you're the real princess.
Sesame oil, sugar!
- A small bottle of oil?- Yeah!
- This sugar?- Hurry, hurry.
Okay!
Vinegar, spaghetti, ketchup!
There's the vinegar...
And there's the spaghetti!
Here?
Here, the ketchup's here. Okay...
Hurry, hurry!
- Olive oil, pickles!- Olive oil, pickles!
Boeun!
Are you okay, Boeun?
Boeun, Boeun, Are you okay?
Are you okay?
Ow, my leg!
It hurts?
- Does it hurt bad?- No. Why? Get off?
Stay put before I change my mind.
Don't touch me there!
I'm not doing it on purpose.Why should I?
My hand just went there naturally.
What a great excuse!Now walk straight.
You slant to the right becauseyour butt is lop-sided.
Don't start with me.
I'm not kidding.
Your right butt has grown bigger.
Hey, stop it!
Stop it! Hey, stop it!
Lop-sided butt~Lop-sided butt~
- Stop it, stop it!- Okay, okay!
- Ladies and gentlemen!- Shut up...
Boeun has a lop-sided butt!
Lop-sided butt~
Look at how you're cutting.
You should put your heart intowhat you're cooking.
Just be quiet!
- Be quiet? I'm older than you...- Stop it!
Stop what? I'm older...Hey... You little...
- What?- Take my sword.
- Pest... aim at what you can take.- Hey, come here.
What are you going to do with that?
- Hey, stop it... it’s hot. Hot! Hey...- Hey...
Hey... that's not fair!
Ouch!
- It's delicious.- Yeah.
You got something on your mouth.
The same with you.
Rock, paper, scissors!Rock, paper, scissors!
Yes!
Make sure everything's spotless.It's more important than cooking.
Give me a break!
Hey, is it this side?
Hey! You pervert! If I were you, I would help!
This picture's great. I look so handsome.
Gotcha!
Sangmin... Don't come near me!
Stop it!
Don't come near me! Stop it, stop...
- Now, I'm taking everything off!- Stop!
- Thanks, the sushi's great.- Really?
The baseball field's empty.Aren't people coming to watch the game?
No one comes to watchhigh school baseball anymore.
It's pro- baseball or the major leaguethat they go to.
I hope you'll play in themajor league some day.
Hey, Lee Jungwoo!
Good luck!
I'm starved.
Double crust seafood...
This is pretty good.
Lee Jungwoo, hurrah~
Give us a break.Great pitching and now good batting?
She's quite a chick.Why don't you share? Shit.
Yes, that player's Lee Jungwoo.An upcoming star in high school baseball!
Huh? It's Boeun's high school.
Was I too generous?That's doesn't look good...
Youngsters with raging hormones.Something to do without.
But, I guess they'll grow out of it.
One cute student is quite passionate about a player.
- Ah, it's the sushi girl.- Excuse me?
They were sharing a sushi lunch before the game.Nice picture.
I see.
Can't you be more early?
- Were you still up?- I've been waiting for you.
It gets dangerous at night. Go to bed.
Okay.
- Sleep.- Go to sleep.
- Yeah.- Night.
- What's wrong?- Don't you know?
What?
The whole school knowsabout you and Jungwoo.
- What's wrong with that?- Do you think it's right?
You're married.
Just by law! You know how things are!
What if Sangmin's parents and your's find out about this?How can you be so selfish?
Why are you crying?
I like Jungwoo too!
There you are.We're having a meeting at our place tonight.
I know.
You look great.Your hubby must be treating you well.
- Hey!- Yes?
- You live in apt. 106, right?- Yes
There's an important meeting tonight,so tell your mom to come, okay?
- It's apt. 108.- Okay.
- Hey!- Yes?
You're such a cute little thing.
Thank you.
- Thanks for everything. Bye.- Good night.
- Bye. Take care.- Thanks for tonight.
Where have you been?
Apartment meeting.
Look at him.He looks like a sleazebag.
Yeah, he really does.
Looks mean as well.
What did you tell them?
How can you do this to me!
See you later.
Shit, why am I such a loser.
I envy you.You have a husband and a boyfriend.
Next, next.
No. 2, Hulk,No. 3, Tiger Woods,
- No. 4 Zidane!- Okay, Zidane!
Zidane, Zidane!
What is it?
Aw shit. You should've knocked...
- Uh! Jisoo...- Jisoo...
You're here.I have your assigned internship schools.
- Sangmin is Dongin High.- What?
- Dongin High.- Shit!
What is it? What's wrong?
It's Boeun's high school.
Idiot!
Boeun...
Huh?
- You know...- What!?
- What is it? I'm late for school!- Okay.
We'll talk at home, okay? Bye!
Excuse me,but where is the faculty office?
Faculty office? I don't know.
I loathe that place.
Wait for me!
Hey, who told you to dye your hair?
What a funky hairstyle! Come here.
Excuse me!Hey!
Your tea...
Thank you.
You should have told me.
You seemed too attractiveto be a pervert.
Working out?
Sir, this is the new intern Park Sangmin.
Hello, sir.
Miss. Kim, you may be excused.
Yes, we'll be seeing a lot of each other.
- How have you been, sir?- Good.
- Take good care of Boeun.- Yes.
- No one knows except for me.- Right.
Last night I was at a disco club...Do you know who I met there?
- Who?- Our room teacher.
What?
She must've gone thereto pick up men.
Old maid syndrome!
Quiet!
We have a new intern here.
- Wow, he's so cute.- He's really cute.
Doesn't he look familiar?
Yeah, he does look familiar.He's cute, though...
I'm Park Sangmin who will be teaching Art.
- I hope we get along.- Yes!
Don't even think of playing tricks on Mr. Park, okay?
Yes, ma'am...
You all have a bright future,you know what I mean!
- Anything else?- No, that's all.
Quiet!
Now, let's make a toast!
Cheers! We'll spendthe entire night toasting.
Mr. Park, bottoms up!
Mr. Park!
Now one from your supervisor.
- Here you go~- Just a little bit.
- How is it, Mr. Park?- Excuse me?
- The kids are hard to deal with, huh?- No, I can handle them.
- Are you busy tonight?- Yes, a bit...
Aw~ come on!
It's a great coincidencethat we're teaching the same class.
This calls for a celebration together!
No thank you!
It’ll make your internship much easier.One more round, okay? Okay...
Mr. Park, let's go! The second round.
When I first met you in Jeju Isle, I felt weird inside.
Miss Kim! Wake up. Please!
Don't take me easy because I'm a spinster!
I'll kill you if you do!
I don't believe this is happening!
Mr. Park...You know...I went to a fortune teller earliar this year.
I'm supposed to marry a younger man.What do you think about this?
What do you mean?We talked about this before!
Don't take me easy!
I'll pound you with a brick if you do!
Miss Kim... Miss Kim! Miss...Miss Kim, Miss Kim...
Where are you going Mr. Park?
Nowhere... drive on, mister.
Why are you up?
What?
Why didn't you answer your phone?
Your teachers all drink like fishes!
I couldn't keep up.
- Why of all schools is it mine?- I know...
If the school finds out, I'm going to die!Be careful!
I'll be careful. Don't worry.There won't be any rumors.
Don't worry. Go to sleep.
Wash up! You stink of liquor.
Okay. Sleep.
Why should I be the only oneto be careful?
- Hey!- What!
I'll be careful.
What?
Sorry, but can I pee next to you?
- No!- I'll turn around.
Boeun, I can't hold myself!
Oh my god!
What are you doing?
Hey! Park Sangmin, what are you doing!
Didn't I warn you not to drink too much!
I feel like shit.
Now, focus!
Mr. Park.
Huh?
Get a grip on your wife.
Mr. Park!
Ah, yes, Miss Kim!
Isn't this adorable?
Mr. Park, what are you doing after school?
Well, my grandfather's sick.
- You must be the first son.- I'm the only son.
Your family must have a weak male line.
We're all sons except for me.Isn't it funny?
I'm just joking.
Mr. Park...
- It's okay.- A bright smile.
- The kids are watching.- Let them watch.
What's with the old maid?She's caught her prey.
The old maid's pathetic.
She made the physical education teachertransfer to another school.
- Hello, sir.- Hi.
Was it good?
Were you watching?
You seemed to reallyenjoy the cozy lunch together.
It was great.Better than the school store's stale bread.
Jealous?
You're such a loser!
- Hello, sir.- Uh, yeah.
- Hello, Mr. Park.- Uh, yeah, hi.
- Is there a Lee Jungwoo here?- Yes, that will be me.
- Are you Lee Jungwoo?- Yes.
- So you're Jungwoo...- Yes, I am Lee Jungwoo.
- Jungwoo, was the sushi good?- What?
You look good. Keep it up!
Shit!
- Having fun?- Yeah.
Hey, I was getting to the fun part!
They're all naked. How could you say it's fun?
- Don't say that about my hobby!- You call that a hobby?
- Give it to me!- Forget it!
It's educational. Give it back!
You should be ashamed of yourself!I'm studying!
Then close the door!
- Stop watching!- Shut up!
- Alright, so give it back.- No.
- I'm sorry, so give it back.- You're sorry?
It won't stop you from watching it again!
Gimme. Okay.
Hey! Do as you wish!
Hey! Someone's at the door!
Jeez.
Boeun! Boeun, Miss Kim's at the door!
Miss Kim?
What did you do to make her comeall this way!
I don't know!Hurry and clean this up. Hurry!
Underwear, underwear!
Mr. Park~
- Mr. Park!- Oh god!
- Oh, the door's open~- Yes...
Oh, your place has everything.
- A woman could just fit in.- Miss Kim, what brings you here?
Mr. Park, I came to do your dirty laundry.
- Is that your bedroom?- Miss Kim!
- What's that?- An automatic vacuum cleaner.
Automatic...it does everything by itself...
- Someone's here, Mr. Park.- No!
It's a ghost, a ghost!
Who was that? Who was it?
- It's my sister, she's a bit crazy...- Crazy? It does seem like it...
Munch is a Norwegian painter.
A pioneer of expressionism, whosepaintings were of angst and grief.
- Then there was...- Mr. Park.
- Huh, what?- Forget Munch...
Tell us about your first artworkin the deptartment Of romance.
- First artwork...- Yes!
Let's continue the class!
- Your first love!- Mr... tell us about your first love
Okay. My first love was
the only visitor during my three yearsof military service.
But that person doesn't knowhow much I like her.
Does she still do?
It must be Jisoo.
She may or may not know.Now back to class.
How's the internship?
I'm so unlucky being stuckwith a boys only high school!
How could you be luckywhen you're not with the girls?
How about you, Sangmin?
Everything's great, thanks to you.
I felt that you two neededsome time together.
The dude's having ball.
He goes to school where he can meethis pretty wife,
and be surroundedby young high school girls.
How could he get bored there?
I'm bored out of my brains.
Seeing my bossy wife at school and at home...
Dude, you've got nothing but luck.Take this.
What is it?Military service...
It's tomorrow, so don't be late.And bring coins to play coin games.
Your husband's off to serve his country!
Allegiance!
- No, it's "Victory!"- Victory!
See you later.
Oh, and don't forget what I asked you to do.
Have fun.
Thank you. Morning training's over!
Time has passed, but I still got the form, don't I?
Your beer belly is destroying the form.
- They're lining up.- It's the lunch ration line!
Morons...
Thank you.
Hey, Sangmin, it's noodles...
- Fried tofu noodles?- Yeah.
Can I have another bowl?
No, it's okay.
You're not eating, right?
Is that sushi?
- Victory!- Victory!
- Thank you.- You're welcome.
- I'm sorry. I just brought only one.- Don't worry.
It's okay. Is it good, dude?
Don't talk to me. It's delicious.
At least you could offer some.
- Want a piece of kimchi?- Kimchi, kimchi...
Another piece would be nice.
A big piece! Let go!
Aren't you marine Park?
Victory...
Victory!
- Invincible!- Invincible!
- Marines!- Marines!
Once a marine, always a marine.
What do they want?
Marines are all like that.
- Do something!- Ah, delicious.
Stop! Don't touch anything!
Invincible... Marines...
Mister, what do you think you're doing!
- Get up!- This won't take long.
A feisty one, aren't you?Are you his wife or what?
- Yeah, I am his wife!- Sorry, she's my little sister.
What's there to hide!
How dare you push my hubby around? Apologize!
- I'm a marine.- Now!
- I'm a marine.- My grandpa's a marine, too!
What's your year rank! What year!?
Hey, Boeun...
Now, I'm leaving for the sea.
Casting a net to catch fish~
I am the romantic cat~
Meow~
My hot lips wish to touch your soft lips.
So my feelings can reach your heart~
If you still don't know.
More than anyone, I will love you ~
- I will love you~- Forever~
- I will love you~- Like this moment,
More than anyone, I will love you ~
We can't meet~The feeling's important~
That's what I think~I don't want things to be too simple~
Even if it may be just this once~The feeling's important~
That's what I think~I don't want things to be too fast~
I still don't know what love is~Wait a little longer~
If you really love me~You can wait a little longer~
If you really love me~You can wait a little longer,
even if it may be just once~The feeling's important ~
I can't meet you, I can't~
Stop it.
Stop.
- Tickle, tickle~- Stop~
- Nice picture.- Hullo, hullo!
- Who are you people?- We're hoodlums.
You're her sugar daddy, aren't you?
- Cute.- Really cute.
Do you want to die by my hands!
Hey, I'd love to be her sugar daddy.
Sangmin, Sangmin, shit!
You're all dead meat.
Let go!
Can't you file a paper, right?
How can this high schooler be your wife?
They all say they're married to the girl when they're caught.
It's true.
I'm no sugar daddy. You can check my record then.
Mister, it's true. We're married.
You're both fucking with me, aren't you?
What is the world coming to?
I'm so pissed. How could you get beat up like that?
How will you live in the real world!
How come everyone you meet is a bully?
I really worry about you.
- Stop...- Keep rolling...
How will you go to school with a face like that?
I'm worried about school...
Everything will be okay.Yeah...
Hello.
Attention!
For this year's school festival,our class is assigned to decorations.
No!
Quiet!
Stage decorations will be done by No. 1 to 15.
The stands and stairways, No. 16 to 21.
The Entrance, No. 23 to 32.
- And No. 22!- Yes?
No. 22 will do the hall wall. Alone!That's all!
But, Miss Kim!
That's unfair.How will Boeun paint that huge wall by herself?
Right! I told her to do it herself! So what!?
With my luck with men, what was I thinking?
You are huge.
Have you thought about what you'll paint?
No.
What do you mean?Even if I wanted to help you,
I can't, for fear of starting rumors at school.I'm really worried.
I really worry about you, Boeun.
Do you know what I'm thinking?Do you?
- Cut it out.- Boeun!
Shhh!
Follow me.
Oh my...
I must be a lesbian.I like my friend better than a boy.
If you're a lesbian, I'm a cheating wife.
Hey~ Your husband is so cute.
Stop talking about that loser.
He keeps staring at you during class.
He has a cool side to him.
Cool my ass!
Suh Boeun!
I know you're seeing Jungwoowith romantic feelings,
but have you ever thoughtabout Sangmin's feelings?
I really think you like Sangmin.Am I right?
No...Sangmin's just like a big brother since we were little.
- Stop fooling around.- You're always on my back.
- Hey, sew her mouth, shut.- Uh?
Wow, look at all this food.The table's barely holding up.
- Eat.- Thank you for the meal.
Thank you for the meal, mom.
Easy. Have you been skipping meals?
I've really been busy.
I missed your cooking, it's delicious.
You shouldn't say that,your wife's right here.
You'll hurt Boeun's feelings.
Mom, don't worry. I'm undernourished.
When Boeun reaches twenty,you'll totally forget mom's cooking.
Boeun, I've put food in the fridge,so don't forget, okay?
There'll be more when you're done with it.
Yes...
Okay, it's late.I'm leaving after dinner.
Yes.
Mom, it's raining.Sleep over at your son's place.
Yes, mom.
Is it okay?
Sleep over, sleep over.Eat, mom.
Oh, okay.
It's your son's place. What's the big deal!
Oh, great. So comfortable.
Turn around.No, not this way, but the other.
Okay.
- Stay in that direction.- Okay, pest.
- Are you asleep, Boeun?- No...
You can't sleep?
- Sangmin, I thought about it...- Yeah...
It's not fair to you.
Look at me, Sangmin.
What?
Did you know? That you're really cute?
You're pretty yourself.
- Sangmin.- Yeah, Boeun...
Boeun...
Sangmin, what are you doing?
- What do you think?- Stop!
Wait, Boeun.
Uh, stop it!
Sleep.
Did we paint that much?
Let's hurry up with this.There's not much time left till the festival.
- Hurry!- Okay.
Hey, wait!
Gotcha, gotcha!
I see you've been working hard, but can you finish at this pace?
The festival's coming up.
Don't worry. We'll be done by then.Yeah, and it'll look great too.
Really? We'll see about that...
I've seen enough...
Whatever...
The hag has appeared.
To find fault in our wall painting.
Miss Kim,
with her nasty tone, she will...
I hate to admit it, but we've done a horrible job.
- It's okay.- Really?
Let's wash our hands and grab some snacks.
Are you taking care of Sangmin's meals?
It's really hard to be an intern you know.
It couldn't be that hard!
Hey, but he's your husband.
Hey, I'm busy myself.And he'll never skip a meal.
What kind of wife are you?
Then you be his wife.Mrs. Park Sangmin.
Forget it. I don't want it.
- Why the sudden interest!- Shut up.
Hey, Park Sangmin! Where are you?
Shouldn't you be helping me?
I couldn't believe it myself!
- Coke.- Thanks.
- Good?- Yeah.
- Eat up. We'll be painting until dawn.- What?
Hey, isn't she a babe?
She's the queen of Sunil Girls' Jr. High.
- Hey, let me see.- Hey!
I'm going to make a move on her,so nice shots, please.
Okay.
Just don't get blown off.
From this day on,she's Suh Dongku's woman!
Excuse me, but,aren't you going to Sunil Girls' Jr. High?
Hey! Over there.Isn't that Dongku's sister?
Where? It really is his sister.
Her husband looked older than that...
Then, who's that?
She must've fallen for a younger dude.
Nice.
The whole family's fooling around!
I got her number. Did you get a good shot?
Here.
COME TO THE MONTHLY FAMILY DINNERBEFORE IT'S TOO LATE.
Jungwoo, I have to go home.
Already?
Hurry in and sit.
Can't you be more early?
Leave her alone.
It's okay. Let's eat.
The chili squid was great...
Attention, please.I'll now show you my girlfriend!
- Do you have a girlfriend?- Yes, of course.
- Now take a good look.- That's her?
She's better than your sister.
- Hey, look... look...- Who's that? Huh?
Hey, Boeun!
Hey!
Boeun!
When you were little,
I always pushed you on this swing here.You really loved it.
But one day,
you fell off the swing while I was pushing.
I actually did it on purpose.
I'm sorry, Sangmin...
Everyone will be worried.Let's go.
This marriage...
it seems like your grandpa forced you into it,
but in fact we wanted to haveSangmin as our son-in-law.
Do you remember? How often you would cry?
But whenever Sangmin came,a smile would spread on your face.
You would fall all the time.
Scraping and breaking yourself.Sangmin felt worse than I did.
He carried you on his back all the time, that Sangmin.
Anyway, I envy you.
The way he spends more time on your schoolfestival than his graduation exhibition,
I guess he's gone to paint the wall with Yongju and Youngchul...
Sangmin! Sangmin!
Sangmin! I came with the family to see you,
but an emergency at your squad forces me to turn away.
Are you doing well?
A few days ago, heavy snow came down in Seoul.
The Han River is frozen as well...
It's colder here, right?Don't catch a cold.
And this is a secret
but my mom says that I've become a woman now.
I'm a bit behind than the other girls,
but being an idiot that you are,you won't understand what I mean, will you?
It's strange but when you were around, I hated your guts,
but your absence has me missing you.
Are you feeling the same?
Then be good to me from now on. Stupid.
The disappointment of not being ableto meet you has your mom crying.
Anyway, this letter, I hope it reaches you.
Where have you been?I've been looking all over for you.
The wall's great.
- I... have something to say.- Yeah, what?
I'm sorry. I've been so selfish.
To you and...
What's got into you?
I'm breaking up with you.I'm sorry, Jungwoo.
People laugh and dance but I hate to laugh~
While we drink and search for love,we forget about the truth~
Why are you late?
Did you see him?
Who? Your husband or boyfriend?
I'm not kidding!
There he is.
I like the smiling clown~Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah~
I like the clown who embraces sadness~
Aren't they great?
Now, intern, Park Sangmin will share a few words with us.
I thank everyone, the principal, all the teachers...
and all the students for helping me finishthis internship in one piece.
It may have been a short time,
but personally,
it has left me with precious memoriesI will carry for the rest of my life.
Mr. Intern, cut the boring crap and show us some honestly.
Mr. Park Sangmin is a married man.
Didn't you know?
Of course, it's not a sin to be married.
But in fact you're married to a 15 year oldhigh school girl, right?
To Suh Boeun who's sitting right there...
Correct. We are married.
But Boeun had no choice.
The only crime she's committed was grantingher sick grandfather's last wish.
It was against her will to marry me.
She may be married, but she's still a 15 year old high school girl.
She goes crazy over a bowl of chili and spaghetti.
She loves cute stars and sushi-...loving attractive baseball players.
Everyday, she's stressed over exams,and applying to university.
I hope you won't persecute Boeun'sschool life over a marriage document.
I beg you all.
Sangmin, I'm not a kid anymore.
Since I was little, you were always at my side.
I was never aware of the strange feelings...inside...
but... I think I'm in love with you...
Our poor Dongku.She's the end of all your fun and play.
Fun and play...
I knew it since he was fixed onthat school queen or whatever...
I can't believe grandpa fell for her grandmother.
- I can't believe it...- She looks bright though.
Just consider it starting early! Do it!
Do it!
Oh, shut up and peel the garlic.
I'm in no position to say this, but
you can hide a lop-sided butt, but not lop-sized balls.
Anyway, congrats.
It's good that she doesn't have a clue.
Who would marry a lop-sized ball manif they knew, right?
Right.
Oh, you're here!
Oh, dad!
You're here.
I'm really getting into peeling these things...
Did you get married to peel garlic?
Mom!
Okay!
Say cheese. One, two, three!!