At 9:50am Haitham Ziad Al-Mis'hal was targeted by an unmanned
Israeli aircraft in North Gaza, justNorth of the Beach refugee camp where he
resided, right outside a Hamas trainingsite
The targeted assassination was the firstof its kind since the eight-day war of
November. The hamas government in Gazacondemned the targeting in a relatively
measured statement.
According to the Occupying state of Israel
Haitham was responsible for a rocket firingincident in Egypt's Sinai desert a
fortnight ago. No israelis were injuredor killed went two Grad rockets
landed in the Israeli town of Eilat.
Some of Haitham's friends and relativesarrived at the morgue to see his body.
At the mortuary Haitham's fatherconfirmed his son's involvement with
various resistance groups. All of his life he worked with the
resistance and
he always aspired to be martyred like his relative Ahmad al-Mis'hal.
Now he followed Ahmad.
The targeting of Haitham was apparently ajoint Israeli military and secret
service intelligence operation. Israelfurther claimed that Hamas knew about
Haitham's militant activities and failedto stop him
Israel holds the Hamas governmentresponsible for any attacks emanating
from Gaza
Hamas hasn't been able to restrain thearmed activities of some resistance
groups since it came to power in 2007. Men carried Haitham's body
from the morgue to his family home
Haitham's body was dismembered
His ankles, torn off by two drone missiles.The women of the family and neighbourhood
received the body
Haitham's mother said that 20 moreresistance fighters will rise up in his
place. She added that she hopes that theresistance groups will destroy Israel
She herself hopes to be killed defendingPalestinian land
His older sister exclaimed: where is thecease-fire? Then she said Gaza doesn't
need a cease-fire anyway.
Today was Haitham's [25th] birthday
Haitham had four brothers and threesisters. We spoke with his middle sister
Twelve-year-old Aya who said he was thefamily's only breadwinner
Honestly Haitham was a good
guy. He was like a caring father figure and brother. Now he is
a martyr with his Lord. We have not lost outbecause this was God's will. God's will
governs even the lives of the collaborators. I hope that God
kills all those who betrayed our people.
In the Catastrophe of 1948 Haitham's family was displaced from
al-Jorah
near Ashkelon, now inside Israel, a few miles north from his family home
According to his family Haitham was riding a motorbike when he received a
mobile phone call telling him to ridenorth to visit the unknown caller. He was
targeted en route.
I'm the wife of Haitham
We married 3 months ago. I am proud of his martyrdom. I'm pregnant.
Who's the one who's going to raise the baby inside me? God is the best of planners.
The family fears Haitham's wife will miscarry because
of the grief and stress
The men then proceeded to a graveyard in Sheikh Redwan where he was buried.
Um Amar Abu Sharaekh lives
directly opposite Haitham's home and helped raise him.
Haitham was not the first to be martyred and he won't be the last
And many will rise up like Haitham. Israel shouldn't think that our youth and our
resistance will stop rising up
and the one who taught Haitham will teach many more. In the future the
the rocket firers will strike further away than Tel Aviv. They will respond.
Haitham is our son and anyone martyred is our son. Anyone from the Muslim youth
is our son too.
Israel maintains that
they it preemptively target anyone involved in planned rocket attacks from
Gaza or Egypt
Meanwhile various militant groups herein Gaza have issued statements saying
that they will answer today's targeting
It's now more likely the things willescalate in Gaza in the coming days
Visit GazaReport.com for moreinsight into the situation afflicting Gaza
This films production was made possibleby Gaza Report's funders