Mawlaya salli wa sallim da'iman abadan (My Lord send Your peace and blessings always and forever)
'Ala habibika khayril khalqi kullihimi (Upon Your beloved, the best of the entire creation)
'Ala habibika khayril khalqi kullihimi  (Upon Your beloved, the best of the entire creation)
Ya Rabbee salli 'aleeh (My Lord send Your peace upon him)
Salawatu Allahi 'aleeh (May Allah's salutations be upon him)
All the poetry ever written
Every verse and every line
All the love songs in the world
And every melody and rhyme
If they were combined
They would still be unable to express
What I want to define
When I try to describe my love for you
Mawlaya salli wa sallim da'iman abadan (My Lord send Your peace and blessings always and forever)
'Ala habibika khayril khalqi kullihimi (Upon Your beloved, the best of the entire creation)
Ya Rabbee salli 'aleeh (My Lord send Your peace upon him)
Salawatu Allahi 'aleeh (May Allah's salutations be upon him)
Every sound and every voice
In every language ever heard
Each drop of ink that has been used
To write every single word
They could never portray
Everything I feel in my heart and want to say
And it’s hard to explain
Why I could never describe my love for you
Mawlaya salli wa sallim da'iman abadan (My Lord send Your peace and blessings always and forever)
'Ala habibika khayril khalqi kullihimi (Upon Your beloved, the best of the entire creation)
Ya Rabbee salli 'aleeh (My Lord send Your peace upon him)
Salawatu Allahi 'aleeh (May Allah's salutations be upon him)
There’s not a single person
Who can ever match his worth
In character and beauty
To ever walk on earth
I envy every rock and tree
And every grain of sand
That embraced his noble feet
Or that kissed his blessed hands
Ya Rasool Allah (O Messenger of Allah)
Ya Habiba Allah (O Allah's Beloved)
Grant us the chance to be with him
We pray to You Allah
Mawlaya salli wa sallim da'iman abadan (My Lord send Your peace and blessings always and forever)
'Ala habibika khayril khalqi kullihimi (Upon Your beloved, the best of the entire creation)
Ya Rabbee salli 'aleeh (My Lord send Your peace upon him)
Salawatu Allahi 'aleeh (May Allah's salutations be upon him)
Mawlaya salli wa sallim da'iman abadan (My Lord send Your peace and blessings always and forever)
'Ala habibika khayril khalqi kullihimi (Upon Your beloved, the best of the entire creation)
Ya Rabbee salli 'aleeh (My Lord send Your peace upon him)
Salawatu Allahi 'aleeh (May Allah's salutations be upon him)