Your document list is now a part of GoogleDrive.
Just like before, you can access your filesall in one place,
and easily share them with others.
Google Drive comes with a desktop applicationfor Mac and PC that adds a Drive folder on
your computer.
Anything you drag into this folder syncs automatically,
with Google Drive on the web,
and across your devices.
You can also still create new documents, presentationsand spreadsheets.
And now, you can use other applications too.
We've added a new grid view so you can seefiles at a glance.
And, the left hand navigation has been simplified.
'My Drive' includes all the files and foldersthat you've created, uploaded or moved there.
This folder syncs with Google Drive on yourdesktop.
If you want to sync files that others haveshared with you to your desktop, simply drag
them from 'Shared with me' to 'My Drive'.
Click 'More' for other ways to view your files,
Like 'Activity', which includes everythingthat has recently been edited by you or others.
This was called 'Home' before.
To quickly find a file, search and filterby file type or owner.
You can even search text within scanned documentsand image files without any text at all.
With Google Drive, all your stuff is togetherin one place.
Upgrade today by visiting drive.google.com.