There’s an "edit" button
Just click on it,
find the place where the text is, and edit
and then click "Save". It’s that easy.
The cool thing about Wikipedia,
is that you can change things.
You don’t need anybody’s permission
and it’s not hard.
It looks a little bit daunting at first,
but it’s really not hard
People don’t realise, as though it’s some sort of blindness.
People read articles and they don’t see the "edit" button.
Click on that button, and see what happens.
"Edit."
When you open yourself to something,
and you go and start editing,
all kinds of other things can happen,
and that’s really beautiful.
Like, it can be just a starting point,
it’s an invitation for more life, somehow.
Whenever we start an article, we don’t like it,
because you find it ugly.
But wait just... hours
and see how it will be developed to a great article.
The "edit" button: click it, and change something,
save page, you have made a difference to the whole world.
"Save".