Tae Ik's phone is turned off..
Stylist Jang isn't picking up her phone..
Ah, seriously!
There are no traces of them entering the resort.
He even exchanged fists with the advertiser and then disappeared.
Then, where exactly did they go?
Please wait outside.
Yes.
If there is a rescue team at the resort, I would like to make a request.
What is the situation now? &lt;br&gt;Is the guest hurt?
Well.. someone is missing..
Oh, someone is missing?
Tae Ik!
Spread out and look for him. Spread out.
Hey! Spread out! Spread out!
I said spread out!
Tae Ik!
Go over there.
Tae Ik! Tae Ik!
Lee Tae Ik!
Tae Ik!
Hey, open the door.
Tae Ik!&lt;br&gt;Tae Ik!
Lee Tae Ik!&lt;br&gt;Tae Ik!
I told you it's locked..
Then where is he?
Ah! Shocks!
By the way, why am I here?
I definitely slept outside.
Hey! What did you do to the sleeping bag?
Do you sleep walk by any chance?
What? Sleep walk?
Yes. Did you do something while I was sleeping?
No.
Yesterday, I was definitely outside with the cat.
Huh? Cat!!
Don't open it!
What are you doing here, Stylist Jang?
That is..
I got shocked.
Tae Ik!&lt;br&gt;You..
That's not it.
I will take the others to the other side, &lt;br /&gt;so take care of things and come out.
Separately! All right?
So that people don’t catch on.
What are you doing?
Clean this.
By myself?
You have to help me fold this.
&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Episode 5 &lt;br&gt;~Part 1~&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Subtitles brought to you by &lt;br&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Maid of House 2 Team&lt;/b&gt; @Viki
&lt;i&gt;Something is weird... I'm sure I slept outside..
&lt;i&gt;Then.. that guy... by chance...
&lt;i&gt; He would never do that.
&lt;i&gt;Do I really sleep walk?
&lt;i&gt;Was she perhaps... pretending to sleep?
&lt;i&gt;Otherwise how could she be outside the sleeping bag?
&lt;i&gt; What is this dirty feeling?
&lt;i&gt; It's not.. right? It wouldn't be.
&lt;i&gt;Ehhy!
This one without a zipper hasn’t come in yet?
I asked for a call once it arrived.
Sir, someone else reserved it, so . . .
I did that.
Oh my!&lt;br&gt;Please, come this way.
Wow, what is this?
These are all my style! &lt;br&gt;This, too. This, too.
Buy all this? I can't... &lt;br&gt;Don't tempt me.
It's already been paid for.
By whom?
Here. &lt;br&gt;If you look here, you will know.
&lt;i&gt;JY Hotel&lt;i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Suite 813&lt;i&gt;
-Hello?&lt;br&gt;&lt;i&gt;-Where are you?
Oh?&lt;br&gt;I'm outside.
&lt;i&gt;Are you going shopping again?
Am I addicted to shopping? &lt;br /&gt;I'm not always shopping!
Then hurry back.
Why? President told me to rest today!
Something came up.
I'll be back in Seoul in 1 hour. Come back by then.
I came to meet an important person. &lt;br /&gt;I may even sleep over.
The company atmosphere is really chilly today.
Hyung-nim! Why are you not talking to me?&lt;br&gt; Who are you going to meet?
Don’t try to pry into other’s personal live.
You don't even know who it is, so hang up!
It's me.
Relax, relax… after we go in.
Jackpot !
Why aren't you eating? You said you were hungry.
Just seeing my son makes me full.
Stop looking, my face will wear out.
You're not sick, right?
Of course, I am the completely healthy type.
What about your eye? Has it gone bad?
Let me look at it.
I'm really okay.
Mom, give me some coffee.
Come back with me..
and let's get an examination, huh?
I had it checked already. &lt;br /&gt;Everything is alright.
Really?
Son.. Can you stop your music career &lt;br /&gt;and come back with me?
I am really lonely without my son.
You are always with Chairman Won.&lt;br /&gt;How can you be lonely?
Do you think I like being next to a sick Chairman?
This is all for.. you..
Mom, stop.. Let's not talk about that..
How can I not? There really isn’t much time left for the Chairman now.
Ju Ming is trying to take your place.
I have to go now..
I forgot I had practice today..
If you continue to act like this, I don’t know what I will do.
They are not just empty words.
For all the precious time I've spent caring for your old father,&lt;br /&gt;I will definitely stake your place.
Mom... you really...
make me sad. Coming after such a long time…
Kang Hwi, Mom…
I'm going . . .
Son..
Don't follow me... &lt;br /&gt;You know I don't like things like that, don't you?
I'll be going.
I'm not going to give up!
I think I caught something big.
Let’s go.
Why here?
Let’s go in first.
The President is waiting.
Stylist Jang,
what on earth happened yesterday?
Nothing happened.
We just lost our way.
No, not that.
At the shoot yesterday.
Ah!
That is… I got a little fired up.
No matter how much you got fired up,
I don’t understand why hyung hit the advertiser.
What?
Who hit who?
Tae Ik hyung.
Though he has a temper, he isn’t one to do something like that.
Ah! Seriously...
I heard that our Tae Ik behaved rudely to you, Department Director.
Really… that is… I am really sorry.
I came out of consideration for you.
But what is this?
The individual isn’t even here.
Ah! Tae Ik, sit down
He does music, so there is a sensitive side to him.
Please accept a drink from me and magnanimously get over your anger.
That's all right. &lt;br /&gt;I will hear the apology directly from the person.
Ah! Of course, you should.
What are you doing? &lt;br&gt;Hurry and apologize.
Pour me a drink.
Let me receive a drink from a Hallyu star.
What is this?
Are you in your right mind?
There is a limit to how much you can sass.
You seem to still think you are still the son of a chaebol.
Don’t fool yourself!
You are but a singer and a commercial model.
And he is the advertiser who employed you.
Did the two of you plot together?
You both say the same thing.
What?
Is there only one commercial?
Will something happen to the company,&lt;br /&gt; if I don’t shoot that commercial?
Whether we shoot that commercial or not will be decided by me and not you.
You are merely my puppet! &lt;br&gt;Do you get it?
Then...
my master can take care of it.
And the puppet can leave.
Tae Ik. Tae Ik. Tae Ik!
Hey, Tae Ik. Why are you like this?
Let’s go in. Let’s go in and…
Move.
I said, move!
Because I can’t see straight right now.
Hey, alright! Alright! &lt;br&gt;Wait, I will get the car.
&lt;i&gt;This place, you see, was actually Tae Ik hyung’s house.
&lt;i&gt;All the way over to that hill completely belonged to Tae Ik’s family.&lt;/i&gt;
You were extremely rich, Lee Tae Ik.
&lt;i&gt; Hey! They were among the top builders.
&lt;i&gt;But… how did this happen?
&lt;i&gt; I also don’t know that well either. &lt;br&gt;Everyone keeps it quiet.
&lt;i&gt;Then, is only that house Tae Ik’s?
&lt;i&gt;All the money he earned so far was spent in buying that.
&lt;i&gt;Hyung wants to somehow retrieve this place completely.
&lt;i&gt;The piece of land is extremely large and also expensive…
&lt;i&gt;The President bought it for investment, so he will not give it up easily.
Excuse me!
I called you, but you won’t even answer.
Move.
Ah, seriously!
I didn’t even go home and waited all this time.
Here!
What is this?
It is an oriental medicine pain relief patch.
Stick it on your back where you got hurt yesterday.
I bought this specially, expensive one.
It is hypoallergenic, so they said you can stick it anywhere.
Take it.
Only then can I also go home.
I’ll be going.
Wait!
Breathe.
I said let’s eat something at home... &lt;br /&gt;Do we have to go at this hour?
Is it still far?
We are going there?
Yes.
This place looks really expensive.
It is.
Hey. Let’s just go somewhere else. Huh?
Why? You said that you want to eat something delicious.
Everything is delicious for me…
Ah! There was a soft tofu store in front over there, let’s go there.
Unless it is organic tofu, I don’t eat it.
But... it is expensive, places like this.
If you don’t want to eat, go home alone.
Ah, seriously!
Please enjoy your food.
Is there anything else that you need?
No.
I don’t think we will be able to finish all of this either.
Do you have pine mushroom?
Ah, is the season over?
We have some that was brought in yesterday from Bonghwa.
An order for two is possible.
No! Just give us one serving. &lt;br /&gt;I don’t like mushrooms much.
Give 2 servings.
Yes.
Also please prepare pheasant Shabu-Shabu.
How will we eat all of this that you keep ordering?
I will eat it, I will.
Aren’t you eating?
I will, I will eat, but still this is…
Natural abalone, Yeongdeok snow crab, tile fish from Jeju, rib patties made of Korean beef!
These are precious foods that you will never see set on the same table in your whole life.
What? Is there something lacking?
Ah! That’s not it.
Eat! Eat everything completely from here to there without leaving anything.
Ah, alright.
I will eat it and then die.
Kang Hwi
&lt;i&gt;Hi, Man Ok, it’s me.
Kang Hwi, wait a moment.
Man Ok, can you come to me now?
I want to see you.
I am eating now…
Just come, huh?
I will buy you something delicious, huh?
I was about to eat… I will go after I eat.
Ah! I don’t want to be alone.
Where are you now?
Near the company… The playground.
It is close to here… &lt;br /&gt;I will go there immediately after I eat.
Yes, alright.
I won’t budge and wait here.
You must come quickly, Man Ok!
Yes.
&lt;i&gt;Kang Hwi, Who do you like most in the world?
&lt;i&gt;Mom!
&lt;i&gt;Mom, likes you best too!
&lt;i&gt;If I have only you, there isn’t a thing that I am envious of in this whole world.
&lt;i&gt; Kang Hwi, what is it? What's the matter?
&lt;i&gt;Kang Hwi.
&lt;i&gt;Kang Hwi.&lt;br&gt;What should I do?
&lt;i&gt;What should I do? What should I do, Kang Hwi?
&lt;i&gt;- What to do? &lt;br&gt; - Mom!
&lt;i&gt; - Mom! &lt;br&gt; - Let go!
&lt;i&gt;Kang Hwi! Kang Hwi! Kang Hwi!
&lt;i&gt;Let go of me!&lt;br&gt; Let go of me!
&lt;i&gt;Kang Hwi!
&lt;i&gt;Kang Hwi!!
&lt;i&gt;What are you doing? During a meal! &lt;br&gt; Take him away!
I will never go back! Never again!
Please stop eating.
Your stomach will burst!
Ah, seriously! &lt;br&gt;Kang Hwi will be waiting…
I told you. We can’t go till we finish eating all of this!
Why are you being cranky for no reason?
Do you even know how much this is?
If you know how much this costs, you won’t be able to say that you will go, leaving food behind.
Ah! How much is it? &lt;br&gt;I will pay for it!
570,000 won?
Will you pay?
Uh-uh.
Then eat it, all of it.
&lt;i&gt; Why aren’t you coming?
&lt;i&gt;I have a problem.
&lt;i&gt;It's going to take a little time.&lt;br&gt; I'm sorry.
Hello, Sunbaenm.
What is it? Why are you here?
I came for a drink and I heard that you were here,
I came to say hello.
Why are you saying hello to me?
I will pour you a drink.
There isn't any.
Just a moment.
I will bring mine.
We don’t have to go this far.
We even have the video.
The more certain, the better.
Prepare it well.
You have to pay me well.
If I get the commercial.
Sunbae, you should have a drink.
I brought drinks.
I will pour you a drink.
Drink it up!
You have to poke it.
I won’t.
You definitely have indigestion.
If you poke it, it won’t even hurt and the food will go down, really!
I can't be sick from eating those expensive foods.
It’s just… my condition isn’t good.
You ate that much... it would be weird if you didn't have indigestion.
How can a man be so afraid?
Hurry and give me your arm!
Hey! Let go of me!&lt;br&gt;Are you really crazy?
Let go immediately!
See what happens if you poke! &lt;br&gt;I will not leave you alone if you really poke me!
Don't poke! &lt;br&gt;Ouch!
You have indigestion!
Look Look! How dark it is!
Blood...
It will be better soon.
If it still doesn’t go down, we can poke your toes.
So scared..
I'll bring some water. So, also take some medicine.
Here..
He fell asleep already?
Bye!
Don't tell me... &lt;br&gt; That he's still waiting there until now.
What did he say?
He's not answering.
No, Jong Chul!
This business is not such an easy venue.
Were you with a girl I don't know?
That's not it!
Yes, grandfather.
At one, shout!&lt;br&gt; At two, action!
Ay! &lt;br&gt; Two!
Oi!
The place that made me tjhe Jin Se Ryeong of today, &lt;br&gt;shouldn't that be my destination?
&lt;i&gt;shouldn't that be my next destination?
You refused to listen to me!
What are all these??
That's why I told you to be careful!
I told you there are always eyes everywhere.
Proceed immediately as planned.