What exists in every corner of the world - embraced and celebrated in some countries
but is illegal in 76?
What is hidden for fear of public shame, imprisonment,
torture or in 7 countries
even the death penalty?
What tears families apart?
What makes people confront the risk of brutal
violence on a daily basis?
What simple trait gets people treated as second-class
citizens everywhere they go?
What gets children kicked out of homes,
students bullied and expelled from schools
and workers fired from jobs without warning?
What has existed in every country throughout history
but some people still consider "abnormal"?
The answer?
Being gay,
being lesbian
bisexual
or transgender
All over the world millions of people face
violence and discrimination
Just for being who they are
Every nation is obligated by international human rights law
to protect all lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender people
from torture, discrimination and violence
The United Nations has one simple message
to the millions of LGBT people around the world
You are not alone
LGBT rights are human rights
Together we will build a world
We will build a world
that is Free and Equal