Presented by SHOWEAST
Produced by BLUE STORM
A light on channel 3 isn'tcoming on.
Gwang-il
can you finish up here alone?
Can you?
Yes.
Something urgent came up.
- I'll call you later.- But sir...
I'll be back beforethe concert.
April Snow
BAE Yong-joon
SON Ye-jin
Operating Room
Intensive Care Unit
Why was she out there?
Must've been here on business.
Is she hurt?
Pretty badly.
But the boss is looking for you.
I'll try reaching Mr. Kimagain later.
But I can't...
You can do it kid.
I'll try.
Okay, bye.
I'm looking for Officer Kim.
You're here regarding Kang Su-jin?
Yes.
We still don't knowwho was driving.
They were both foundoutside the car.
It was a big accident.
Ms. Kang was intoxicatedat the time.
But my wife doesn't drink.
It's what the report says.You can check with the hospital later.
Is this...?
No.
Stop filming...
Samchuk Hospital
Hello? Design Sai.
Is this the main office?
Yes.
I'm calling about Kang Su-jin.
Um...
She's on vacation.Who's calling, please?
Hello, sir.
She was out here on business?
Yes...
I need to go to Seoulfor a day or so.
Try to have some more, Dad.
Password
Give me.
Look, ln-su.
I understand, but...
The production isn't happywith you
running out on last nights show.
Just take some time off.
Okay.
Sam-heung Motel
Excuse me?
Yes? What is it?
Was your husband really hereon business?
Yes, that's right.
My wife was on vacation.
But I said she was hereon a side job.
I think you should say the same.
Samchuk Hospital
What are you doing?
Have you hada lot of stress recently?
Yes...
Hello.
Do you want something strongor mild?
Something that works well.
$2 please.
Don't take morethan one a day.
How may I help you?
Here you are. Thank you.
Do you need anythingin particular?
Yes.
I'm having trouble sleeping.
I have something to ask you.
And something toreturn to you.
How did you find out?
I read the messages on her phone.
And you?
I read his messages, too.
And the camera wasn't my husband's.
Excuse me...
This may sound weird but...
Could I read your husband's messages?
Let's go away together.Can you take time off?
YOON Kyung-ho
I'm worn out from last night.KANG Su-jin
I'm filming us now...
Don 't.
Stop filming...
Don 't tickle me.
Maybe you should've just died.
Hey.
How've you been, sir?
Okay...
Did you eat?
No.
Then let's go eat.
Are you staying the night?
No, there's a concert tomorrow.
Thats right...
Gwang-il...
When I saw Su-jin at the hospital,
I wished that I'd beenhurt instead.
Don't worry.She'll be fine.
Right...
So, how are things with your wife?
Good, I guess....
You think I'm pathetic,
don't you?
No.
Yeah, right...
Gwang-il...
Just leave...
Sorry, man. Just go.
Please just go.
Bastard.
Hey.
Please...
Open the door.
Please, I need to talk to you.
Hey...
I... uhm...
I'd like to apologize.
I'm very sorry.
- Oh, hello.- Hello.
Have a seat.
It won't be easy settling with them.
The victim was so young.
Since we don't knowwho was driving yet...
It'd be best if you bothwent to his funeral.
Do you want to wait here?
Are you friends of Young-ki?
No, the husband of the onein the accident.
I am very sorry.
Mother...
Who are you?
- I'm very sorry.- I'm very sorry.
I'm the wife of the onewho caused the accident.
You bitch!Bring back my brother!
Bring my brother back!Bastard!
Stop it!
Just go.Please, just go.
I'm begging you.Just leave.
Please, go.
Please just leave.
Please stop the car.
Sleep well.
One, two, three.
Why'd you have to do it, Su-jin?
I just don't get it.
Throw away the sadness.
Good-bye!
Life is beautiful.
Singing!
Throw away the sadness!
Would you like to try?
Are you an athlete?
Why do you ask?
Back therewhen you were throwing...
Oh, that.
No, I'm a lighting directorfor stages.
Like at concerts.
That sounds like fun.
It is when I'm setting it up,
but it seems so futile afterwards.
But it's still funwhen you're setting up, right?
I guess.
What do you do?
Housework and chores.
That's a hard job.
Thank you for saying that...
How did the two of you meet?
She came to take concert picturesduring college.
My wife used to bein a photography club.
What university didshe go to?
Joong-ang University.
Then, they must've beenin the same club.
Would you like some more?
I'll have the beer.
When do you feel happy?
When I sleep?
Me, too.
That hit the spot.
How did you two meet?
After I graduated,
My dad told meto get married early.
He set us up to meet.
Things were so good then....
But I guess career womenare more attractive.
No, not really.
I wish this was all a dream.
A dream...
I don't know what I did wrong.
I hope he comes out of the coma.
So I can at leastget an explanation.
What will you do when she wakes up?
Get revenge.
Should we have an affair?
That'd make them flip.
I need to get some air.
Here you are.
Finished already?
Yes.
- Have some more.- It's okay.
Come in.
Hello.
Have you eaten?
Yes.
So you're going to Seoul?
Yes, for a few days.
I see.
Please take good care of her.
Sure.
Hello.
Hi.
Are things going okay?
Yes.
I knew you could do it.
Thanks.
Let's take it from the top.
Raise up the MR please.
Okay.
Do you like to walk?
Yes, I do.
Do you?
I do, too.
Doesn't it feel weird meetingin Seoul?
Aren't you cold?
Yes, aren't you?
Just a little.
Should we go back?
We came pretty far.
If you're cold, should we run?
Please don't let it die.
I'll take good care of it.
So, what should we do today?
What would you like to do?
Are you always this quiet?
What's your favorite season?
Spring.What about you, ln-su?
Well... I like winter.
I like the snow, too.
Then, I guess it should snowin spring.
Think that'd ever happen?
Want to take a picture?
Never mind.
Sure, why not?
Look here?
Yes.
One, two, three...
Here, let me do it.
Who is it?
It's your father-in-law, son.
Yes, sir. Just a moment.
Okay.
Hello, sir.
I didn't know you were coming.
Holding up okay?
Yes.
Ah... did you eat?
No, not yet.
I was just on my way outfor dinner.
Wait here.
- Did you stop by the hospital?- Yes.
Su-jin looks a lot better.
She does.
Ah, Dad?I think I forgot to lock the door.
I'll wait downstairs.
I'll be right down.
I'm okay.
Hello?
Yes, I'll be right there.
Su-jin.
It might take a few weeksfor the patient to talk.
You said you'd be back late.
Thank you. I'll take it from here.
Okay.
I almost forgot, his blood pressurewent down this afternoon.
Thank you...
There is no big changein his vital signs...
But his bodily functionsare weakening.
Do you want to transfer him to
a bigger hospital in Seoul or stay?
What should I do, doctor?
It's up to you to decide.
What about the womanin the accident with him?
She'll be transferred to Seoul.
I see.
You must be happy.Now you can both go back to Seoul.
Want to go out to eat?
Not really.
I'll wait.
I must be out of my mind.
If we...
met long ago or much later,what would we be?
What will become of us?
Yes, it's me.
No. Something came up.I can't make it back tonight.
Is everything okay?
How's his blood pressure?
I see...
But something came up today.I can't make it back.
I'll be there first thingin the morning.
Please take good care of him.Bye.
4, 7, 8, 9... 20.
...40. Square that all up
and it comes to 1 60 points.
Are you sure?Count it up again.
It's right.Look, 3, 4. It's 7.
7, 8...
He passed away at 3:23 p.m.
Would you like to goin and see him?
Funeral Home
"The departed saint" - "YOON Kyung-ho""The chief mourner" - "HANG Seo-young"
Honey, I want a cigarette.
Are you okay to smoke?
Thank you, In-su...
For what?
For everything.
Last bus to Seoul!
- Seoul!- Where are you going?
Seoul!Last call to Seoul!
Seoul!
Thank you.
In-su, isn't there somethingyou want to ask me?
How long are you goingto hold it back?
At first, I wanted to know...
But not anymore.
Su-jin...
He died.
Gwang-il.
Yes?
Check on the bank.
Right on it, sir!
Good.
Okay.
A great snow squall is fallingfar into spring.
Tae-Baek Mts are about toembrace the spring warm
but it seems he has decidedto hibernate again.
The spring flowers are being
helplessly buriedin the snow...
Where should we go?
Where would you like?
Directed by HUR Jin-hoExecutive producer KIM Dong-joo,BAE Yong-kookProducer KANG Bong-rae
Cinematographer/ LEE Mo-gaeLighting/ OH Seung-chulMusic/ CHO Sung-woo (M&F)Editing/ LEE Eun-soo
Production design PARK Sang-hun